<monster>
<name>Taka-onna</name>
<size>M</size>
<type>fey</type>
<alignment>neutral</alignment>
<ac>12</ac>
<hp>33 (6d8 + 6)</hp>
<speed>30 ft., fly 40 ft.</speed>
<str>11</str>
    <dex>15</dex>
    <con>12</con>
    <intel>10</intel>
    <wis>14</wis>
    <cha>10</cha>
<skill>Acrobatics +6 </skill>

<senses>darkvision 60 ft.</senses>
<passive>11</passive>
<languages>Kami, Oriental (common), Sylvan</languages>
<cr>1</cr>
<trait><text>
Dive Attack. If the taka-onna is flying and dives at least 30 feet straight toward a target
and then hits it with a melee weapon attack, the attack deals an extra 9 (2d8) damage
to the target.</text></trait>
<trait>Keen Sight. The taka-onna has advantage on Wisdom (perception) checks that rely on
sight.</trait>
<trait>Rampage. When the taka-onna reduces a creature to 0 hit points with a melee attack
on its turn, the taka-onna can take a bonus action to move up to half its speed and
make a bite attack.</trait>
Actionss
<action>Multiattack. The taka-onna makes two attacks: one with its bite and one with its hair.
While flying, it can replace one or both attacks with claw attacks.</action>
<action>Bite. Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 4 (1d4 + 2) piercing
damage. If the target is a creature, it must succeed a DC 11 Constitution saving throw
or take 2 (1d4) slashing damage at the start of each of its turns do to the festering
wound. Each time the taka-onna hits the wounded target with this attack, the damage
dealt by the wound increases by 2 (1d4). Any creature can take an action to stanch the
wound with a successful DC 10 Wisdom (medicine) check. The wound also closes if
the target receives magical healing.</action>
<action>Claws. Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 6 (1d8 + 2) slashing
damage.</action>
<action>Grasping Hair. Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 10 ft., one target. Hit: 7 (1d6 +
4) bludgeoning damage, and the target is grappled (escape DC 10). Until this grapple
ends, the target is restrained and the taka-onna cannot grapple another target with its
grasping hair.</action>
<action>Ballade of Jealousy (Recharge 5-6). The taka-onna sings a magical song, directed at a
creature within 30 feet of the taka-onna that can hear it. The target must succeed a DC
12 Intelligence saving throw or be cursed for 1 hour. While cursed, the target creature
spends its turns unequipping any as many items as it can, starting with whatever it is
holding, laying everything at its feet in an orderly fashion. It cannot move, talk or do
anything else while afflicted with this curse. The creature can repeat the saving throw
at the end of each of its turns and each time it takes damage, ending the curse on a
successful save. The curse also ends if the taka-onna or its allies attack the target, or if
removed by a remove curse spell or similar magic.</action>
</monster>