<subclass>
	<name>rogue core</name>
	<class>Rogue</class>
	<hd>8</hd>
	<saves>Dexterity, Intelligence</saves>
	<proficiency>Acrobatics, Athletics, Deception, Insight, Intimidation, Investigation, Perception, Performance. Persuasion, Sleight of Hand, Stealth</proficiency>
	<spellAbility>Intelligence</spellAbility>
	<numSkills>4</numSkills>
		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Starting Rogue</name>
				<text>As a 1st-level Rogue, you begin play with 8+your Constitution modifier hit points.</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>You are proficient with the following items, in addition to any proficiencies provided by your race or background.</text>
				<text>&#8226; Armor: light armor</text>
				<text>&#8226; Weapons: simple weapons, hand crossbows, longswords, rapiers, shortswords</text>
				<text>&#8226; Tools: thieves' tools</text>
				<text>&#8226; Skills: Choose four from Acrobatics, Athletics, Deception, Insight, Intimidation, Investigation, Perception, Performance. Persuasion, Sleight of Hand, and Stealth</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>You begin play with the following equipment, in addition to any equipment provided by your background.</text>
				<text>&#8226; (a) a rapier or (b) a shortsword</text>
				<text>&#8226; (a) a shortbow and quiver of 20 arrows or (b) a shortsword</text>
				<text>&#8226; (a) a burglar's pack, (b) a dungeoneer's pack, or (c) an explorer's pack</text>
				<text>&#8226; Leather armor, two daggers, and thieves' tools </text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>Alternatively, you may start with 4d4x10 gp and choose your own equipment.</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 94</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Multiclass Rogue</name>
				<text>To multiclass as a Rogue, you must meet the following prerequisites:</text>
				<text>&#8226; Dexterity 13</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>You gain the following proficiencies:</text>
				<text>&#8226; light armor, thieves' tools; choose one skill from Acrobatics, Athletics, Deception, Insight, Intimidation, Investigation, Perception, Performance. Persuasion, Sleight of Hand, and Stealth</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 163</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>
<armor>light armor</armor><weapons>simple weapons, hand crossbows, longswords, rapiers, shortswords</weapons><tools>thieves' tools</tools><wealth>4d4x10</wealth>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Expertise</name>
				<text>At 1st level, choose two of your skill proficiencies, or one of your skill proficiencies and your proficiency with thieves&#8217; tools. Your proficiency bonus is doubled for any ability check you make that uses either of the chosen proficiencies.</text>
				<text>	At 6th level, you can choose two more of your proficiencies (in skills or with thieves&#8217; tools) to gain this benefit.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 96</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Sneak Attack</name>
				<text>Beginning at 1st level, you know how to strike subtly and exploit a foe&#8217;s distraction. Once per turn, you can deal an extra 1d6 damage to one creature you hit with an attack if you have advantage on the attack roll. The attack must use a finesse or a ranged weapon.</text>
				<text>	You don&#8217;t need advantage on the attack roll if another enemy of the target is within 5 feet of it, that enemy isn&#8217;t incapacitated, and you don&#8217;t have disadvantage on the attack roll.</text>
				<text>	The amount of the extra damage increases by 1d6 every odd level you gain in this class, to a maximum of 10d6 at 19th level.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 96</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Thieves' Cant</name>
				<text>During your rogue training you learned thieves&#8217; cant, a secret mix of dialect, jargon, and code that allows you to hide messages in seemingly normal conversation. Only another creature that knows thieves&#8217; cant understands such messages. It takes four times longer to convey such a message than it does to speak the same idea plainly.</text>
				<text>	In addition, you understand a set of secret signs and symbols used to convey short, simple messages, such as whether an area is dangerous or the territory of a thieves&#8217; guild, whether loot is nearby, or whether the people in an area are easy marks or will provide a safe house for thieves on the run.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 96</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Cunning Action</name>
				<text>Starting at 2nd level, your quick thinking and agility allow you to move and act quickly. You can take a bonus action on each of your turns in combat. This action can be used only to take the Dash, Disengage, or Hide action.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 96</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots optional="YES">3, 2</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Roguish Archetype</name>
				<text>At 3rd level, you choose an archetype that you emulate in the exercise of your rogue abilities: Thief, Assassin, or Arcane Trickster, all detailed at the end of the class description. Your archetype choice grants you features at 3rd level and then again at 9th, 13th, and 17th level.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 96</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Roguish Archetype: Arcane Trickster</name>
				<text>Some rogues enhance their fine-honed skills of stealth and agility with magic, learning tricks of enchantment and illusion. These rogues include pickpockets and burglars, but also pranksters, mischief-makers, and a significant number of adventurers.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 97</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Spellcasting (Arcane Trickster)</name>
				<text>When you reach 3rd level, you gain the ability to cast spells. See chapter 10 for the general rules of spellcasting and chapter 11 for the wizard spell list. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Cantrips: You learn three cantrips: mage hand and two other cantrips of your choice from the wizard spell list. You learn another wizard cantrip of your choice at 10th level. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Spell Slots: The Arcane Trickster Spellcasting table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your spells of 1st level and higher. To cast one of these spells, you must expend a slot of the spell&#8217;s level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.</text>
				<text>	For example. if you know the 1st-level spell charm person and have a 1st-level and a 2nd-level spell slot available, you can cast charm person using either slot. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Spells Known of 1st-Level and Higher: You know three 1st-level wizard spells of your choice, two of which you must choose from the enchantment and illusion spells on the wizard spell list. </text>
				<text>	You learn one additional spell at 4th, 7th, 8th, 10th, 11th, 13th, 14th, 16th, 19th, and 20th level. Each of these spells must be an enchantment or illusion spell of your choice, and must be of a level for which you have spell slots. For instance, when you reach 7th level in this c1ass. you can learn one new spell of 1st or 2nd level. </text>
				<text>	The spells you learn at 8th. 14th, and 20th level can come from any school of magic. </text>
				<text>	Whenever you gain a level in this c1ass, you can replace one of the wizard spells you know with another spell of your choice from the wizard spell list. The new spell must be of a level for which you have spell slots, and it must be an enchantment or illusion spell, unless you&#8217;re replacing the spell you gained at 8th, 14th, or 20th level. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Spellcasting Ability: Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for your wizard spells, since you learn your spells through dedicated study and memorization. You use your Intelligence whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Intelligence modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a wizard spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Spell save DC = 8+your proficiency bonus+your Intelligence modifier </text>
				<text>	Spell attack modifier = your proficiency bonus+your Intelligence modifier</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 98</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Mage Hand Legerdemain (Arcane Trickster)</name>
				<text>Starting at 3rd level, when you cast mage hand, you can make the spectral hand invisible, and you can perform the following additional tasks with it.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>&#8226; You can stow one object the hand is holding in a container worn or carried by another creature.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>&#8226; You can retrieve an object in a container worn or carried by another creature.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>&#8226; You can use thieves&#8217; tools to pick locks and disarm traps at range.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>	You can perform one of these tasks without being noticed by a creature if you succeed on a Dexterity (Sleight of Hand) check contested by the creature&#8217;s Wisdom (Perception) check.</text>
				<text>	In addition, you can use the bonus action granted by your Cunning Action to control the hand.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 98</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Roguish Archetype: Assassin</name>
				<text>You focus your training on the grim art of death. Those who adhere to this archetype are diverse: hired killers, spies, bounty hunters, and even specially anointed priests trained to exterminate the enemies of their deity. Stealth, poison, and disguise help you eliminate your foes with deadly efficiency.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 97</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Bonus Proficiencies (Assassin)</name>
				<text>When you choose this archetype at 3rd level, you gain proficiency with the disguise kit and the poisoner&#8217;s kit.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 97</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Assassinate (Assassin)</name>
				<text>Starting at 3rd level, you are at your deadliest when you get the drop on your enemies. You have advantage on attack rolls against any creature that hasn&#8217;t taken a turn in the combat yet. In addition, any hit you score against a creature that is surprised is a critical hit.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 97</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Roguish Archetype: Inquisitive</name>
				<text>As an archetypal Inquisitive, you excel at rooting out secrets and unraveling mysteries. You rely on your sharp eye for detail, but also on your finely honed ability to read the words and deeds of other creatures to determine their true intent. You excel at defeating creatures that hide among and prey upon ordinary folk, and your mastery of lore and your keen deductions make you well equipped to expose and end hidden evils.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Xanathar's Guide to Everything, p. 45</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Ear for Deceit (Inquisitive)</name>
				<text>When you choose this archetype at 3rd level, you develop a talent for picking out lies. Whenever you make a Wisdom (Insight) check to sense if a creature is lying, treat a roll of 7 or lower on the d20 as an 8.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Xanathar's Guide to Everything, p. 45</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Eye for Detail (Inquisitive)</name>
				<text>Starting at 3rd level, you can use a bonus action to make a Wisdom (Perception) check to spot a hidden creature or object or to make an Intelligence (Investigation) check to uncover and decipher clues.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Xanathar's Guide to Everything, p. 46</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Insightful Fighting (Inquisitive)</name>
				<text>At 3rd level, you gain the ability to decipher an opponent&#8217;s tactics and develop a counter to them. As a bonus action, you can make a Wisdom (Insight) check against a creature you can see that isn&#8217;t incapacitated, contested by the target&#8217;s Charisma (Deception) check. If you succeed, you can use your Sneak Attack against that creature even if you don&#8217;t have advantage on the attack roll, but not if you have disadvantage on it.</text>
				<text>	This benefit lasts for 1 minute or until you successfully use this feature against a different target.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Xanathar's Guide to Everything, p. 46</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Roguish Archetype: Mastermind</name>
				<text>Your focus is on people and on the influence and secrets they have. Many spies, courtiers, and schemers follow this archetype, leading lives of intrigue. Words are your weapons as often as knives or poison, and secrets and favors are some of your favorite treasures.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Sword Coast Adventurer's Guide, p. 135</text>
				<text>		Xanathar's Guide to Everything, p. 46</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Master of Intrigue (Mastermind)</name>
				<text>When you choose this archetype at 3rd level, you gain proficiency with the disguise kit, the forgery kit, and one gaming set of your choice. You also learn two languages of your choice. </text>
				<text>	Additionally, you can unerringly mimic the speech patterns and accent of a creature that you hear speak for at least 1 minute, allowing you to pass yourself off as a native speaker of a particular land, provided that you know the language.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Sword Coast Adventurer's Guide, p. 135</text>
				<text>		Xanathar's Guide to Everything, p. 46</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Master of Tactics (Mastermind)</name>
				<text>Starting at 3rd level, you can use the Help action as a bonus action. Additionally, when you use the Help action to aid an ally in attacking a creature, the target of that attack can be within 30 feet of you, rather than 5 feet of you, if the target can see or hear you.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Sword Coast Adventurer's Guide, p. 135</text>
				<text>		Xanathar's Guide to Everything, p. 46</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Roguish Archetype: Scout</name>
				<text>You are skilled in stealth and surviving far from the streets of a city, allowing you to scout ahead of your companions during expeditions. Rogues who embrace this archetype are at home in the wilderness and among barbarians and rangers, and many Scouts serve as the eyes and ears of war bands. Amubusher, spy, bounty hunter&#8212;these are just a few of the roles thats Scouts assume as they range the world.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Xanathar's Guide to Everything, p. 47</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Skirmisher (Scout)</name>
				<text>Starting at 3rd level, you are difficult to pin down during a fight. You can move up to half your speed as a reaction when an enemy ends its turn within 5 feet of you. This movement doesn&#8217;t provoke opportunity attacks.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Xanathar's Guide to Everything, p. 47</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Survivalist (Scout)</name>
				<text>When you choose this archetype at 3rd level, you gain proficiency in the Nature and Survival skills if you don&#8217;t already have it. Your proficiency bonus is doubled for any ability check you make that uses either of those proficiencies.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Xanathar's Guide to Everything, p. 47</text>
				<proficiency>nature, survival</proficiency>
				<modifier category="skills">Nature+%0</modifier>
				<modifier category="skills">survival + prof</modifier>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Roguish Archetype: Swashbuckler</name>
				<text>You focus your training on the art of the blade, relying on speed, elegance, and charisma in equal parts. While other warriors are brutes clad in heavy armor, your method of fighting looks more like performance. Duelists and pirates typically belong to this archetype.</text>
				<text>	A Swashbuckler excels in single combat, and can fight with two weapons while safely darting away from an opponent.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Sword Coast Adventurer's Guide, p. 135</text>
				<text>		Xanathar's Guide to Everything, p. 47</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Fancy Footwork (Swashbuckler)</name>
				<text>When you choose this archetype at 3rd level, you learn how to land a strike and then slip away without reprisal. During your turn, if you make a melee attack against a creature, that creature cannot make opportunity attacks against you for the rest of your turn.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Sword Coast Adventurer's Guide, p. 135</text>
				<text>		Xanathar's Guide to Everything, p. 47</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Rakish Audacity (Swashbuckler)</name>
				<text>Starting at 3rd level, your unmistakable confidence propels you into battle. You can give yourself a bonus to your initiative rolls equal to your Charisma modifier.</text>
				<text>	You also gain an additional way to use your Sneak Attack: you don&#8217;t need advantage on the attack roll to use your Sneak Attack against a creature if you are within 5 feet of it, no other creatures are within 5 feet of you, and you don&#8217;t have disadvantage on the attack roll. All the other rules for Sneak Attack still apply to you</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Sword Coast Adventurer's Guide, p. 136</text>
				<text>		Xanathar's Guide to Everything, p. 47</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Roguish Archetype: Thief</name>
				<text>You hone your skills in the larcenous arts. Burglars, bandits, cutpurses, and other criminals typically follow this archetype, but so do rogues who prefer to think of themselves as professional treasure seekers, explorers, delvers, and investigators. In addition to improving your agility and stealth, you learn skills useful for delving into ancient ruins, reading unfamiliar languages, and using magic items you normally couldn&#8217;t employ.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 97</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Fast Hands (Thief)</name>
				<text>Starting at 3rd level, you can use the bonus action granted by your Cunning Action to make a Dexterity (Sleight of Hand) check, use your thieves&#8217; tools to disarm a trap or open a lock, or take the Use an Object action.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 97</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Second-Story Work (Thief)</name>
				<text>When you choose this archetype at 3rd level, you gain the ability to climb faster than normal; climbing no longer costs you extra movement.</text>
				<text>	In addition, when you make a running jump, the distance you cover increases by a number of feet equal to your Dexterity modifier.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 97</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots optional="YES">3, 3</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 10th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can&#8217;t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
				<text>	If your DM uses the optional Feats, you can instead take a feat.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 96</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots optional="YES">3, 3</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Uncanny Dodge</name>
				<text>Starting at 5th level, when an attacker that you can see hits you with an attack, you can use your reaction to halve the attack&#8217;s damage against you.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 96</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots optional="YES">3, 3</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots optional="YES">3, 4, 2</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Evasion</name>
				<text>Beginning at 7th level, you can nimbly dodge out of the way of certain area effects, such as a red dragon&#8217;s fiery breath or an ice storm spell. When you are subjected to an effect that allows you to make a Dexterity saving throw to take only half damage, you instead take no damage if you succeed on the saving throw, and only half damage if you fail.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 96</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots optional="YES">3, 4, 2</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Ability Score Improvement (2nd)</name>
				<text>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 10th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can&#8217;t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
				<text>	If your DM uses the optional Feats, you can instead take a feat.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 96</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots optional="YES">3, 4, 2</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Magical Ambush (Arcane Trickster)</name>
				<text>Starting at 9th level, if you are hidden from a creature when you cast a spell on it, the creature has disadvantage on any saving throw it makes against the spell this turn.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 98</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Infiltration Expertise (Assassin)</name>
				<text>Starting at 9th level, you can unfailingly create false identities for yourself. You must spend seven days and 25 gp to establish the history, profession, and affiliations for an identity. You can&#8217;t establish an identity that belongs to someone else. For example, you might acquire appropriate clothing, letters of introduction, and official-looking certification to establish yourself as a member of a trading house from a remote city so you can insinuate yourself into the company of other wealthy merchants.</text>
				<text>	Thereafter, if you adopt the new identity as a disguise, other creatures believe you to be that person until given an obvious reason not to.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 97</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Steady Eye (Inquisitive)</name>
				<text>Starting at 9th level, you have advantage on any Wisdom (Perception) or Intelligence (Investigation) check if you move no more than half your speed on the same turn.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Xanathar's Guide to Everything, p. 46</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Insightful Manipulator (Mastermind)</name>
				<text>Starting at 9th level, if you spend at least 1 minute observing or interacting with another creature outside combat, you can learn certain information about its capabilities compared to your own. The DM tells you if the creature is your equal, superior, or inferior in regard to two of the following characteristics of your choice: </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>&#8226; Intelligence score </text>
				<text>&#8226; Wisdom score </text>
				<text>&#8226; Charisma score </text>
				<text>&#8226; Class levels (if any) </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>	At the DM&#8217;s option, you might also realize you know a piece of the creature&#8217;s history or one of its personality traits, if it has any.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Sword Coast Adventurer's Guide, p. 135</text>
				<text>		Xanathar's Guide to Everything, p. 46</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Superior Mobility (Scout)</name>
				<text>At 9th level, your walking speed increases by 10 feet. If you have a climbing or swimming speed, this increase applies to that speed as well.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Xanathar's Guide to Everything, p. 47</text>
				<modifier category="bonus">speed + 10</modifier>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Panache (Swashbuckler)</name>
				<text>At 9th level, your charm becomes extraordinarily beguiling. As an action, you can make a Charisma (Persuasion) check contested by a creature&#8217;s Wisdom (Insight) check. The creature must be able to hear you, and the two of you must share a language.</text>
				<text>	If you succeed on the check and the creature is hostile to you, it has disadvantage on attack rolls against targets other than you and can&#8217;t make opportunity attacks against targets other than you. This effect lasts for 1 minute, until one of your companions attacks the target or affects it with a spell, or until you and the target are more than 60 feet apart.</text>
				<text>	If you succeed on the check and the creature isn&#8217;t hostile to you, it is charmed by you for 1 minute. While charmed, it regards you as a friendly aquaintance. This effect ends immediately if you or your companions do anything harmful to it.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Charmed:</text>
				<text>&#8226; A charmed creature can't attack the charmer or target the charmer with harmful abilities or magical effects.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>&#8226; The charmer has advantage on any ability check to interact socially with the creature.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Sword Coast Adventurer's Guide, p. 136</text>
				<text>		Xanathar's Guide to Everything, p. 47</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Supreme Sneak (Thief)</name>
				<text>Starting at 9th level, you have advantage on a Dexterity (Stealth) check if you move no more than half your speed on the same turn.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 97</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots optional="YES">4, 4, 3</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Ability Score Improvement (3rd)</name>
				<text>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 10th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can&#8217;t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
				<text>	If your DM uses the optional Feats, you can instead take a feat.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 96</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots optional="YES">4, 4, 3</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Reliable Talent</name>
				<text>By 11th level, you have refined your chosen skills until they approach perfection. Whenever you make an ability check that lets you add your proficiency bonus, you can treat a d20 roll of 9 or lower as a 10.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 96</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots optional="YES">4, 4, 3</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Ability Score Improvement (4th)</name>
				<text>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 10th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can&#8217;t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
				<text>	If your DM uses the optional Feats, you can instead take a feat.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 96</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots optional="YES">4, 4, 3, 2</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Versatile Trickster (Arcane Trickster)</name>
				<text>At 13th level, you gain the ability to distract targets with your mage hand. As a bonus action on your turn, you can designate a creature within 5 feet of the spectral hand created by the spell. Doing so gives you advantage on attack rolls against that creature until the end of the turn.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 98</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Imposter (Assassin)</name>
				<text>At 13th level, you gain the ability to unerringly mimic another person&#8217;s speech, writing, and behavior. You must spend at least three hours studying these three components of the person&#8217;s behavior, listening to speech, examining handwriting, and observing mannerisms.</text>
				<text>	Your ruse is indiscernible to the casual observer. If a wary creature suspects something is amiss, you have advantage on any Charisma (Deception) check you make to avoid detection.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 97</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Unerring Eye (Inquisitive)</name>
				<text>Beginning at 13th level, your senses are almost impossible to foil. As an action, you sense the presence of illusions, shapechangers not in their original form, and other magic designed to deceive the senses within 30 feet of you, provided you aren&#8217;t blinded or deafened. You sense that an effect is attempting to trick you, but you gain no insight into what is hidden or into its true nature.</text>
				<text>	You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Wisdom modifier (minimum of once), and you regain all expended uses of it when you finish a long rest.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Xanathar's Guide to Everything, p. 46</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Misdirection (Mastermind)</name>
				<text>Beginning at 13th level, you can sometimes cause another creature to suffer an attack meant for you. When you are targeted by an attack while a creature within 5 feet of you is granting you cover against that attack, you can use your reaction to have the attack target that creature instead of you.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Sword Coast Adventurer's Guide, p. 135</text>
				<text>		Xanathar's Guide to Everything, p. 46</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Ambush Master (Scout)</name>
				<text>Starting at 13th level, you excel at leading ambushes and acting first in a fight.</text>
				<text>	You have advantage on initiative rolls. In addition, the first creature you hit during the first round of combat becomes easier for you and others to strike; attack rolls against that target have advantage until the start of your next turn.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Xanathar's Guide to Everything, p. 47</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Elegant Maneuver (Swashbuckler)</name>
				<text>Starting at 13th level, you can use a bonus action on your turn to gain advantage on the next Dexterity (Acrobatics) or Strength (Athletics) check you make during the same turn.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Sword Coast Adventurer's Guide, p. 136</text>
				<text>		Xanathar's Guide to Everything, p. 47</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Use Magic Device (Thief)</name>
				<text>By 13th level, you have learned enough about the workings of magic that you can improvise the use of items even when they are not intended for you. You ignore all class, race, and level requirements on the use of magic items.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 97</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots optional="YES">4, 4, 3, 2</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Blindsense</name>
				<text>Starting at 14th level, if you are able to hear, you are aware of the location of any hidden or invisible creature within 10 feet of you.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 96</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots optional="YES">4, 4, 3, 2</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Slippery Mind</name>
				<text>By 15th level, you have acquired greater mental strength. You gain proficiency in Wisdom saving throws.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 96</text>
				<proficiency>wisdom</proficiency>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots optional="YES">4, 4, 3, 3</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Ability Score Improvement (5th)</name>
				<text>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 10th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can&#8217;t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
				<text>	If your DM uses the optional Feats, you can instead take a feat.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 96</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots optional="YES">4, 4, 3, 3</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Spell Thief (Arcane Trickster)</name>
				<text>At 17th level, you gain the ability to magically steal the knowledge of how to cast a spell from another spellcaster.</text>
				<text>	Immediately after a creature casts a spell that targets you or includes you in its area of effect, you can use your reaction to force the creature to make a saving throw with its spellcasting ability modifier. The DC equals your spell save DC. On a failed save, you negate the spell&#8217;s effect against you, and you steal the knowledge of the spell if it is at least 1st level and of a level you can cast (it doesn&#8217;t need to be a wizard spell). For the next 8 hours, you know the spell and can cast it using your spell slots. The creature can&#8217;t cast that spell until the 8 hours have passed.</text>
				<text>	Once you use this feature, you can&#8217;t use it again until you finish a long rest.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 98</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Death Strike (Assassin)</name>
				<text>Starting at 17th level, you become a master of instant death. When you attack and hit a creature that is surprised, it must make a Constitution saving throw (DC 8 + your Dexterity modifier + your proficiency bonus). On a failed save, double the damage of your attack against the creature.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 97</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Eye for Weakness (Inquisitive)</name>
				<text>At 17th level, you learn to exploit a creature&#8217;s weaknesses by carefully studying its tactics and movement. While your Insightful Fighting feature applies to a creature, your Sneak Attack damage against that creature increases by 3d6.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Xanathar's Guide to Everything, p. 46</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Soul of Deceit (Mastermind)</name>
				<text>Starting at 17th level, your thoughts can&#8217;t be read by telepathy or other means, unless you allow it. You can present false thoughts by making a Charisma (Deception) check contested by the mind reader&#8217;s Wisdom (Insight) check.</text>
				<text>	Additionally, no matter what you say, magic that would determine if you are telling the truth indicates you are being truthful, if you so choose, and you can&#8217;t be compelled to tell the truth by magic.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Sword Coast Adventurer's Guide, p. 135</text>
				<text>		Xanathar's Guide to Everything, p. 46</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Sudden Strike (Scout)</name>
				<text>Starting at 17th level, you can strike with deadly speed. If you take the Attack action on your turn, you can make one additional attack as a bonus action. This attack can benefit from your Sneak Attack even if you have already used it this turn, but you can&#8217;t use your Sneak Attack against the same target more than once in a turn.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Xanathar's Guide to Everything, p. 47</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Master Duelist (Swashbuckler)</name>
				<text>Beginning at 17th level, your mastery of the blade lets you turn failure into success in combat. If you miss with an attack roll, you can roll it again with advantage. Once you do so, you can&#8217;t use this feature again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Sword Coast Adventurer's Guide, p. 136</text>
				<text>		Xanathar's Guide to Everything, p. 47</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Thief's Reflexes (Thief)</name>
				<text>When you reach 17th level, you have become adept at laying ambushes and quickly escaping danger. You can take two turns during the first round of any combat. You take your first turn at your normal initiative and your second turn at your initiative minus 10. You can&#8217;t use this feature when you are surprised.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 97</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots optional="YES">4, 4, 3, 3</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Elusive</name>
				<text>Beginning at 18th level, you are so evasive that attackers rarely gain the upper hand against you. No attack roll has advantage against you while you aren&#8217;t incapacitated.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 96</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots optional="YES">4, 4, 3, 3, 1</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Ability Score Improvement (6th)</name>
				<text>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 10th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can&#8217;t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
				<text>	If your DM uses the optional Feats, you can instead take a feat.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 96</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots optional="YES">4, 4, 3, 3, 1</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Stroke of Luck</name>
				<text>At 20th level, you have an uncanny knack for succeeding when you need to. If your attack misses a target within range, you can turn the miss into a hit. Alternatively, if you fail an ability check, you can treat the d20 roll as a 20.</text>
				<text>	Once you use this feature, you can&#8217;t use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 97</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

</subclass>

<subclass>
	<name>Sorcerer</name>
	<hd>6</hd>
	<proficiency>Constitution, Charisma, Arcana, Deception, Insight, Intimidation, Persuasion, Religion</proficiency>
	<spellAbility>Charisma</spellAbility>
	<numSkills>2</numSkills>
		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Starting Sorcerer</name>
				<text>As a 1st-level Sorcerer, you begin play with 6+your Constitution modifier hit points.</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>You are proficient with the following items, in addition to any proficiencies provided by your race or background.</text>
				<text>&#8226; Armor: none</text>
				<text>&#8226; Weapons: daggers, darts, slings, quarterstaffs, light crossbows</text>
				<text>&#8226; Tools: none</text>
				<text>&#8226; Skills: Choose two from Arcana, Deception, Insight, Intimidation, Persuasion, and Religion</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>You begin play with the following equipment, in addition to any equipment provided by your background.</text>
				<text>&#8226; (a) a light crossbow and 20 bolts or (b) any simple weapon</text>
				<text>&#8226; (a) a component pouch or (b) an arcane focus</text>
				<text>&#8226; (a) a dungeoneer's pack or (b) an explorer's pack</text>
				<text>&#8226; Two daggers </text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>Alternatively, you may start with 3d4x10 gp and choose your own equipment.</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 99</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Multiclass Sorcerer</name>
				<text>To multiclass as a Sorcerer, you must meet the following prerequisites:</text>
				<text>&#8226; Charisma 13</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>You gain the following proficiencies:</text>
				<text>&#8226; none</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 163</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>
<armor>none</armor><weapons>daggers, darts, slings, quarterstaffs, light crossbows</weapons><tools>none</tools><wealth>3d4x10</wealth>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots>4, 2</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Spellcasting</name>
				<text>An event in your past, or in the life of a parent or ancestor, left an indelible mark on you, infusing you with arcane magic. This font of magic, whatever its origin, fuels your spells. See chapter 10 for the general rules of spellcasting and chapter 11 for the sorcerer spell list. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Cantrips:</text>
				<text>	At 1st level, you know four cantrips of your choice from the sorcerer spell list. You learn an additional sorcerer cantrip of your choice at 4th level and another at 10th level. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Spell Slots:</text>
				<text>	The Sorcerer table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your spells of 1st level and higher. To cast one of these sorcerer spells, you must expend a slot of the spell&#8217;s level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.</text>
				<text>	For example, if you know the 1st-level spell burning hands and have a 1st-level and a 2nd-level spell slot available, you can cast burning hands using either slot. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Spells Known of 1st Level and Higher:</text>
				<text>	You know two 1st-level spells of your choice from the sorcerer spell list.</text>
				<text>	You learn an additional sorcerer spell of your choice at each level except 12th, 14th, 16th, 18th, 19th, and 20th. Each of these spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots. For instance, when you reach 3rd level in this class, you can learn one new spell of 1st or 2nd level.</text>
				<text>	Additionally, when you gain a level in this class, you can choose one of the sorcerer spells you know and replace it with another spell from the sorcerer spell list, which also must be of a level for which you have spell slots.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Spellcasting Ability:</text>
				<text>	Charisma is your spellcasting ability for your sorcerer spells, since the power of your magic relies on your ability to project your will into the world. You use your Charisma whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Charisma modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a sorcerer spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.</text>
				<text>	Spell save DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier</text>
				<text>	Spell attack modifier = your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 101</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Sorcerous Origin</name>
				<text>Choose a sorcerous origin, which describes the source of your innate magical power: Draconic Bloodline or Wild Magic, both detailed at the end of the class description.</text>
				<text>	Your choice grants you features when you choose it at 1st level and again at 6th, 14th, and 18th level.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 101</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Sorcerous Origin: Divine Soul</name>
				<text>Sometimes the spark of magic that fuels a sorcerer comes from a divine source that glimmers within the soul. Having such a blessed soul is a sign that your innate magic might come from a distant but powerful familial connection to a divine being. Perhaps your ancestor was an angel, transformed into a mortal and sent to fight in a god&#8217;s name. Or your birth might align with an ancient prophecy, marking you as a servant of the gods or a chosen vessel of divine magic.</text>
				<text>	A Divine Soul, with a natural magnetism, is seen as a threat ny some religious hierarchies. As an outsider who commands sacred power, a Divine Soul can undermine an existing order by claiming a direct tie to the divine.</text>
				<text>	In some cultures, only those who can claim the power of a Divine Soul may command religious power. In these lands, ecclesiastical positions are dominated by a few bloodlines and preserved over generations.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Xanathar's Guide to Everything, p. 50</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Divine Magic (Divine Soul)</name>
				<text>Your link to the divine allows you to learn spells from the cleric class. When your Spellcasting feature lets you learn or replace a sorcerer cantrip or a sorcerer spell of 1st level or higher, you can choose the new spell from the cleric spell list or the sorcerer spell list. You must otherwise obey all the restrictions for selecting the spell, and it becomes a sorcerer spell for you. </text>
				<text>	In addition, choose an affinity for the source of your divine power: good, evil, law, chaos, or neutrality. You learn an additional spell based on that affinity, as shown below. It is a sorcerer spell for you, but it doesn;t count against your number of sorcerer spells known. If you later replace this spell, you must replace it with a spell from the cleric spell list.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Affinity&#8212;Spell:</text>
				<text>Good&#8212;cure wounds</text>
				<text>Evil&#8212;inflict wounds</text>
				<text>Law&#8212;bless</text>
				<text>Chaos&#8212;bane</text>
				<text>Neutrality&#8212;protection from evil and good</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Xanathar's Guide to Everything, p. 50</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Favored by the Gods (Divine Soul)</name>
				<text>Starting at 1st level, divine power guards your destiny. If you fail a saving throw or miss with an attack roll, you can roll 2d4 and add it to the total, possibly changing the outcome. Once you use this feature, you can&#8217;t use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Xanathar's Guide to Everything, p. 50</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Sorcerous Origin: Draconic Bloodline</name>
				<text>Your innate magic comes from draconic magic that was mingled with your blood or that of your ancestors. Most often, sorcerers with this origin trace their descent back to a mighty sorcerer of ancient times who made a bargain with a dragon or who might even have claimed a dragon parent. Some of these bloodlines are well established in the world, but most are obscure. Any given sorcerer could be the first of a new bloodline, as a result of a pact or some other exceptional circumstance.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 102</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Black Dragon Ancestor (Black Draconic Bloodline)</name>
				<text>You have a black dragon ancestor.</text>
				<text>	You can speak, read, and write Draconic. Additionally, whenever you make a Charisma check when interacting with dragons, your proficiency bonus is doubled if it applies to the check.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 102</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Blue Dragon Ancestor (Blue Draconic Bloodline)</name>
				<text>You have a blue dragon ancestor.</text>
				<text>	You can speak, read, and write Draconic. Additionally, whenever you make a Charisma check when interacting with dragons, your proficiency bonus is doubled if it applies to the check.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 102</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Brass Dragon Ancestor (Brass Draconic Bloodline)</name>
				<text>You have a brass dragon ancestor.</text>
				<text>	You can speak, read, and write Draconic. Additionally, whenever you make a Charisma check when interacting with dragons, your proficiency bonus is doubled if it applies to the check.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 102</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Bronze Dragon Ancestor (Bronze Draconic Bloodline)</name>
				<text>You have a bronze dragon ancestor.</text>
				<text>	You can speak, read, and write Draconic. Additionally, whenever you make a Charisma check when interacting with dragons, your proficiency bonus is doubled if it applies to the check.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 102</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Copper Dragon Ancestor (Copper Draconic Bloodline)</name>
				<text>You have a copper dragon ancestor.</text>
				<text>	You can speak, read, and write Draconic. Additionally, whenever you make a Charisma check when interacting with dragons, your proficiency bonus is doubled if it applies to the check.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 102</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Gold Dragon Ancestor (Gold Draconic Bloodline)</name>
				<text>You have a gold dragon ancestor.</text>
				<text>	You can speak, read, and write Draconic. Additionally, whenever you make a Charisma check when interacting with dragons, your proficiency bonus is doubled if it applies to the check.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 102</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Green Dragon Ancestor (Green Draconic Bloodline)</name>
				<text>You have a green dragon ancestor.</text>
				<text>	You can speak, read, and write Draconic. Additionally, whenever you make a Charisma check when interacting with dragons, your proficiency bonus is doubled if it applies to the check.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 102</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Red Dragon Ancestor (Red Draconic Bloodline)</name>
				<text>You have a red dragon ancestor.</text>
				<text>	You can speak, read, and write Draconic. Additionally, whenever you make a Charisma check when interacting with dragons, your proficiency bonus is doubled if it applies to the check.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 102</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Silver Dragon Ancestor (Silver Draconic Bloodline)</name>
				<text>You have a silver dragon ancestor.</text>
				<text>	You can speak, read, and write Draconic. Additionally, whenever you make a Charisma check when interacting with dragons, your proficiency bonus is doubled if it applies to the check.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 102</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>White Dragon Ancestor (White Draconic Bloodline)</name>
				<text>You have a white dragon ancestor.</text>
				<text>	You can speak, read, and write Draconic. Additionally, whenever you make a Charisma check when interacting with dragons, your proficiency bonus is doubled if it applies to the check.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 102</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Draconic Resilience (Draconic Bloodline)</name>
				<text>As magic flows through your body, it causes physical traits of your dragon ancestors to emerge. At 1st level, your hit point maximum increases by 1 and increases by 1 again whenever you gain a level in this class.</text>
				<text>	Additionally, parts of your skin are covered by a thin sheen of dragon-like scales. When you aren&#8217;t wearing armor, your AC equals 13 + your Dexterity modifier.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 102</text>
				<modifier category="bonus">ac +3</modifier>
				<modifier category="bonus">hp +1</modifier>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Sorcerous Origin: Shadow Magic</name>
				<text>You are a creature of shadow, for your innate magic comes from the Shadowfell itself. You might trace your lineage to an entity from that place, or perhaps you were exposed to its fell energy and transformed by it.</text>
				<text>	The power of shadow magic casts a strange pall over your physical presence. The spark of life that sustains you is muffled, as if it struggles to remain viable against the dark energy that imbues your soul. At your option, you can pick from or roll on the following table to create a unique quirk for your character.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>d6&#8212;Quirk:</text>
				<text>1&#8212;You are always icy cold to the touch.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>2&#8212;When you are asleep, you don&#8217;t appear to breathe (though you must still breathe to survive).</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>3&#8212;You don&#8217;t seem to bleed, even when badly injured.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>4&#8212;Your heart beats once per minute. This event sometimes surprises you.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>5&#8212;You have trouble remembering that living creatures and corpses should be treated differently.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>6&#8212;You blinked. Once. Last week.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Xanathar's Guide to Everything, p. 50</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Eyes of the Dark (Shadow Magic)</name>
				<text>Starting at 1st level, you have darkvision with a range of 120 feet.</text>
				<text>	When you reach 3rd level in this class, you learn the darkness spell, which doesn&#8217;t count against your number of sorcerer spells known. In addition, you can cast it by spending 2 sorcery points or by expending a spell slot. If you cast it with sorcery points, you can see through the darkness created by the spell.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Xanathar's Guide to Everything, p. 51</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Strength of the Grave (Shadow Magic)</name>
				<text>Starting at 1st level, your existence in a twilight state between life and death makes you difficult to defeat. When damage reduces you to 0 hit points, you can make a Charisma saving throw (DC 5+the damage taken). On a success, you instead drop to 1 hit point. You cannot use this feature if you are reduced to 0 hit points by radiant damage or by a critical hit.</text>
				<text>	After the saving throw succeeds, you can&#8217;t use this feature again until you finish a long rest.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Xanathar's Guide to Everything, p. 51</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Sorcerous Origin: Storm Sorcery</name>
				<text>Your innate magic comes from the power of elemental air. Many with this power can trace their magic back to a near-death experience caused by the Great Rain, but perhaps you were born during a howling gale so powerful that folk still tell stories of it, or your lineage might include the influence of potent air creatures such as vaati or djinn Whatever the case, the magic of the storm permeates your being.</text>
				<text>	Storm sorcerers are invaluable members of a ship&#8217;s crew. Their magic allows them to exert control over wind and weather in their immediate area. Their abilities also prove useful in repelling attacks by sahuagin, pirates, and other waterborne threats.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Sword Coast Adventurer's Guide, p. 137</text>
				<text>		Xanathar's Guide to Everything p. 51</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Wind Speaker (Storm Sorcery)</name>
				<text>The arcane magic you command is infused with elemental air. You can speak, read, and write Primordial. (Knowing this language allows you to understand and be understood by those who speak its dialects: Aquan, Auran, Ignan, and Terran.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Sword Coast Adventurer's Guide, p. 137</text>
				<text>		Xanathar's Guide to Everything p. 52</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Tempestuous Magic (Storm Sorcery)</name>
				<text>Starting at 1st level, you can use a bonus action on your turn to cause whirling gusts of elemental air to briefly surround you, immediately before or after you cast a spell of 1st level or higher. Doing so allows you to fly up to 10 feet without provoking opportunity attacks.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Sword Coast Adventurer's Guide, p. 137</text>
				<text>		Xanathar's Guide to Everything p. 52</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Sorcerous Origin: Wild Magic</name>
				<text>Your innate magic comes from the wild forces of chaos that underlie the order of creation. You might have endured exposure to some form of raw magic, perhaps through a planar portal leading to Limbo, the Elemental Planes, or the mysterious Far Realm. Perhaps you were blessed by a powerful fey creature or marked by a demon. Or your magic could be a fluke of your birth, with no apparent cause or reason. However it came to be, this chaotic magic churns within you, waiting for any outlet.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 103</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Wild Magic Surge (Wild Magic)</name>
				<text>Starting when you choose this origin at 1st level, your spellcasting can unleash surges of untamed magic. Once per turn, the DM can have you roll a d20 immediately after you cast a sorcerer spell of 1st level or higher. If you roll a 1, roll on the Wild Magic Surge table to create a magical effect. If that effect is a spell, it is too wild to be affected by your Metamagic, and if it normally requires concentration, it doesn&#8217;t require concentration in this case; the spell lasts for its full duration. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Wild Magic Surge: </text>
				<text>d100 &#8212; Effect: </text>
				<text>01-02 &#8212; Roll on this table at the start of each of your turns for the next minute, ignoring this result on subsequent rolls. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>03-04 &#8212; For the next minute, you can see any invisible creature if you have line of sight to it. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>05-06 &#8212; A modron chosen and controlled by the DM appears in an unoccupied space within 5 feet of you, then disappears 1 minute later. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>07-08 &#8212; You cast fireball as a 3rd-level spell centered on yourself. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>09-10 &#8212; You cast magic missile as a 5th-level spell. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>11-12 &#8212; Roll a d10. Your height changes by a number of inches equal to the roll. If the roll is odd, you shrink. If the roll is even, you grow. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>13-14 &#8212; You cast confusion centered on yourself. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>15-16 &#8212; For the next minute, you regain 5 hit points at the start of each of your turns. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>17-18 &#8212; You grow a long beard made of feathers that remains until you sneeze, at which point the feathers explode out from your face. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>19-20 &#8212; You cast grease centered on yourself. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>21-22 &#8212; Creatures have disadvantage on saving throws against the next spell you cast in the next minute that involves a saving throw. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>23-24 &#8212; Your skin turns a vibrant shade of blue. A remove curse spell can end this effect. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>25-26 &#8212; An eye appears on your forehead for the next minute. During that time, you have advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on sight. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>27-28 &#8212; For the next minute, all your spells with a casting time feet of 1 action have a casting time of 1 bonus action. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>29-30 &#8212; You teleport up to 60 feet to an unoccupied space of your choice that you can see. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>31-32 &#8212; You are transported to the Astral Plane until the end of your next turn, after which time you return to the space you previously occupied or the nearest unoccupied space if that space is occupied. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>33-34 &#8212; Maximize the damage of the next damaging spell you cast within the next minute. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>35-36 &#8212; Roll a d10. Your age changes by a number of years equal to the roll. If the roll is odd, you get younger (minimum 1 year old). If the roll is even, you get older. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>37-38 &#8212; 1d6 flumphs controlled by the DM appear in unoccupied spaces within 60 feet of you and are frightened of you. They vanish after 1 minute. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>39-40 &#8212; You regain 2d10 hit points. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>41-42 &#8212; You turn into a potted plant until the start of your next turn. While a plant, you are incapacitated and have vulnerability to all damage. If you drop to 0 hit points, your pot breaks, and your form reverts. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>43-44 &#8212; For the next minute, you can teleport up to 20 feet as next minute. a bonus action on each of your turns. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>45-46 &#8212; You cast levitate on yourself. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>47-48 &#8212; A unicorn controlled by the DM appears in a space within 5 feet of you, then disappears 1 minute later. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>49-50 &#8212; You can&#8217;t speak for the next minute. Whenever you try, pink bubbles float out of your mouth. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>51-52 &#8212; A spectral shield hovers near you for the next minute, granting you a +2 bonus to AC and immunity to magic missile. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>53-54 &#8212; You are immune to being intoxicated by alcohol for the next 5d6 days. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>55-56 &#8212; Your hair falls out but grows back within 24 hours. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>57-58 &#8212; For the next minute, any flammable object you touch that isn&#8217;t being worn or carried by another creature bursts into flame. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>59-60 &#8212; You regain your lowest-level expended spell slot. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>61-62 &#8212; For the next minute, you must shout when you speak. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>63-64 &#8212; You cast fog cloud centered on yourself. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>65-66 &#8212; Up to three creatures you choose within 30 feet of you take 4d10 lightning damage. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>67-68 &#8212; You are frightened by the nearest creature until the end of your next turn. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>69-70 &#8212; Each creature within 30 feet of you becomes invisible for the next minute. The invisibility ends on a creature when it attacks or casts a spell. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>71-72 &#8212; You gain resistance to all damage for the next minute. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>73-74 &#8212; A random creature within 60 feet of you becomes poisoned for 1d4 hours. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>75-76 &#8212; You glow with bright light in a 30-foot radius for the next minute. Any creature that ends its turn within 5 feet of you is blinded until the end of its next turn. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>79-80 &#8212; Illusory butterflies and flower petals flutter in the air within 10 feet of you for the next minute. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>77-78 &#8212; You cast polymorph on yourself. If you fail the saving throw, you turn into a sheep for the spell&#8217;s duration. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>81-82 &#8212; You can take one additional action immediately. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>83-84 &#8212; Each creature within 30 feet of you takes 1d10 necrotic damage. You regain hit points equal to the sum of the necrotic damage dealt. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>85-86 &#8212; You cast mirror image. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>87-88 &#8212; You cast fly on a random creature within 60 feet of you. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>89-90 &#8212; You become invisible for the next minute. During that time, other creatures can&#8217;t hear you. The invisibility ends if you attack or cast a spell. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>91-92 &#8212; If you die within the next minute, you immediately come back to life as if by the reincarnate spell. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>93-94 &#8212; Your size increases by one size category for the next minute. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>95-96 &#8212; You and all creatures within 30 feet of you gain vulnerability to piercing damage for the next minute. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>97-98 &#8212; You are surrounded by faint, ethereal music for the next minute. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>99-100 &#8212; You regain all expended sorcery points.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 103</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Tides of Chaos (Wild Magic)</name>
				<text>Starting at 1st level, you can manipulate the forces of chance and chaos to gain advantage on one attack roll, ability check, or saving throw. Once you do so, you must finish a long rest before you can use this feature again.</text>
				<text>	Any time before you regain the use of this feature, the DM can have you roll on the Wild Magic Surge table immediately after you cast a sorcerer spell of 1st level or higher. You then regain the use of this feature.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 103</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots>4, 3</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Font of Magic</name>
				<text>At 2nd level, you tap into a deep wellspring of magic within yourself. This wellspring is represented by sorcery points, which allow you to create a variety of magical effects. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Sorcery Points:</text>
				<text>	You have a number of sorcery points equal to your sorcerer level. You can never have more sorcery points than your sorcerer level. You regain all spent sorcery points when you finish a long rest. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Flexible Casting:</text>
				<text>	You can use your sorcery points to gain additional spell slots, or sacrifice spell slots to gain additional sorcery points. You learn other ways to use your sorcery points as you reach higher levels. Spell slots you create using sorcery poinys are lost at the end of a long rest.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Creating Spell Slots:</text>
				<text>	You can transform unexpended sorcery points into one spell slot as a bonus action on your turn. It costs 2 sorcery points to create a 1st level spell slot, 3 to create a 2nd level slot, 5 for a 3rd level slot, 6 for a 4th level slot, or 7 for a 5th level slot. You can create spell slots no higher in level than 5th.</text>
				<text>	Any spell slot you create with this feature vanishes when you finish a long rest.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Converting a Spell Slot to Sorcery Points:</text>
				<text>	As a bonus action on your turn, you can expend one spell slot and gain a number of sorcery points equal to the slot&#8217;s level.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 101</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots>4, 4, 2</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Metamagic</name>
				<text>At 3rd level, you gain the ability to twist your spells to suit your needs. You gain two of the following Metamagic options of your choice. You gain another one at 10th and 17th level.</text>
				<text>	You can use only one Metamagic option on a spell when you cast it, unless otherwise noted.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 101</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Metamagic: Careful Spell</name>
				<text>When you cast a spell that forces other creatures to make a saving throw, you can protect some of those creatures from the spell&#8217;s full force. To do so, you spend 1 sorcery point and choose a number of those creatures up to your Charisma modifier (minimum of one creature). A chosen creature automatically succeeds on its saving throw against the spell. </text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 102</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Metamagic: Distant Spell</name>
				<text>When you cast a spell that has a range of 5 feet or greater, you can spend 1 sorcery point to double the range of the spell.</text>
				<text>	When you cast a spell that has a range of touch, you can spend 1 sorcery point to make the range of the spell 30 feet. </text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 102</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Metamagic: Empowered Spell</name>
				<text>When you roll damage for a spell, you can spend 1 sorcery point to reroll a number of the damage dice up to your Charisma modifier (minimum of one). You must use the new rolls.</text>
				<text>	You can use Empowered Spell even if you have already used a different Metamagic option during the casting of the spell. </text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 102</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Metamagic: Extended Spell</name>
				<text>When you cast a spell that has a duration of 1 minute or longer, you can spend 1 sorcery point to double its duration, to a maximum duration of 24 hours. </text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 102</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Metamagic: Heightened Spell</name>
				<text>When you cast a spell that forces a creature to make a saving throw to resist its effects, you can spend 3 sorcery points to give one target of the spell disadvantage on its first saving throw made against the spell. </text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 102</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Metamagic: Quickened Spell</name>
				<text>When you cast a spell that has a casting time of 1 action, you can spend 2 sorcery points to change the casting time to 1 bonus action for this casting. </text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 102</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Metamagic: Subtle Spell</name>
				<text>When you cast a spell, you can spend 1 sorcery point to cast it without any somatic or verbal components. </text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 102</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Metamagic: Twinned Spell</name>
				<text>When you cast a spell that targets only one creature and doesn&#8217;t have a range of self, you can spend a number of sorcery points equal to the spell&#8217;s level to target a second creature in range with the same spell (1 sorcery point if the spell is a cantrip).</text>
				<text>	To be eligible, a spell must be incapable of targeting more than one creature at the spell&#8217;s current level. For example, magic missile and scorching ray aren&#8217;t eligible, but ray of frost and chromatic orb are.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 102</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots>5, 4, 3</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can&#8217;t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
				<text>	If your DM uses the optional Feats, you can instead take a feat.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 102</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots>5, 4, 3, 2</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots>5, 4, 3, 3</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Empowered Healing (Divine Soul)</name>
				<text>Starting at 6th level, the divine energy coursing through you can empower healing spells. Whenever you or an ally within 5 feet of you roll dice to determine the number of hit points a spell restores, you can spend 1 sorcery point to reroll any number of those dice once, provided you aren&#8217;t incapacitated. You can use this feature only once per turn.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Xanathar's Guide to Everything, p. 50</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Elemental Affinity (Black Draconic Bloodline)</name>
				<text>Starting at 6th level, when you cast a spell that deals acid damage, you can add your Charisma modifier to one damage roll of that spell. At the same time, you can spend 1 sorcery point to gain resistance to acid damage for 1 hour.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 102</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Elemental Affinity (Blue Draconic Bloodline)</name>
				<text>Starting at 6th level, when you cast a spell that deals lightning damage, you can add your Charisma modifier to one damage roll of that spell. At the same time, you can spend 1 sorcery point to gain resistance to lightning damage for 1 hour.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 102</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Elemental Affinity (Brass Draconic Bloodline)</name>
				<text>Starting at 6th level, when you cast a spell that deals fire damage, you can add your Charisma modifier to one damage roll of that spell. At the same time, you can spend 1 sorcery point to gain resistance to fire damage for 1 hour.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 102</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Elemental Affinity (Bronze Draconic Bloodline)</name>
				<text>Starting at 6th level, when you cast a spell that deals lightning damage, you can add your Charisma modifier to one damage roll of that spell. At the same time, you can spend 1 sorcery point to gain resistance to lightning damage for 1 hour.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 102</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Elemental Affinity (Copper Draconic Bloodline)</name>
				<text>Starting at 6th level, when you cast a spell that deals acid damage, you can add your Charisma modifier to one damage roll of that spell. At the same time, you can spend 1 sorcery point to gain resistance to acid damage for 1 hour.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 102</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Elemental Affinity (Gold Draconic Bloodline)</name>
				<text>Starting at 6th level, when you cast a spell that deals fire damage, you can add your Charisma modifier to one damage roll of that spell. At the same time, you can spend 1 sorcery point to gain resistance to fire damage for 1 hour.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 102</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Elemental Affinity (Green Draconic Bloodline)</name>
				<text>Starting at 6th level, when you cast a spell that deals poison damage, you can add your Charisma modifier to one damage roll of that spell. At the same time, you can spend 1 sorcery point to gain resistance to poison damage for 1 hour.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 102</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Elemental Affinity (Red Draconic Bloodline)</name>
				<text>Starting at 6th level, when you cast a spell that deals fire damage, you can add your Charisma modifier to one damage roll of that spell. At the same time, you can spend 1 sorcery point to gain resistance to fire damage for 1 hour.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 102</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Elemental Affinity (Silver Draconic Bloodline)</name>
				<text>Starting at 6th level, when you cast a spell that deals cold damage, you can add your Charisma modifier to one damage roll of that spell. At the same time, you can spend 1 sorcery point to gain resistance to cold damage for 1 hour.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 102</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Elemental Affinity (White Draconic Bloodline)</name>
				<text>Starting at 6th level, when you cast a spell that deals cold damage, you can add your Charisma modifier to one damage roll of that spell. At the same time, you can spend 1 sorcery point to gain resistance to cold damage for 1 hour.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 102</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Hound of Ill Omen (Shadow Magic)</name>
				<text>At 6th level, you gain the ability to call forth a howling creature of darkness to harass your foes. As a bonus action, you can spend 3 sorcery points to magically summon a hound of ill omen to target one creature you can see within 120 feet of you. The hound uses the dire wolf&#8217;s statistics with the following changes:</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>&#8226; The hound is size Medium, not Large, and it counts as a monstosity, not a beast.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>&#8226; It appears with a number of temporary hit points equal to half your sorcerer level.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>&#8226; It can move through other creatures and objects as if they were difficult terrain. The hound takes 5 force damage if it ends its turn inside an object.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>&#8226; At the start of its turn, the hound automatically knows its target&#8217;s location. If the target was hidden, it is no longer hidden from the hound.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>	The hound appears in an unoccupied space of your choice within 30 feet of the target. Roll initiative for the hound. On its turn, it can move only toward its target by the most direct route, and it can use its action only to attack its target. The hound makes opportunity attacks, but only against its target. Additionally, while the hound is within 5 feet if the target, the target has disadvantage on saving throws against any spell you cast. The hound disappears if it is reduced to 0 hit points, if its target is reduced to 0 hit points, or after 5 minutes.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Xanathar's Guide to Everything, p. 51</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Heart of the Storm (Storm Sorcery)</name>
				<text>At 6th level, you gain resistance to lightning and thunder damage. In addition, whenever you start casting a spell of 1st level or higher that deals lightning or thunder damage, stormy magic erupts from you. This eruption causes creatures of your choice that you can see within 10 feet of you to take lightning or thunder damage (choose each time this ability activates) equal to half your sorcerer level.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Sword Coast Adventurer's Guide, p. 137</text>
				<text>		Xanathar's Guide to Everything p. 52</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Storm Guide (Storm Sorcery)</name>
				<text>At 6th level, you gain the ability to subtly control the weather around you.</text>
				<text>	If it is raining, you can use an action to cause the rain to stop falling in a 20-foot radius centered on you. You can end this effect as a bonus action.</text>
				<text>	If it is windy, you can use a bonus action each round to choose the direction that the wind blows in a 100-foot radius around you. The wind blows in that direction until the end of your next turn. You have no ability to alter the speed of the wind.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Sword Coast Adventurer's Guide, p. 137</text>
				<text>		Xanathar's Guide to Everything p. 52</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Bend Luck (Wild Magic)</name>
				<text>Starting at 6th level, you have the ability to twist fate using your wild magic. When another creature you can see makes an attack roll, an ability check, or a saving throw, you can use your reaction and spend 2 sorcery points to roll 1d4 and apply the number rolled as a bonus or penalty (your choice) to the creature&#8217;s roll. You can do so after the creature rolls but before any effects of the roll occur.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 103</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots>5, 4, 3, 3, 1</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots>5, 4, 3, 3, 2</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Ability Score Improvement (2nd)</name>
				<text>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can&#8217;t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
				<text>	If your DM uses the optional Feats, you can instead take a feat.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 102</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots>5, 4, 3, 3, 3, 1</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots>6, 4, 3, 3, 3, 2</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Metamagic Option (3rd)</name>
				<text>At 10th level, you learn an additional metamagic option.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 101</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Metamagic: Careful Spell</name>
				<text>When you cast a spell that forces other creatures to make a saving throw, you can protect some of those creatures from the spell&#8217;s full force. To do so, you spend 1 sorcery point and choose a number of those creatures up to your Charisma modifier (minimum of one creature). A chosen creature automatically succeeds on its saving throw against the spell. </text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 102</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Metamagic: Distant Spell</name>
				<text>When you cast a spell that has a range of 5 feet or greater, you can spend 1 sorcery point to double the range of the spell.</text>
				<text>	When you cast a spell that has a range of touch, you can spend 1 sorcery point to make the range of the spell 30 feet. </text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 102</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Metamagic: Empowered Spell</name>
				<text>When you roll damage for a spell, you can spend 1 sorcery point to reroll a number of the damage dice up to your Charisma modifier (minimum of one). You must use the new rolls.</text>
				<text>	You can use Empowered Spell even if you have already used a different Metamagic option during the casting of the spell. </text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 102</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Metamagic: Extended Spell</name>
				<text>When you cast a spell that has a duration of 1 minute or longer, you can spend 1 sorcery point to double its duration, to a maximum duration of 24 hours. </text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 102</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Metamagic: Heightened Spell</name>
				<text>When you cast a spell that forces a creature to make a saving throw to resist its effects, you can spend 3 sorcery points to give one target of the spell disadvantage on its first saving throw made against the spell. </text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 102</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Metamagic: Quickened Spell</name>
				<text>When you cast a spell that has a casting time of 1 action, you can spend 2 sorcery points to change the casting time to 1 bonus action for this casting. </text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 102</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Metamagic: Subtle Spell</name>
				<text>When you cast a spell, you can spend 1 sorcery point to cast it without any somatic or verbal components. </text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 102</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Metamagic: Twinned Spell</name>
				<text>When you cast a spell that targets only one creature and doesn&#8217;t have a range of self, you can spend a number of sorcery points equal to the spell&#8217;s level to target a second creature in range with the same spell (1 sorcery point if the spell is a cantrip).</text>
				<text>	To be eligible, a spell must be incapable of targeting more than one creature at the spell&#8217;s current level. For example, magic missile and scorching ray aren&#8217;t eligible, but ray of frost and chromatic orb are.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 102</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots>6, 4, 3, 3, 3, 2, 1</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots>6, 4, 3, 3, 3, 2, 1</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Ability Score Improvement (3rd)</name>
				<text>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can&#8217;t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
				<text>	If your DM uses the optional Feats, you can instead take a feat.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 102</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots>6, 4, 3, 3, 3, 2, 1, 1</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots>6, 4, 3, 3, 3, 2, 1, 1</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Otherworldly Wings (Divine Soul)</name>
				<text>Starting at 14th level, you can use a bonus action to manifest a pair of spectral wings from your back. While the wings are present, you have a flying speed of 30 feet. The wings last until you&#8217;re incapacitated, you die, or you dismiss them as a bonus action.</text>
				<text>	The affinity you chose for your Divine Magic feature determines the appearance of the spectral wings: eagle wings for good or law, bat wings for evil or chaos, and dragonfly wings for neutrality.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Xanathar's Guide to Everything, p. 50</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Dragon Wings (Draconic Bloodline)</name>
				<text>At 14th level, you gain the ability to sprout a pair of dragon wings from your back, gaining a flying speed equal to your current speed. You can create these wings as a bonus action on your turn. They last until you dismiss them as a bonus action on your turn.</text>
				<text>	You can&#8217;t manifest your wings while wearing armor unless the armor is made to accommodate them, and clothing not made to accommodate your wings might be destroyed when you manifest them.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 103</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Shadow Walk (Shadow Magic)</name>
				<text>At 14th level, you gain the ability to step from one shadow into another. When you are in dim light or darkness, as a bonus action, you can teleport up to 120 feet to an unoccupied space you can see that is also in dim light or darkness.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Xanathar's Guide to Everything, p. 51</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Storm's Fury (Storm Sorcery)</name>
				<text>Starting at 14th level, when you are hit by a melee attack, you can use your reaction to deal lightning damage to the attacker. The damage equals your sorcerer level. The attacker must also make a Strength saving throw against your sorcerer spell save DC. On a failed save, the attacker is pushed in a straight line up to 20 feet away from you.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Sword Coast Adventurer's Guide, p. 137</text>
				<text>		Xanathar's Guide to Everything p. 52</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Controlled Chaos (Wild Magic)</name>
				<text>At 14th level, you gain a modicum of control over the surges of your wild magic. Whenever you roll on the Wild Magic Surge table, you can roll twice and use either number.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 103</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots>6, 4, 3, 3, 3, 2, 1, 1, 1</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots>6, 4, 3, 3, 3, 2, 1, 1, 1</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Ability Score Improvement (4th)</name>
				<text>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can&#8217;t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
				<text>	If your DM uses the optional Feats, you can instead take a feat.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 102</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots>6, 4, 3, 3, 3, 2, 1, 1, 1, 1</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Metamagic Option (4th)</name>
				<text>At 17th level, you learn an additional metamagic option.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 101</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Metamagic: Careful Spell</name>
				<text>When you cast a spell that forces other creatures to make a saving throw, you can protect some of those creatures from the spell&#8217;s full force. To do so, you spend 1 sorcery point and choose a number of those creatures up to your Charisma modifier (minimum of one creature). A chosen creature automatically succeeds on its saving throw against the spell. </text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 102</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Metamagic: Distant Spell</name>
				<text>When you cast a spell that has a range of 5 feet or greater, you can spend 1 sorcery point to double the range of the spell.</text>
				<text>	When you cast a spell that has a range of touch, you can spend 1 sorcery point to make the range of the spell 30 feet. </text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 102</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Metamagic: Empowered Spell</name>
				<text>When you roll damage for a spell, you can spend 1 sorcery point to reroll a number of the damage dice up to your Charisma modifier (minimum of one). You must use the new rolls.</text>
				<text>	You can use Empowered Spell even if you have already used a different Metamagic option during the casting of the spell. </text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 102</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Metamagic: Extended Spell</name>
				<text>When you cast a spell that has a duration of 1 minute or longer, you can spend 1 sorcery point to double its duration, to a maximum duration of 24 hours. </text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 102</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Metamagic: Heightened Spell</name>
				<text>When you cast a spell that forces a creature to make a saving throw to resist its effects, you can spend 3 sorcery points to give one target of the spell disadvantage on its first saving throw made against the spell. </text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 102</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Metamagic: Quickened Spell</name>
				<text>When you cast a spell that has a casting time of 1 action, you can spend 2 sorcery points to change the casting time to 1 bonus action for this casting. </text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 102</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Metamagic: Subtle Spell</name>
				<text>When you cast a spell, you can spend 1 sorcery point to cast it without any somatic or verbal components. </text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 102</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Metamagic: Twinned Spell</name>
				<text>When you cast a spell that targets only one creature and doesn&#8217;t have a range of self, you can spend a number of sorcery points equal to the spell&#8217;s level to target a second creature in range with the same spell (1 sorcery point if the spell is a cantrip).</text>
				<text>	To be eligible, a spell must be incapable of targeting more than one creature at the spell&#8217;s current level. For example, magic missile and scorching ray aren&#8217;t eligible, but ray of frost and chromatic orb are.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 102</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots>6, 4, 3, 3, 3, 3, 1, 1, 1, 1</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Unearthly Recovery (Divine Soul)</name>
				<text>At 18th level, you gain the ability to overcome grievous injuries. As a bonus action when you have fewer than half of your hit points remaining, you can regain a number of hit points equal to half your hit point maximum.</text>
				<text>	Once you use this feature, you can&#8217;t use it again until you finish a long rest.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Xanathar's Guide to Everything, p. 50</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Draconic Presence (Draconic Bloodline)</name>
				<text>Beginning at 18th level, you can channel the dread presence of your dragon ancestor, causing those around you to become awestruck or frightened. As an action, you can spend 5 sorcery points to draw on this power and exude an aura of awe or fear (your choice) to a distance of 60 feet. For 1 minute or until you lose your concentration (as if you were casting a concentration spell), each hostile creature that starts its turn in this aura must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or be charmed (if you chose awe) or frightened (if you chose fear) until the aura ends. A creature that succeeds on this saving throw is immune to your aura for 24 hours.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Charmed:</text>
				<text>&#8226; A charmed creature can't attack the charmer or target the charmer with harmful abilities or magical effects.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>&#8226; The charmer has advantage on any ability check to interact socially with the creature.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Frightened:</text>
				<text>&#8226; A frightened creature has disadvantage on ability checks and attack rolls while the source of its fear is within line of sight.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>&#8226; The creature can't willingly move closer to the source of its fear.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 103</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Umbral Form (Shadow Magic)</name>
				<text>Starting at 18th level, you can spend 6 sorcery points as a bonus action to magically transform yourself into a shadowy form. In this form, you have resistance to all damage except force and radiant damage, and you can move through other creatures and objects as if they were difficult terrain. You take 5 force damage if you end your turn inside an object.</text>
				<text>	You remain in this form for 1 minute. It ends early if you are incapacitated, if you die, or if you dismiss it as a bonus action.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Xanathar's Guide to Everything, p. 51</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Wind Soul (Storm Sorcery)</name>
				<text>At 18th level, you gain immunity to lightning and thunder damage.</text>
				<text>	You also gain a magical flying speed of 60 feet. As an action, you can reduce your flying speed to 30 feet for one hour and choose a number of creatures within 30 feet of you equal to 3 + your Charisma modifier. The chosen creatures gain a flying speed of 30 feet for 1 hour. Once you reduce your flying speed in this way, you can&#8217;t do so again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Sword Coast Adventurer's Guide, p. 137</text>
				<text>		Xanathar's Guide to Everything p. 52</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Spell Bombardment (Wild Magic)</name>
				<text>Beginning at 18th level, the harmful energy of your spells intensifies. When you roll damage for a spell and roll the highest number possible on any of the dice, choose one of those dice, roll it again and add that roll to the damage. You can use the feature only once per turn.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 103</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots>6, 4, 3, 3, 3, 3, 2, 1, 1, 1</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Ability Score Improvement (5th)</name>
				<text>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can&#8217;t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
				<text>	If your DM uses the optional Feats, you can instead take a feat.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 102</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots>6, 4, 3, 3, 3, 3, 2, 2, 1, 1</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Sorcerous Restoration</name>
				<text>At 20th level, you regain 4 expended sorcery points whenever you finish a short rest.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 102</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

</subclass>

<subclass>
	<name>Warlock</name>
	<hd>8</hd>
	<proficiency>Wisdom, Charisma, Arcana, Deception, History, Intimidation, Investigation, Nature, Religion</proficiency>
	<spellAbility>Charisma</spellAbility>
	<numSkills>2</numSkills>
		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Starting Warlock</name>
				<text>As a 1st-level Warlock, you begin play with 8+your Constitution modifier hit points.</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>You are proficient with the following items, in addition to any proficiencies provided by your race or background.</text>
				<text>&#8226; Armor: light armor</text>
				<text>&#8226; Weapons: simple weapons</text>
				<text>&#8226; Tools: none</text>
				<text>&#8226; Skills: Choose two skills from Arcana, Deception, History, Intimidation, Investigation, Nature, and Religion</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>You begin play with the following equipment, in addition to any equipment provided by your background.</text>
				<text>&#8226; (a) a light crossbow and 20 bolts or (b) any simple weapon</text>
				<text>&#8226; (a) a component pouch or (b) an arcane focus</text>
				<text>&#8226; (a) a scholar's pack or (b) a dungeoneer's pack</text>
				<text>&#8226; Leather armor, any simple weapon, and two daggers </text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>Alternatively, you may start with 4d4x10 gp and choose your own equipment.</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 105</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Multiclass Warlock</name>
				<text>To multiclass as a Warlock, you must meet the following prerequisites:</text>
				<text>&#8226; Charisma 13</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>You gain the following proficiencies:</text>
				<text>&#8226; light armor, simple weapons</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 163</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>
<armor>light armor</armor><weapons>simple weapons</weapons><tools>none</tools><wealth>4d4x10</wealth>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots>2, 1</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Pact Magic</name>
				<text>Your arcane research and the magic bestowed on you by your patron have given you facility with spells. See chapter 10 for the general rules of spellcasting and chapter 11 for the warlock spell list. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Cantrips:</text>
				<text>	You know two cantrips of your choice from the warlock spell list. You learn an additional warlock cantrip of your choice at 4th level, and another at 10th level. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Spell Slots:</text>
				<text>	The Warlock table shows how many spell slots you have. The table also shows what the level of those slots is; all of your spell slots are the same level. To cast one of your warlock spells of 1st level or higher, you must expend a spell slot. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a short or long rest.</text>
				<text>	For example, when you are 5th level, you have two 3rd-level spell slots. To cast the 1st-level spell witch bolt you must spend one of those slots, and you cast it as a 3rd-level spell. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Spells Known of 1st Level and Higher:</text>
				<text>	At 1st level, you know two 1st-level spells of your choice from the warlock spell list.</text>
				<text>	You learn an additional warlock spell at 2nd through 9th level, and at every odd level thereafter. A spell you choose must be of a level no higher than what&#8217;s shown in the table&#8217;s Slot Level column for your level. When you reach 6th level, for example, you learn a new warlock spell, which can be 1st, 2nd, or 3rd level.</text>
				<text>	Additionally, when you gain a level in this class, you can choose one of the warlock spells you know and replace it with another spell from the warlock spell list, which also must be of a level for which you have spell slots. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Spellcasting Ability:</text>
				<text>	Charisma is your spellcasting ability for your warlock spells, so you use your Charisma whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Charisma modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a warlock spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.</text>
				<text>	Spell save DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier</text>
				<text>	Spell attack modifier = your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Spellcasting Focus:</text>
				<text>	You can use an arcane focus (found in chapter 5) as a spellcasting focus for your warlock spells.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 107</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Otherworldly Patron</name>
				<text>At 1st level, you have struck a bargain with an otherworldly being of your choice: the Archfey, the Fiend, or the Great Old One, each of which is detailed at the end of the class description. Your choice grants you features at 1st level and again at 6th, 10th, and 14th level.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 107</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Otherworldly Patron: The Archfey</name>
				<text>Your patron is a lord or lady of the fey, a creature of legend who holds secrets that were forgotten before the mortal races were born. This being&#8217;s motivations are often inscrutable, and sometimes whimsical, and might involve a striving for greater magical power or the settling of age-old grudges. Beings of this sort include the Prince of Frost; the Queen of Air and Darkness, ruler of the Gloaming Court; Titania of the Summer Court; her consort Oberon, the Green Lord; Hyrsam, the Prince of Fools; and ancient hags. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Expanded Spell List:</text>
				<text>	The Archfey lets you choose from an expanded list of spells when you learn a warlock spell. The following spells are added to the warlock spell list for you.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>1st &#8212; faerie fire, sleep</text>
				<text>2nd &#8212; calm emotions, phantasmal force</text>
				<text>3rd &#8212; blink, plant growth</text>
				<text>4th &#8212; dominate beast, greater invisibility</text>
				<text>5th &#8212; dominate person, seeming</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 108</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Fey Presence (The Archfey)</name>
				<text>Starting at 1st level, your patron bestows upon you the ability to project the beguiling and fearsome presence of the fey. As an action, you can cause each creature in a 10-foot cube originating from you to make a Wisdom saving throw against your warlock spell save DC. The creatures that fail their saving throws are all charmed or frightened by you (your choice) until the end of your next turn.</text>
				<text>	Once you use this feature, you can&#8217;t use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Charmed:</text>
				<text>&#8226; A charmed creature can't attack the charmer or target the charmer with harmful abilities or magical effects.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>&#8226; The charmer has advantage on any ability check to interact socially with the creature.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Frightened:</text>
				<text>&#8226; A frightened creature has disadvantage on ability checks and attack rolls while the source of its fear is within line of sight.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>&#8226; The creature can't willingly move closer to the source of its fear.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 109</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Otherworldly Patron: The Celestial</name>
				<text>Your patron is a powerful being of the Upper Planes. You have bound yourself to an ancient empyrean, solar, ki-rin, or unicorn or to another entity that resides in the planes of everlasting bliss. Your pact with that being allows you to experience the barest touch of the holy light that illuminates the multiverse.</text>
				<text>	Being connected to such power can cause changes in your behavior and beliefs. You might find yourself driven to annihilate the undead, to defeat fiends, and to protect the innocent. At times, your heart might also be filled with a longing for the celestial realm of your patron, and a desire to wander that paradise for the rest of your days. But you know that your mission is among mortals for now and that your pact binds you to bring light to the dark places of the world.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Expanded Spell List: </text>
				<text>	The Celestial lets you choose from an expanded list of spells when you learn a warlock spell. The following spells are added to the warlock spell list for you.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>1st &#8212; cure wounds, guiding bolt</text>
				<text>2nd &#8212; flaming sphere, lesser restoration</text>
				<text>3rd &#8212; daylight, revivify</text>
				<text>4th &#8212; guardian of faith, wall of fire</text>
				<text>5th &#8212; flame strike, greater restoration.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Xanathar's Guide to Everything, p. 54</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Bonus Cantrips (The Celestial)</name>
				<text>At 1st level, you learn the sacred flame and light cantrips. They count as warlock cantrips for you, but they don&#8217;t count against your number of cantrips known.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Xanathar's Guide to Everything, p. 54</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Healing Light (The Celestial)</name>
				<text>At 1st level, you gain the ability to channel celestial energy to heal wounds. You have a pool of d6s that you spend to fuel this healing. The number of dice in the pool equals 1 + your warlock level.</text>
				<text>	As a bonus action, you can heal one  creature you can see within 60 feet of you, spending dice from the pool. The maximum number of dice you can spend at once equals your Charisma modifier (minimum of one die). Roll the dice you spend, add them together, and restore a number of hit points equal to the total.</text>
				<text>	Your pool regains all expended dice when you finish a long rest.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Xanathar's Guide to Everything, p. 54</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Otherworldly Patron: The Fiend</name>
				<text>You have made a pact with a fiend from the lower planes of existence, a being whose aims are evil, even if you strive against those aims. Such beings desire the corruption or destruction of all things, ultimately including you. Fiends powerful enough to forge a pact include demon lords such as Demogorgon, Orcus, Fraz&#8217;Urb-luu, and Baphomet; archdevils such as Asmodeus, Dispater, Mephistopheles, and Belial; pit fiends and balors that are especially mighty; and ultroloths and other lords of the yugoloths. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Expanded Spell List:</text>
				<text>	The Fiend lets you choose from an expanded list of spells when you learn a warlock spell. The following spells are added to the warlock spell list for you.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>1st &#8212; burning hands, command</text>
				<text>2nd &#8212; blindness/deafness, scorching ray</text>
				<text>3rd &#8212; fireball, stinking cloud</text>
				<text>4th &#8212; fire shield, wall of fire</text>
				<text>5th &#8212; flame strike, hallow</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 109</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Dark One's Blessing (The Fiend)</name>
				<text>Starting at 1st level, when you reduce a hostile creature to 0 hit points, you gain temporary hit points equal to your Charisma modifier + your warlock level (minimum of 1).</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 109</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Otherworldly Patron: The Great Old One</name>
				<text>Your patron is a mysterious entity whose nature is utterly foreign to the fabric of reality. It might come from the Far Realm, the space beyond reality, or it could be one of the elder gods known only in legends. Its motives are incomprehensible to mortals, and its knowledge so immense and ancient that even the greatest libraries pale in comparison to the vast secrets it holds. The Great Old One might be unaware of your existence or entirely indifferent to you, but the secrets you have learned allow you to draw your magic from it. Entities of this type include Ghaunadar, called That Which Lurks; Tharizdun, the Chained God; Dendar, the Night Serpent; Zargon, the Returner; Great Cthulhu; and other unfathomable beings.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Expanded Spell List:</text>
				<text>	The Great Old One lets you choose from an expanded list of spells when you learn a warlock spell. The following spells are added to the warlock spell list for you.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>1st &#8212; dissonant whispers, Tasha&#8217;s hideous laughter</text>
				<text>2nd &#8212; detect thoughts, phantasmal force</text>
				<text>3rd &#8212; clairvoyance, sending</text>
				<text>4th &#8212; dominate beast, Evard&#8217;s black tentacles</text>
				<text>5th &#8212; dominate person, telekinesis</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 109</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Awakened Mind (The Great Old One)</name>
				<text>Starting at 1st level, your alien knowledge gives you the ability to touch the minds of other creatures. You can communicate telepathically with any creature you can see within 30 feet of you. You don&#8217;t need to share a language with the creature for it to understand your telepathic utterances, but the creature must be able to understand at least one language.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 110</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Otherworldly Patron: The Hexblade</name>
				<text>You have made your pact with a mysterious entity from the Shadowfell&#8212;a force that manifests in sentient magic weapons carved from the stuff of shadow. The mighty sword Blackrazor is the most notable of these weapons, several of which have spread across the multiverse over the ages. The shadowy force behind these weapons can offer power to warlocks who form pacts with it. Many hexblade warlocks create weapons that emulate those formed in the Shadowfell. Others forgo such arms, content to weave the dark magic of that plane into their spellcasting.</text>
				<text>	Because the Raven Queen is known to have forged the first of these weapons, many sages speculate that she and the force are one and that the weapons, along with hexblade warlocks, are tools she uses to manipulate events on the Material Plane to her inscrutable ends.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Expanded Spell List:</text>
				<text>	The Hexblade lets you choose from an expanded list of spells when you learn a warlock spell. The following spells are added to the warlock spell list for you.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>1st &#8212; shield, wrathful smite</text>
				<text>2nd &#8212; blur, branding smite</text>
				<text>3rd &#8212; blink, elemental weapon</text>
				<text>4th &#8212; phantasmal killer, staggering smite</text>
				<text>5th &#8212; Banishing smite, cone of cold</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Xanathar's Guide to Everything, p. 55</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Hexblade&#8217;s Curse (Hexblade)</name>
				<text>Starting at 1st level, you gain the ability to place a baleful curse on someone. As a bonus action, choose one creature you can see within 30 feet of you. The target is cursed for 1 minute. The curse ends early if the target dies, you die, or you are incapacitated. Until the curse ends, you gain the following benefits:</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>&#8226; You gain a bonus to damage rolls against the cursed target. The bonus equals your proficiency bonus.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>&#8226; Any attack roll you make against the cursed target is a critical hit on a roll of 19 or 20 on the d20.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>&#8226; If the cursed target dies, you regain hit points equal to your warlock level + your Charisma modifier.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>	You can&#8217;t use this feature again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Xanathar's Guide to Everything, p. 55</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Hex Warrior (Hexblade)</name>
				<text>At 1st level, you acquire the training necessary to effectively arm yourself for battle. You gain proficiency with medium armor, shields, and martial weapons.</text>
				<text>	The influence of your patron also allows you to mystically channel your will through a particular weapon. Whenever you finish a long rest, you can touch one weapon that you are proficient with and that lacks the two-handed property. When you attack with that weapon, you can use your Charisma modifier, instead of Strength or Dexterity, for the attack and damage rolls. This benefit lasts until you finish a long rest. If you later gain the Pact of the Blade feature, this benefit extends to every pact weapon you conjure with that feature, no matter the weapon&#8217;s type.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Xanathar's Guide to Everything, p. 55</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Otherworldly Patron: The Undying</name>
				<text>Death holds no sway over your patron, who has unlocked the secrets of everlasting life, although such a prize&#8212;like all power&#8212;comes at a price. Once mortal, the Undying has seen mortal lifetimes pass like the seasons, like the flicker of endless days and nights. It has the secrets of the ages to share, secrets of life and death. Beings of this sort include Vecna, Lord of the Hand and the Eye; the dread Iuz; the lich-queen Vol; the Undying Court of Aerenal; Vlaakith, lich-queen of the githyanki; and the deathless wizard Fistandantalus.</text>
				<text>	In the Realms, Undying patrons include Larloch the Shadow King, legendary master of Warlock&#8217;s Crypt, and Gilgeam, the God-King of Unther.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Expanded Spell List:</text>
				<text>	The Undying lets you choose from an expanded list of spells when you learn a warlock spell. The following spells are added to the warlock spell list for you.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>1st &#8212; false life, ray of sickness</text>
				<text>2nd &#8212; blindness/deafness, silence</text>
				<text>3rd &#8212; feign death, speak with dead</text>
				<text>4th &#8212; aura of life, death ward</text>
				<text>5th &#8212; contagion, legend lore</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Sword Coast Adventurer's Guide, p. 139</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Among the Dead (The Undying)</name>
				<text>Starting at 1st level, you learn the spare the dying cantrip, which counts as a warlock cantrip for you. You also have advantage on saving throws against any disease.</text>
				<text>	Additionally, undead have difficulty harming you. If an undead targets you directly with an attack or a harmful spell, that creature must make a Wisdom saving throw against your spell save DC (an undead needn&#8217;t make the save when it includes you in an area effect, such as the explosion of fireball). On a failed save, the creature must choose a new target or forfeit targeting someone instead of you, potentially wasting the attack or spell. On a succesful save, the creature is immune to this effect for 24 hours. An undead is also immune to this effect for 24 hours if you target it with an attack or a harmful spell.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Sword Coast Adventurer's Guide, p. 139</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots>2, 2</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Eldritch Invocations</name>
				<text>In your study of occult lore, you have unearthed eldritch invocations, fragments of forbidden knowledge that imbue you with an abiding magical ability.</text>
				<text>	At 2nd level, you gain two eldritch invocations of your choice. Your invocation options are detailed at the end of the class description. When you gain certain warlock levels, you gain additional invocations of your choice. You gain an additional invocation at 5th, 7th, 9th, 12th, 15th, and 18th warlock level.</text>
				<text>	Additionally, when you gain a level in this class, you can choose one of the invocations you know and replace it with another invocation that you could learn at that level.</text>
				<text>	To select or change your invocations, add them as spells from the "Eldritch Invocations" spell list.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 107</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots>2, 0, 2</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Pact Boon</name>
				<text>At 3rd level, your otherworldly patron bestows a gift upon you for your loyal service. You gain one of the following features of your choice: Pact of the Chain, Pact of the Blade, or Pact of the tome.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 107</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Pact Boon: Pact of the Blade</name>
				<text>You can use your action to create a pact weapon in your empty hand. You can choose the form that this melee weapon takes each time you create it (see chapter 5 for weapon options). You are proficient with it while you wield it. This weapon counts as magical for the purpose of overcoming resistance and immunity to nonmagical attacks and damage.</text>
				<text>	Your pact weapon disappears if it is more than 5 feet away from you for 1 minute or more. It also disappears if you use this feature again, if you dismiss the weapon (no action required), or if you die.</text>
				<text>	You can transform one magic weapon into your pact weapon by performing a special ritual while you hold the weapon. You perform the ritual over the course of 1 hour, which can be done during a short rest. You can then dismiss the weapon, shunting it into an extradimensional space, and it appears whenever you create your pact weapon thereafter. You can&#8217;t affect an artifact or a sentient weapon in this way. The weapon ceases being your pact weapon if you die, if you perform the 1-hour ritual on a different weapon, or if you use a 1-hour ritual to break your bond to it. The weapon appears at your feet if it is in the extradimensional space when the bond breaks. </text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 107</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Pact Boon: Pact of the Chain</name>
				<text>You learn the find familiar spell and can cast it as a ritual. The spell doesn&#8217;t count against your number of spells known.</text>
				<text>	When you cast the spell, you can choose one of the normal forms for your familiar or one of the following special forms: imp, pseudodragon, quasit, or sprite.</text>
				<text>	Additionally, when you take the Attack action, you can forgo one of your own attacks to allow your familiar to make one attack of its own with its reaction.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 107</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Pact Boon: Pact of the Tome</name>
				<text>Your patron gives you a grimoire called a Book of Shadows. When you gain this feature, choose three cantrips from any class&#8217;s spell list (the three needn&#8217;t be from the same list). While the book is on your person, you can cast those cantrips at will. They don&#8217;t count against your number of cantrips known. If they don&#8217;t appear on the warlock spell list, they are nonetheless warlock spells for you.</text>
				<text>	If you lose your Book of Shadows, you can perform a 1-hour ceremony to receive a replacement from your patron. This ceremony can be performed during a short or long rest, and it destroys the previous book. The book turns to ash when you die.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 108</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots>3, 0, 2</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can&#8217;t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
				<text>	If your DM uses the optional Feats, you can instead take a feat.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 108</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots>3, 0, 0, 2</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Additional Invocation</name>
				<text>At 5th level, you learn an additional Eldritch Invocation.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 107</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots>3, 0, 0, 2</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Misty Escape (The Archfey)</name>
				<text>Starting at 6th level, you can vanish in a puff of mist in response to harm. When you take damage, you can use your reaction to turn invisible and teleport up to 60 feet to an unoccupied space you can see. You remain invisible until the start of your next turn or until you attack or cast a spell.</text>
				<text>	Once you use this feature, you can&#8217;t use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Invisible:</text>
				<text>&#8226; An invisible creature is impossible to see without the aid of magic or a special sense. For the purpose of hiding, the creature is heavily obscured. The creature's location can be detected by any noise it makes or any tracks it leaves.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>&#8226; Attack rolls against the creature have disadvantage, and the creature's attack rolls have advantage.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 109</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Radiant Soul (The Celestial)</name>
				<text>Starting at 6th level, your link to the Celestial allows you to serve as a conduit for radiant energy. You have resistance to radiant damage, and when you cast a spell that deals radiant or fire damage, you can add your Charisma modifier to one radiant or fire damage roll of that spell against one of its targets.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Xanathar's Guide to Everything, p. 55</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Dark One's Own Luck (The Fiend)</name>
				<text>Starting at 6th level, you can call on your patron to alter fate in your favor. When you make an ability check or a saving throw, you can use this feature to add a d10 to your roll. You can do so after seeing the initial roll but before any of the roll&#8217;s effects occur.</text>
				<text>	Once you use this feature, you can&#8217;t use it again until you finish a short or long rest</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 109</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Entropic Ward (The Great Old One)</name>
				<text>At 6th level, you learn to magically ward yourself against attack and to turn an enemy&#8217;s failed strike into good luck for yourself. When a creature makes an attack roll against you, you can use your reaction to impose disadvantage on that roll. If the attack misses you, your next attack roll against the creature has advantage if you make it before the end of your next turn.</text>
				<text>	Once you use this feature, you can&#8217;t use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 110</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Accursed Specter (Hexblade)</name>
				<text>Starting at 6th level, you can curse the soul of a person you slay, temporarily binding it to your service. When you slay a humanoid, you can cause its spirit to rise from its corpse as a specter, the statistics for which are in the Monster Manual. When the specter appears, it gains temporary hit points equal to half your warlock level. Roll initiative for the specter, which has its own turns. It obeys your verbal commands, and it gains a special bonus to attack equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum of +0).</text>
				<text>	The specter remains in your service until the end of your next long rest, at which point it vanishes to the afterlife.</text>
				<text>	Once you bind a specter with this feature, you can&#8217;t use the feature again until you finish a long rest.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Xanathar's Guide to Everything, p. 56</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Defy Death (The Undying)</name>
				<text>Starting at 6th level, you can give yourself vitality when you cheat death or when you help someone else cheat it. You can regain hit points equal to 1d8 + your Constitution modifier (minimum of 1 hit point) when you succeed on a death saving throw or when you satbilize a creature with spare the dying.</text>
				<text>	Once you use this feature, you can&#8217;t use it again until you finish a long rest.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Sword Coast Adventurer's Guide, p. 140</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots>3, 0, 0, 0, 2</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Additional Invocation</name>
				<text>At 7th level, you learn an additional Eldritch Invocation.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 107</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots>3, 0, 0, 0, 2</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Ability Score Improvement (2nd)</name>
				<text>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can&#8217;t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
				<text>	If your DM uses the optional Feats, you can instead take a feat.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 108</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots>3, 0, 0, 0, 0, 2</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Additional Invocation</name>
				<text>At 9th level, you learn an additional Eldritch Invocation.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 107</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots>4, 0, 0, 0, 0, 2</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Beguiling Defenses (The Archfey)</name>
				<text>Beginning at 10th level, your patron teaches you how to turn the mind-affecting magic of your enemies against them. You are immune to being charmed, and when another creature attempts to charm you, you can use your reaction to attempt to turn the charm back on that creature. The creature must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw against your warlock spell save DC or be charmed by you for 1 minute or until the creature takes any damage.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Charmed:</text>
				<text>&#8226; A charmed creature can't attack the charmer or target the charmer with harmful abilities or magical effects.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>&#8226; The charmer has advantage on any ability check to interact socially with the creature.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 109</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Celestial Resilience (The Celestial)</name>
				<text>Starting at 10th level, you gain temporary hit points whenever you finish a short or long rest. These temporary hit points equal your warlock level + your Charisma modifier. Additionally, choose up to five creatures you can see at the end of the rest. Those creatures each gain temporary hit points equal to half your warlock level + your Charisma modifier.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Xanathar's Guide to Everything, p. 55</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Fiendish Resilience (The Fiend)</name>
				<text>Starting at 10th level, you can choose one damage type when you finish a short or long rest. You gain resistance to that damage type until you choose a different one with this feature. Damage from magical weapons or silver weapons ignores this resistance.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 109</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Thought Shield (The Great Old One)</name>
				<text>Starting at 10th level, your thoughts can&#8217;t be read by telepathy or other means unless you allow it. You also have resistance to psychic damage, and whenever a creature deals psychic damage to you, that creature takes the same amount of damage that you do.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 110</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Armor of Hexes (Hexblade)</name>
				<text>At 10th level, your hex grows more powerful. If the target cursed by your Hexblade&#8217;s Curse hits you with an attack roll, you can use your reaction to roll a d6. On a 4 or higher, the attack instead misses you, regardless of its roll.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Xanathar's Guide to Everything, p. 56</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Undying Nature (The Undying)</name>
				<text>Beginning at 10th level, you can hold your breath indefinitely, and you don&#8217;t require food, water, or sleep, although you still require rest to reduce exhaustion and still benefit from finishing short and long rests.</text>
				<text>	In addition, you age at a slower rate. For every 10 years that pass, your body ages only 1 year, and you are immune to being magically aged.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Sword Coast Adventurer's Guide, p. 140</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots>4, 0, 0, 0, 0, 3</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Mystic Arcanum</name>
				<text>At 11th level, your patron bestows upon you a magical secret called an arcanum. Choose one 6th-level spell from the warlock spell list as this arcanum.</text>
				<text>	You can cast your arcanum spell once without expending a spell slot. You must finish a long rest before you can do so again.</text>
				<text>	At higher levels, you gain more warlock spells of your choice that can be cast in this way: one 7th-level spell at 13th level, one 8th-level spell at 15th level, and one 9th-level spell at 17th level. You regain all uses of your Mystic Arcanum when you finish a long rest.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 108</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots>4, 0, 0, 0, 0, 3</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Ability Score Improvement (3rd)</name>
				<text>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can&#8217;t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
				<text>	If your DM uses the optional Feats, you can instead take a feat.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 108</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Additional Invocation</name>
				<text>At 12th level, you learn an additional Eldritch Invocation.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 107</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots>4, 0, 0, 0, 0, 3</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots>4, 0, 0, 0, 0, 3</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Dark Delirium (The Archfey)</name>
				<text>Starting at 14th level, you can plunge a creature into an illusory realm. As an action, choose a creature that you can see within 60 feet of you. It must make a Wisdom saving throw against your warlock spell save DC. On a failed save, it is charmed or frightened by you (your choice) for 1 minute or until your concentration is broken (as if you are concentrating on a spell). This effect ends early if the creature takes any damage.</text>
				<text>	Until this illusion ends, the creature thinks it is lost in a misty realm, the appearance of which you choose. The creature can see and hear only itself, you, and the illusion.</text>
				<text>	You must finish a short or long rest before you can use this feature again.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Charmed:</text>
				<text>&#8226; A charmed creature can't attack the charmer or target the charmer with harmful abilities or magical effects.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>&#8226; The charmer has advantage on any ability check to interact socially with the creature.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Frightened:</text>
				<text>&#8226; A frightened creature has disadvantage on ability checks and attack rolls while the source of its fear is within line of sight.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>&#8226; The creature can't willingly move closer to the source of its fear.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 109</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Searing Vengeance (The Celestial)</name>
				<text>Starting at 14th level, the radiant energy you channel allows you to resist death. When you have to make a death saving throw at the start of your turn, you can instead spring back to your feet with a burst of radiant energy. You regain hit points equal to half your hit point maximum, and then you stand up, if you so choose. Each creature of your choice that is within 30 feet of you takes radiant damage equal to 2d8 + your Charisma modifier, and it is blinded until the end of the current turn.</text>
				<text>	Once you use this feature, you can&#8217;t use it again until you finish a long rest.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Xanathar's Guide to Everything, p. 55</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Hurl Through Hell (The Fiend)</name>
				<text>Starting at 14th level, when you hit a creature with an attack, you can use this feature to instantly transport the target through the lower planes. The creature disappears and hurtles through a nightmare landscape.</text>
				<text>	At the end of your next turn, the target returns to the space it previously occupied, or the nearest unoccupied space. If the target is not a fiend, it takes 10d10 psychic damage as it reels from its horrific experience.</text>
				<text>	Once you use this feature, you can&#8217;t use it again until you finish a long rest.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 109</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Create Thrall (The Great Old One)</name>
				<text>At 14th level, you gain the ability to infect a humanoid&#8217;s mind with the alien magic of your patron. You can use your action to touch an incapacitated humanoid. That creature is then charmed by you until a remove curse spell is cast on it, the charmed condition is removed from it, or you use this feature again.</text>
				<text>	You can communicate telepathically with the charmed creature as long as the two of you are on the same plane of existence.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Charmed:</text>
				<text>&#8226; A charmed creature can't attack the charmer or target the charmer with harmful abilities or magical effects.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>&#8226; The charmer has advantage on any ability check to interact socially with the creature.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 110</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Master of Hexes (Hexblade)</name>
				<text>Starting at 14th level, you can spread your Hexblade&#8217;s Curse from a slain creature to another creature. When the creature cursed by your Hexblade&#8217;s Curse dies, you can apply the curse to a different creature you can see within 30 feet of you, provided you aren&#8217;t incapacitated. When you apply the curse in this way, you don&#8217;t regain hit points from the death of the previously cursed creature</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Xanathar's Guide to Everything, p. 56</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Indestructible Life (The Undying)</name>
				<text>When you reach 14th level, you partake some of the true secrets of the Undying. On your turn, you can use a bonus action to regain hit points equal to 1d8 + your warlock level. Additionally, if you put a severed body part of yours back in place when you use this feature, the part reattaches.</text>
				<text>	Once you use this feature, you can&#8217;t use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Sword Coast Adventurer's Guide, p. 140</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots>4, 0, 0, 0, 0, 3</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Additional Invocation</name>
				<text>At 15th level, you learn an additional Eldritch Invocation.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 107</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots>4, 0, 0, 0, 0, 3</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Ability Score Improvement (4th)</name>
				<text>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can&#8217;t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
				<text>	If your DM uses the optional Feats, you can instead take a feat.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 108</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots>4, 0, 0, 0, 0, 4</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots>4, 0, 0, 0, 0, 4</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Additional Invocation</name>
				<text>At 18th level, you learn an additional Eldritch Invocation.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 107</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots>4, 0, 0, 0, 0, 4</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Ability Score Improvement (5th)</name>
				<text>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can&#8217;t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
				<text>	If your DM uses the optional Feats, you can instead take a feat.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 108</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots>4, 0, 0, 0, 0, 4</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Eldritch Master</name>
				<text>At 20th level, you can draw on your inner reserve of mystical power while entreating your patron to regain expended spell slots. You can spend 1 minute entreating your patron for aid to regain all your expended spell slots from your Pact Magic feature. Once you regain spell slots with this feature, you must finish a long rest before you can do so again.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 108</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

</subclass>

<subclass>
	<name>Wizard</name>
	<hd>6</hd>
	<proficiency>Intelligence, Wisdom, Arcana, History, Insight, Investigation, Medicine, Religion</proficiency>
	<spellAbility>Intelligence</spellAbility>
	<numSkills>2</numSkills>
		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Starting Wizard</name>
				<text>As a 1st-level Wizard, you begin play with 6+your Constitution modifier hit points.</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>You are proficient with the following items, in addition to any proficiencies provided by your race or background.</text>
				<text>&#8226; Armor: none</text>
				<text>&#8226; Weapons: daggers, darts, slings, quarterstaffs, light crossbows</text>
				<text>&#8226; Tools: none</text>
				<text>&#8226; Skills: Choose two from Arcana, History, Insight, Investigation, Medicine, and Religion</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>You begin play with the following equipment, in addition to any equipment provided by your background.</text>
				<text>&#8226; (a) a quarterstaff or (b) a dagger</text>
				<text>&#8226; (a) a component pouch or (b) an arcane focus</text>
				<text>&#8226; (a) a scholar's pack or (b) an explorer's pack</text>
				<text>&#8226; A spellbook</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>Alternatively, you may start with 4d4x10 gp and choose your own equipment.</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 112</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Multiclass Wizard</name>
				<text>To multiclass as a Wizard, you must meet the following prerequisites:</text>
				<text>&#8226; Intelligence 13</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>You gain the following proficiencies:</text>
				<text>&#8226; none</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 163</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>
<armor>none</armor><weapons>daggers, darts, slings, quarterstaffs, light crossbows</weapons><tools>none</tools><wealth>4d4x10</wealth>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots>3, 2</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Spellcasting</name>
				<text>As a student of arcane magic, you have a spellbook containing spells that show the first glimmerings of your true power. See chapter 10 for the general rules of spellcasting and chapter 11 for the wizard spell list. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Cantrips:</text>
				<text>	At 1st level, you know three cantrips of your choice from the wizard spell list. You learn an additional wizard cantrip of your choice at 4th level, and another at 10th level.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Spellbook:</text>
				<text>	At 1st level, you have a spellbook containing six 1st-level wizard spells of your choice. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Preparing and Casting Spells:</text>
				<text>	The Wizard table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your spells of 1st level and higher. To cast one of these spells, you must expend a slot of the spell&#8217;s level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.</text>
				<text>	You prepare the list of wizard spells that are available for you to cast. To do so. choose a number of wizard spells from your spellbook equal to your Intelligence modifier + your wizard level (minimum of one spell). The spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots.</text>
				<text>	For example, if you&#8217;re a 3rd-level wizard, you have four 1st-level and two 2nd-level spell slots. With an Intelligence of 16, your list of prepared spells can include six spells of 1st or 2nd level, in any combination, chosen from your spellbook. If you prepare the 1st-level spell magic missile, you can cast it using a 1st-level or a 2nd-level slot. Casting the spell doesn&#8217;t remove it from your list of prepared spells.</text>
				<text>	You can change your list of prepared spells when you finish a long rest. Preparing a new list of wizard spells requires time spent studying your spellbook and memorizing the incantations and gestures you must make to cast the spell: at least 1 minute per spell level for each spell on your list. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Spellcasting Ability:</text>
				<text>	Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for your wizard spells, since you learn your spells through dedicated study and memorization. You use your Intelligence whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Intelligence modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a wizard spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.</text>
				<text>	Spell save DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier</text>
				<text>	Spell attack modifier = your proficiency bonus + your intelligence modifier </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Ritual Casting:</text>
				<text>	You can cast a wizard spell as a ritual if that spell has the ritual tag and you have the spell in your spellbook. You don&#8217;t need to have the spell prepared. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Spellcasting Focus:</text>
				<text>	You can use an arcane focus (found in chapter 5) as a spellcasting focus for your wizard spells. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Learning Spells of 1st Level and Higher:</text>
				<text>	Each time you gain a wizard level, you can add two wizard spells of your choice to your spellbook. Each of these spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots, as shown on the Wizard table. On your adventures, you might find other spells that you can add to your spellbook.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 114</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Spellbook</name>
				<text>The spells of 1st level and higher that you add to your spellbook as you gain levels reflect the arcane research you conduct on your own, as well as intellectual breakthroughs you have had about the nature of the multiverse. You might find other spells during your adventures. You could discover a spell recorded on a scroll in an evil wizard&#8217;s chest, for example, or in a dusty tome in an ancient library.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Copying a Spell into the Book:</text>
				<text>	When you find a wizard spell of 1st level or higher, you can add it to your spellbook if it is of a spell level you can prepare and if you can spare the time to decipher and copy it.</text>
				<text>	Copying that spell into your spellbook involves reproducing the basic form of the spell, then deciphering the unique system of notation used by the wizard who wrote it. You must practice the spell until you understand the sounds or gestures required, then transcribe it into your spellbook using your own notation.</text>
				<text>	For each level of the spell, the process takes 2 hours and costs 50 gp. The cost represents material components you expend as you experiment with the spell to master it, as well as the fine inks you need to record it. Once you have spent this time and money, you can prepare the spell just like your other spells.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Replacing the Book:</text>
				<text>	You can copy a spell from your own spellbook into another book &#8212; for example, if you want to make a backup copy of your spellbook. This is just like copying a new spell into your spellbook, but faster and easier, since you understand your own notation and already know how to cast the spell. You need spend only 1 hour and 10 gp for each level of the copied spell.</text>
				<text>	If you lose your spellbook, you can use the same procedure to transcribe the spells that you have prepared into a new spellbook. Filling out the remainder of your spellbook requires you to find new spells to do so, as normal. For this reason, many wizards keep backup spellbooks in a safe place.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>The Book&#8217;s Appearance:</text>
				<text>	Your spellbook is a unique compilation of spells, with its own decorative flourishes and margin notes. It might be a plain, functional leather volume that you received as a gift from your master, a finely bound gilt-edged tome you found in an ancient library, or even a loose collection of notes scrounged together after you lost your previous spellbook in a mishap.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 114</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Arcane Recovery</name>
				<text>You have learned to regain some of your magical energy by studying your spellbook. Once per day when you finish a short rest, you can choose expended spell slots to recover. The spell slots can have a combined level that is equal to or less than half your wizard level (rounded up), and none of the slots can be 6th level or higher.</text>
				<text>	For example, if you&#8217;re a 4th-level wizard, you can recover up to two levels worth of spell slots. You can recover either a 2nd-level spell slot or two 1st-level spell slots.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 115</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots>3, 3</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Arcane Tradition</name>
				<text>When you reach 2nd level, you choose an arcane tradition, shaping your practice of magic through one of eight schools: Abjuration, Conjuration, Divination, Enchantment, Evocation, Illusion, Necromancy, or Transmutation, all detailed at the end of the class description.</text>
				<text>	Your choice grants you features at 2nd level and again at 6th, 10th, and 14th level.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 115</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Arcane Tradition: Bladesinging</name>
				<text>Bladesingers are elves who bravely defend their people and lands. They are elf wizards who master a school of sword fighting grounded in a tradition of arcane magic. In combat, a bladesinger uses a series of intricate, elegant maneuvers that fend off harm and allow the bladesinger to channel magic into devastating attacks and a cunning defense.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Sword Coast Adventurer's Guide, p. 141</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Restriction: Elves Only (Bladesinging)</name>
				<text>Only elves and half-elves can choose the bladesinger arcane tradition. In the world of Faer&#251;n, elves closely guard the secrets of bladesinging.</text>
				<text>	Your DM can lift this restriction to better suit the campaign. The restriction reflects the story of bladesingers in the Forgotten Realms, but it might not apply to your DM&#8217;s setting or your DM&#8217;s version of the Realms.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Sword Coast Adventurer's Guide, p. 121</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Training in War and Song (Bladesinging)</name>
				<text>When you adopt this tradition at 2nd level, you gain proficiency with light armor, and you gain proficiency with one type of one-handed melee weapon of your choice.</text>
				<text>	You also gain proficiency in the Performance skill if you don&#8217;t already have it.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Sword Coast Adventurer's Guide, p. 142</text>
				<proficiency>Performance</proficiency>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Bladesong (Bladesinging)</name>
				<text>Starting at 2nd level, you can invoke a secret elven magic called the Bladesong, provided you aren&#8217;t wearing medium or heavy armor or using a shield. It graces you with supernatural speed, agility, and focus.</text>
				<text>	You can use a bonus action to start the Bladesong, which lasts for 1 minute. It ends early if you are incapacitated, if you don medium or heavy armor or a shield, or if you use two hands to make an attack with a weapon. You can also dismiss Bladesong at any time you choose (no action required).</text>
				<text>	While your bladesong is active, you gain the following benefits:</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>&#8226; You gain a bonus to your AC equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum of +1).</text>
				<text>&#8226; Your walking speed increases by 10 feet.</text>
				<text>&#8226; You have advantage on Dexterity (Acrobatics) checks.</text>
				<text>&#8226; You gain a bonus to any Constitution saving throws you make to maintain concentration on a spell. The bonus equals your Intelligence modifier (minimum of +1).</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>	You can use this feature twice. You regain all expended uses of it when you finish a short or long rest.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Sword Coast Adventurer's Guide, p. 142</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Arcane Tradition: School of Abjuration</name>
				<text>When you reach 2nd level, you choose an arcane tradition, shaping your practice of magic through one of eight schools: Abjuration, Conjuration, Divination, Enchantment, Evocation, Illusion, Necromancy, or Transmutation, all detailed at the end of the class description.</text>
				<text>	Your choice grants you features at 2nd level and again at 6th, 10th, and 14th level.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 115</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Abjuration Savant (School of Abjuration)</name>
				<text>Beginning when you select this school at 2nd level, the gold and time you must spend to copy an abjuration spell into your spellbook is halved.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 115</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Arcane Ward (School of Abjuration)</name>
				<text>Starting at 2nd level, you can weave magic around yourself for protection. When you cast an abjuration spell of 1st level or higher, you can simultaneously use a strand of the spell&#8217;s magic to create a magical ward on yourself that lasts until you finish a long rest. The ward has hit points equal to twice your wizard level + your Intelligence modifier. Whenever you take damage, the ward takes the damage instead. If this damage reduces the ward to 0 hit points, you take any remaining damage.</text>
				<text>	While the ward has 0 hit points, it can&#8217;t absorb damage, but its magic remains. Whenever you cast an abjuration spell of 1st level or higher, the ward regains a number of hit points equal to twice the level of the spell.</text>
				<text>	Once you create the ward, you can&#8217;t create it again until you finish a long rest.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 115</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Arcane Tradition: School of Conjuration</name>
				<text>When you reach 2nd level, you choose an arcane tradition, shaping your practice of magic through one of eight schools: Abjuration, Conjuration, Divination, Enchantment, Evocation, Illusion, Necromancy, or Transmutation, all detailed at the end of the class description.</text>
				<text>	Your choice grants you features at 2nd level and again at 6th, 10th, and 14th level.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 116</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Conjuration Savant (School of Conjuration)</name>
				<text>Beginning when you select this school at 2nd level, the gold and time you must spend to copy a conjuration spell into your spellbook is halved.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 116</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Minor Conjuration (School of Conjuration)</name>
				<text>Starting at 2nd level when you select this school, you can use your action to conjure up an inanimate object in your hand or on the ground in an unoccupied space that you can see within 10 feet of you. This object can be no larger than 3 feet on a side and weigh no more than 10 pounds, and its form must be that of a nonmagical object that you have seen. The object is visibly magical, radiating dim light out to 5 feet.</text>
				<text>	The object disappears after 1 hour, when you use this feature again, or if it takes or deals any damage.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 116</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Arcane Tradition: School of Divination</name>
				<text>When you reach 2nd level, you choose an arcane tradition, shaping your practice of magic through one of eight schools: Abjuration, Conjuration, Divination, Enchantment, Evocation, Illusion, Necromancy, or Transmutation, all detailed at the end of the class description.</text>
				<text>	Your choice grants you features at 2nd level and again at 6th, 10th, and 14th level.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 116</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Divination Savant (School of Divination)</name>
				<text>Beginning when you select this school at 2nd level, the gold and time you must spend to copy a divination spell into your spellbook is halved.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 116</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Portent (School of Divination)</name>
				<text>Starting at 2nd level when you choose this school, glimpses of the future begin to press in on your awareness. When you finish a long rest, roll two d20s and record the numbers rolled. You can replace any attack roll, saving throw, or ability check made by you or a creature that you can see with one of these foretelling rolls. You must choose to do so before the roll, and you can replace a roll in this way only once per turn.</text>
				<text>	Each foretelling roll can be used only once. When you finish a long rest, you lose any unused foretelling rolls.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 116</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Arcane Tradition: School of Enchantment</name>
				<text>When you reach 2nd level, you choose an arcane tradition, shaping your practice of magic through one of eight schools: Abjuration, Conjuration, Divination, Enchantment, Evocation, Illusion, Necromancy, or Transmutation, all detailed at the end of the class description.</text>
				<text>	Your choice grants you features at 2nd level and again at 6th, 10th, and 14th level.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 117</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Enchantment Savant (School of Enchantment)</name>
				<text>Beginning when you select this school at 2nd level, the gold and time you must spend to copy an enchantment spell into your spellbook is halved.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 117</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Hypnotic Gaze (School of Enchantment)</name>
				<text>Starting at 2nd level when you choose this school, your soft words and enchanting gaze can magically enthrall another creature. As an action, choose one creature that you can see within 5 feet of you. If the target can see or hear you, it must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw against your wizard spell save DC or be charmed by you until the end of your next turn. The charmed creature&#8217;s speed drops to 0, and the creature is incapacitated and visibly dazed.</text>
				<text>	On subsequent turns, you can use your action to maintain this effect, extending its duration until the end of your next turn. However, the effect ends if you move more than 5 feet away from the creature, if the creature can neither see nor hear you, or if the creature takes damage.</text>
				<text>	Once the effect ends, or if the creature succeeds on its initial saving throw against this effect, you can&#8217;t use this feature on that creature again until you finish a long rest.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Charmed:</text>
				<text>&#8226; A charmed creature can't attack the charmer or target the charmer with harmful abilities or magical effects.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>&#8226; The charmer has advantage on any ability check to interact socially with the creature.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Incapacitated:</text>
				<text>&#8226; An incapacitated creature can't take actions or reactions.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 117</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Arcane Tradition: School of Evocation</name>
				<text>When you reach 2nd level, you choose an arcane tradition, shaping your practice of magic through one of eight schools: Abjuration, Conjuration, Divination, Enchantment, Evocation, Illusion, Necromancy, or Transmutation, all detailed at the end of the class description.</text>
				<text>	Your choice grants you features at 2nd level and again at 6th, 10th, and 14th level.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 117</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Evocation Savant (School of Evocation)</name>
				<text>Beginning when you select this school at 2nd level, the gold and time you must spend to copy an evocation spell into your spellbook is halved.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 117</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Sculpt Spells (School of Evocation)</name>
				<text>Beginning at 2nd level, you can create pockets of relative safety within the effects of your evocation spells. When you cast an evocation spell that affects other creatures that you can see, you can choose a number of them equal to 1+the spell&#8217;s level. The chosen creatures automatically succeed on their saving throws against the spell, and they take no damage if they would normally take half damage on a successful save.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 117</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Arcane Tradition: School of Illusion</name>
				<text>When you reach 2nd level, you choose an arcane tradition, shaping your practice of magic through one of eight schools: Abjuration, Conjuration, Divination, Enchantment, Evocation, Illusion, Necromancy, or Transmutation, all detailed at the end of the class description.</text>
				<text>	Your choice grants you features at 2nd level and again at 6th, 10th, and 14th level.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 118</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Illusion Savant (School of Illusion)</name>
				<text>Beginning when you select this school at 2nd level, the gold and time you must spend to copy an illusion spell into your spellbook is halved.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 118</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Improved Minor Illusion (School of Illusion)</name>
				<text>When you choose this school at 2nd level, you learn the minor illusion cantrip. If you already know this cantrip, you learn a different wizard cantrip of your choice. The cantrip doesn&#8217;t count against your number of cantrips known.</text>
				<text>	When you cast minor illusion, you can create both a sound and an image with a single casting of the spell.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 118</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Arcane Tradition: School of Necromancy</name>
				<text>When you reach 2nd level, you choose an arcane tradition, shaping your practice of magic through one of eight schools: Abjuration, Conjuration, Divination, Enchantment, Evocation, Illusion, Necromancy, or Transmutation, all detailed at the end of the class description.</text>
				<text>	Your choice grants you features at 2nd level and again at 6th, 10th, and 14th level.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 118</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Necromancy Savant (School of Necromancy)</name>
				<text>Beginning when you select this school at 2nd level, the gold and time you must spend to copy a necromancy spell into your spellbook is halved.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 118</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Grim Harvest (School of Necromancy)</name>
				<text>At 2nd level, you gain the ability to reap life energy from creatures you kill with your spells. Once per turn when you kill one or more creatures with a spell of 1st level or higher, you regain hit points equal to twice the spell&#8217;s level, or three times its level if the spell belongs to the School of Necromancy. You don&#8217;t gain this benefit for killing constructs or undead.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 118</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Arcane Tradition: School of Transmutation</name>
				<text>When you reach 2nd level, you choose an arcane tradition, shaping your practice of magic through one of eight schools: Abjuration, Conjuration, Divination, Enchantment, Evocation, Illusion, Necromancy, or Transmutation, all detailed at the end of the class description.</text>
				<text>	Your choice grants you features at 2nd level and again at 6th, 10th, and 14th level.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 119</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Transmutation Savant (School of Transmutation)</name>
				<text>Beginning when you select this school at 2nd level, the gold and time you must spend to copy a transmutation spell into your spellbook is halved.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 119</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Minor Alchemy (School of Transmutation)</name>
				<text>Starting at 2nd level when you select this school, you can temporarily alter the physical properties of one nonmagical object, changing it from one substance into another. You perform a special alchemical procedure on one object composed entirely of wood, stone (but not a gemstone), iron, copper, or silver, transforming it into a different one of those materials. For each 10 minutes you spend performing the procedure, you can transform up to 1 cubic foot of material. After 1 hour, or until you lose your concentration (as if you were concentrating on a spell), the material reverts to its original substance.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 119</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Arcane Tradition: War Magic</name>
				<text>A variety of arcane colleges specialize in training wizards for war. The tradition of War Magic blends principles of evocation and abjuration, rather than specializing in either of those schools. It teaches techniques that empower a caster&#8217;s spells, while also providing methods for a wizard to bolster their own defenses.</text>
				<text>	Followers of this tradition are known as war mages. They see their magic as both a weapon and armor, a resource superior to any flimsy piece of steel. War mages act fast in battle, using their spells to seize tactical control of a situation. Their spells strike hard, while their defensive skills foil their opponents&#8217; attempts to counterattack. War mages are also adept at turning other spellcasters&#8217; magical energy against them.</text>
				<text>	In great battles, a war mage often works with evokers, abjurers, and other types of wizards. Evokers, in particular, sometimes tease war mages for splitting their attention between offense and defense. A war mage&#8217;s typical response: "What good is being able to throw a mighty fireball if I die before I can cast it?"</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Xanathar's Guide to Everything, p. 59</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Arcane Deflection (War Magic)</name>
				<text>At 2nd level, you have learned to weave your magic to fortify yourself against harm. When you are hit by an attack or fail a Constitution saving throw, you can use your reaction to gain a +2 bonus to your AC against that attack or a +4 bonus to that saving throw.</text>
				<text>	When you use this feature, you can&#8217;t cast spells other than cantrips until the end of your next turn.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Xanathar's Guide to Everything, p. 59</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Tactical Wit (War Magic)</name>
				<text>Starting at 2nd level, your ability to quickly assess tactical situations allows you to act quickly in battle. You can give yourself a bonus to your initiative rolls equal to your Intelligence modifier.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Xanathar's Guide to Everything, p. 60</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots>3, 4, 2</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots>4, 4, 3</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can&#8217;t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
				<text>	If your DM uses the optional Feats, you can instead take a feat.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 115</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots>3, 4, 3, 2</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots>3, 4, 3, 3</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Extra Attack (Bladesinging)</name>
				<text>Starting at 6th level, you can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Sword Coast Adventurer's Guide, p. 142</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Projected Ward (School of Abjuration)</name>
				<text>Starting at 6th level, when a creature that you can see within 30 feet of you takes damage, you can use your reaction to cause your Arcane Ward to absorb that damage. If this damage reduces the ward to 0 hit points, the warded creature takes any remaining damage.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 115</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Benign Transposition (School of Conjuration)</name>
				<text>Starting at 6th level, you can use your action to teleport up to 30 feet to an unoccupied space that you can see. Alternatively, you can choose a space within range that is occupied by a Small or Medium creature. If that creature is willing, you both teleport, swapping places.</text>
				<text>	Once you use this feature, you can&#8217;t use it again until you finish a long rest or you cast a conjuration spell of 1st level or higher.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 116</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Expert Divination (School of Divination)</name>
				<text>Beginning at 6th level, casting divination spells comes so easily to you that it expends only a fraction of your spellcasting efforts. When you cast a divination spell of 2nd level or higher using a spell slot, you regain one expended spell slot. The slot you regain must be of a level lower than the spell you cast and can&#8217;t be higher than 5th level.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 116</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Instinctive Charm (School of Enchantment)</name>
				<text>Beginning at 6th level, when a creature you can see within 30 feet of you makes an attack roll against you, you can use your reaction to divert the attack, provided that another creature is within the attack&#8217;s range. The attacker must make a Wisdom saving throw against your wizard spell save DC. On a failed save, the attacker must target the creature that is closest to it, not including you or itself. If multiple creatures are closest, the attacker chooses which one to target. On a successful save, you can&#8217;t use this feature on the attacker again until you finish a long rest.</text>
				<text>	You must choose to use this feature before knowing whether the attack hits or misses. Creatures that can&#8217;t be charmed are immune to this effect.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 117</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Potent Cantrip (School of Evocation)</name>
				<text>Starting at 6th level, your damaging cantrips affect even creatures that avoid the brunt of the effect. When a creature succeeds on a saving throw against your cantrip, the creature takes half the cantrip&#8217;s damage (if any) but suffers no additional effect from the cantrip.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 117</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Malleable Illusions (School of Illusion)</name>
				<text>Starting at 6th level, when you cast an illusion spell that has a duration of 1 minute or longer, you can use your action to change the nature of that illusion (using the spell&#8217;s normal parameters for the illusion), provided that you can see the illusion.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 118</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Undead Thralls (School of Necromancy)</name>
				<text>At 6th level, you add the animate dead spell to your spellbook if it is not there already. When you cast animate dead, you can target one additional corpse or pile of bones, creating another zombie or skeleton, as appropriate.</text>
				<text>	Whenever you create an undead using a necromancy spell, it has additional benefits.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>&#8226; The creature&#8217;s hit point maximum is increased by an amount equal to your wizard level.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>&#8226; The creature adds your proficiency bonus to its weapon damage rolls.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 119</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Transmuter's Stone (School of Transmutation)</name>
				<text>Starting at 6th level, you can spend 8 hours creating a transmuter&#8217;s stone that stores transmutation magic. You can benefit from the stone yourself or give it to another creature. A creature gains a benefit of your choice as long as the stone is in the creature&#8217;s possession. When you create the stone, choose the benefit from the following options.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>&#8226; Darkvision out to a range of 60 feet, as described in chapter 8</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>&#8226; An increase to speed of 10 feet while the creature is unencumbered</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>&#8226; Proficiency in Constitution saving throws</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>&#8226; Resistance to acid, cold, fire, lightning, or thunder damage (your choice whenever you choose this benefit).</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>	Each time you cast a transmutation spell of 1st level or higher, you can change the effect of your stone if the stone is on your person.</text>
				<text>	If you create a new transmuter&#8217;s stone, the previous one ceases to function.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 119</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Power Surge (War Magic)</name>
				<text>Starting at 6th level,you can store magical energy within yourself to later empower your damaging spells. In its stored form, this energy is called a power surge.</text>
				<text>	You can store a maximum number of power surges equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum of one). Whenever you finish a long rest, your number of power surges resets to one. Whenever you successfully end a spell with dispel magic or counterspell, you gain one power surge, as you steal magic from the spell you foiled. If you end a short rest with no power surges, you gain one power surge.</text>
				<text>	Once per turn when you deal damage to a creature or object with a wizard spell, you can spend one power surge to deal extra force damage to that target. The extra damage equals half your wizard level.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Xanathar's Guide to Everything, p. 60</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots>3, 4, 3, 3, 1</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots>3, 4, 3, 3, 2</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Ability Score Improvement (2nd)</name>
				<text>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can&#8217;t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
				<text>	If your DM uses the optional Feats, you can instead take a feat.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 115</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots>3, 4, 3, 3, 3, 1</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots>5, 4, 3, 3, 3, 2</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Song of Defense (Bladesinging)</name>
				<text>Beginning at 10th level, you can direct your magic to absorb damage while your bladesong is active. When you take damage, you can use your reaction to expend one spell slot and reduce that damage to you by an amount equal to five times the spell&#8217;s slot level.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Sword Coast Adventurer's Guide, p. 142</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Improved Abjuration (School of Abjuration)</name>
				<text>Beginning at 10th level, when you cast an abjuration spell that requires you to make an ability check as a part of casting that spell (as in counterspell and dispel magic), you add your proficiency bonus to that ability check.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 115</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Focused Conjuration (School of Conjuration)</name>
				<text>Beginning at 10th level, while you are concentrating on a conjuration spell, your concentration can&#8217;t be broken as a result of taking damage.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 116</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>The Third Eye (School of Divination)</name>
				<text>Starting at 10th level, you can use your action to increase your powers of perception. When you do so, choose one of the following benefits, which lasts until you are incapacitated or you take a short or long rest. You can&#8217;t use the feature again until you finish a rest.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Darkvision:</text>
				<text>	You gain darkvision out to a range of 60 feet, as described in chapter 8. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Ethereal Sight:</text>
				<text>	You can see into the Ethereal Plane within 60 feet of you. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Greater Comprehension:</text>
				<text>	You can read any language. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>See Invisibility:</text>
				<text>	You can see invisible creatures and objects within 10 feet of you that are within line of sight.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 116</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Split Enchantment (School of Enchantment)</name>
				<text>Starting at 10th level, when you cast an enchantment spell of 1st level or higher that targets only one creature, you can have it target a second creature.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 117</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Empowered Evocation (School of Evocation)</name>
				<text>Beginning at 10th level, you can add your Intelligence modifier to one damage roll of any wizard evocation spell you cast.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 117</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Illusory Step (School of Illusion)</name>
				<text>Beginning at 10th level, you can create an illusory duplicate of yourself as an instant, almost instinctual reaction to danger. When a creature makes an attack roll against you, you can use your reaction to interpose the illusory duplicate between the attacker and yourself. The attack automatically misses you, then the illusion dissipates.</text>
				<text>	Once you use this feature, you can&#8217;t use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 118</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Inured to Undeath (School of Necromancy)</name>
				<text>Beginning at 10th level, you have resistance to necrotic damage, and your hit point maximum can&#8217;t be reduced. You have spent so much time dealing with undead and the forces that animate them that you have become inured to some of their worst effects.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 119</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Shapechanger (School of Transmutation)</name>
				<text>At 10th level, you add the polymorph spell to your spellbook, if it is not there already. You can cast polymorph without expending a spell slot. When you do so, you can target only yourself and transform into a beast whose challenge rating is 1 or lower.</text>
				<text>	Once you cast polymorph in this way, you can&#8217;t do so again until you finish a short or long rest, though you can still cast it normally using an available spell slot.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 119</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Durable Magic (War Magic)</name>
				<text>Beginning at 10th level, the magic you channel helps ward off harm. While you maintain concentration on a spell, you have a +2 bonus to AC and all saving throws.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Xanathar's Guide to Everything, p. 60</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots>5, 4, 3, 3, 3, 2, 1</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots>5, 4, 3, 3, 3, 2, 1</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Ability Score Improvement (3rd)</name>
				<text>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can&#8217;t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
				<text>	If your DM uses the optional Feats, you can instead take a feat.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 115</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots>5, 4, 3, 3, 3, 2, 1, 1</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots>5, 4, 3, 3, 3, 2, 1, 1</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Song of Victory (Bladesinging)</name>
				<text>Starting at 14th level, you add your Intelligence modifier (minimum of +1) to the damage of your melee weapon attacks while your Bladesong is active.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Sword Coast Adventurer's Guide, p. 142</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Spell Resistance (School of Abjuration)</name>
				<text>Starting at 14th level, you have advantage on saving throws against spells.</text>
				<text>	Furthermore, you have resistance against the damage of spells.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 116</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Durable Summons (School of Conjuration)</name>
				<text>Starting at 14th level, any creature that you summon or create with a conjuration spell has 30 temporary hit points.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 116</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Greater Portent (School of Divination)</name>
				<text>Starting at 14th level, the visions in your dreams intensify and paint a more accurate picture in your mind of what is to come. You roll three d20s for your Portent feature, rather than two.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 117</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Alter Memories (School of Enchantment)</name>
				<text>At 14th level, you gain the ability to make a creature unaware of your magical influence on it. When you cast an enchantment spell to charm one or more creatures, you can alter one creature&#8217;s understanding so that it remains unaware of being charmed.</text>
				<text>	Additionally, once before the spell expires, you can use your action to try to make the chosen creature forget some of the time it spent charmed. The creature must succeed on an Intelligence saving throw against your wizard spell save DC or lose a number of hours of its memories equal to 1 + your Charisma modifier (minimum 1). You can make the creature forget less time, and the amount of time can&#8217;t exceed the duration of your enchantment spell.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 117</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Overchannel (School of Evocation)</name>
				<text>Starting at 14th level, you can increase the power of your simpler spells. When you cast a wizard spell of 1st through 5th level that deals damage, you can deal maximum damage with that spell.</text>
				<text>	The first time you do so, you suffer no adverse effect. If you use this feature again before you finish a long rest, you take 2d12 necrotic damage for each level of the spell, immediately after you cast it. Each time you use this feature again before finishing a long rest, the necrotic damage per spell level increases by 1d12. This damage ignores resistance and immunity.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 118</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Illusory Reality (School of Illusion)</name>
				<text>By 14th level, you have learned the secret of weaving shadow magic into your illusions to give them a semireality. When you cast an illusion spell of 1st level or higher, you can choose one inanimate, nonmagical object that is part of the illusion and make that object real. You can do this on your turn as a bonus action while the spell is ongoing. The object remains real for 1 minute. For example, you can create an illusion of a bridge over a chasm and then make it real long enough for your allies to cross.</text>
				<text>	The object can&#8217;t deal damage or otherwise directly harm anyone.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 118</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Command Undead (School of Necromancy)</name>
				<text>Starting at 14th level, you can use magic to bring undead under your control, even those created by other wizards. As an action, you can choose one undead that you can see within 60 feet of you. That creature must make a Charisma saving throw against your wizard spell save DC. If it succeeds, you can&#8217;t use this feature on it again. If it fails, it becomes friendly to you and obeys your commands until you use this feature again.</text>
				<text>	Intelligent undead are harder to control in this way. If the target has an Intelligence of 8 or higher, it has advantage on the saving throw. If it fails the saving throw and has an Intelligence of 12 or higher, it can repeat the saving throw at the end of every hour until it succeeds and breaks free.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 119</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Master Transmuter (School of Transmutation)</name>
				<text>Starting at 14th level, you can use your action to consume the reserve of transmutation magic stored within your transmuter&#8217;s stone in a single burst. When you do so, choose one of the following effects. Your transmuter&#8217;s stone is destroyed and can&#8217;t be remade until you finish a long rest. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Major Transformation:</text>
				<text>	You can transmute one nonmagical object &#8212; no larger than a 5-foot cube &#8212; into another nonmagical object of similar size and mass and of equal or lesser value. You must spend 10 minutes handling the object to transform it. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Panacea:</text>
				<text>	You remove all curses, diseases, and poisons affecting a creature that you touch with the transmuter&#8217;s stone. The creature also regains all its hit points. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Restore Life:</text>
				<text>	You cast the raise dead spell on a creature you touch with the transmuter&#8217;s stone, without expending a spell slot or needing to have the spell in your spellbook. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Restore Youth: </text>
				<text>	You touch the transmuter&#8217;s stone to a willing creature, and that creature&#8217;s apparent age is reduced by 3d10 years, to a minimum of 13 years. This effect doesn&#8217;t extend the creature&#8217;s lifespan.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 119</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Deflecting Shroud (War Magic)</name>
				<text>At 14th level, your Arcane Deflection becomes infused with deadly magic. When you use your Arcane Deflection feature, you can cause magical energy to arc from you. Up to three creatures of your choice that you can see within 60 feet of you each take force damage equal to half your wizard level.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Xanathar's Guide to Everything, p. 60</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots>5, 4, 3, 3, 3, 2, 1, 1, 1</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots>5, 4, 3, 3, 3, 2, 1, 1, 1</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Ability Score Improvement (4th)</name>
				<text>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can&#8217;t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
				<text>	If your DM uses the optional Feats, you can instead take a feat.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 115</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots>5, 4, 3, 3, 3, 2, 1, 1, 1, 1</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots>5, 4, 3, 3, 3, 3, 1, 1, 1, 1</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Spell Mastery</name>
				<text>At 18th level, you have achieved such mastery over certain spells that you can cast them at will. Choose a 1st-level wizard spell and a 2nd-level wizard spell that are in your spellbook. You can cast those spells at their lowest level without expending a spell slot when you have them prepared. If you want to cast either spell at a higher level, you must expend a spell slot as normal.</text>
				<text>	By spending 8 hours in study, you can exchange one or both of the spells you chose for different spells of the same levels.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 115</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots>5, 4, 3, 3, 3, 3, 2, 1, 1, 1</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Ability Score Improvement (5th)</name>
				<text>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can&#8217;t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
				<text>	If your DM uses the optional Feats, you can instead take a feat.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 115</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			<slots>5, 4, 3, 3, 3, 3, 2, 2, 1, 1</slots>
		</lvl##skill>

		<lvl##skill>
			
				<name>Signature Spell</name>
				<text>When you reach 20th level, you gain mastery over two powerful spells and can cast them with little effort. Choose two 3rd-level wizard spells in your spellbook as your signature spells. You always have these spells prepared, they don&#8217;t count against the number of spells you have prepared, and you can cast each of them once at 3rd level without expending a spell slot. When you do so, you can&#8217;t do so again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
				<text>	If you want to cast either spell at a higher level, you must expend a spell slot as normal.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook, p. 115</text>
			
		</lvl##skill>
</subclass>