<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">


<subclass>
	<name>barbarian core</name>
	<class>Barbarian</class>
	<hd>12</hd>
	<saves>Strength, Constitution</saves>
	<proficiency>Animal Handling, Athletics, Intimidation, Nature, Perception, Survival</proficiency>
	<spellAbility></spellAbility>
	<numSkills>2</numSkills>
		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Starting Barbarian</name>
				<text>As a 1st-level Barbarian, you begin play with 12+your Constitution modifier hit points.</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>You are proficient with the following items, in addition to any proficiencies provided by your race or background.</text>
				<text>&#8226; Armor: light armor, medium armor, shields</text>
				<text>&#8226; Weapons: simple weapons, martial weapons</text>
				<text>&#8226; Tools: none</text>
				<text>&#8226; Skills: Choose two from Animal Handling, Athletics, Intimidation, Nature, Perception, and Survival</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>You begin play with the following equipment, in addition to any equipment provided by your background.</text>
				<text>&#8226; (a) a greataxe or (b) any martial melee weapon</text>
				<text>&#8226; (a) two handaxes or (b) any simple weapon</text>
				<text>&#8226; An explorer's pack and four javelins</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>Alternatively, you may start with 2d4x10 gp and choose your own equipment.</text>
				<text> </text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<multiclass>
			
				<name>Multiclass Barbarian</name>
				<text>To multiclass as a Barbarian, you must meet the following prerequisites:</text>
				<text>&#8226; Strength 13</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>You gain the following proficiencies:</text>
				<text>&#8226; shields, simple weapons, martial weapons</text>
				<text> </text>
			
		</multiclass>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Rage</name>
				<text>In battle, you fight with primal ferocity. On your turn, you can enter a rage as a bonus action.</text>
				<text>	While raging, you gain the following benefits if you aren&#8217;t wearing heavy armor.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>&#8226; You have advantage on Strength checks and Strength saving throws.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>&#8226; When you make a melee weapon attack using Strength, you gain a bonus to the damage roll that increases as you gain levels as a barbarian. At 1st level, you have a +2 bonus to damage. Your bonus increases to +3 at 9th level and to +4 at 16th.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>&#8226; You have resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>	If you are able to cast spells, you can&#8217;t cast them or concentrate on them while raging.</text>
				<text>	Your rage lasts for 1 minute. It ends early if you are knocked unconscious or if your turn ends and you haven&#8217;t attacked a hostile creature since your last turn or taken damage since then. You can also end your rage on your turn as a bonus action.</text>
				<text>	Once you have raged the maximum number of times for your barbarian level, you must finish a long rest before you can rage again. You may rage 2 times at 1st level, 3 at 3rd, 4 at 6th, 5 at 12th, and 6 at 17th.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Unarmored Defense</name>
				<text>While you are not wearing any armor, your Armor Class equals 10 + your Dexterity modifier + your Constitution modifier. You can use a shield and still gain this benefit.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Reckless Attack</name>
				<text>Starting at 2nd level, you can throw aside all concern for defense to attack with fierce desperation. When you make your first attack on your turn, you can decide to attack recklessly. Doing so gives you advantage on melee weapon attack rolls using Strength during this turn, but attack rolls against you have advantage until your next turn.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Danger Sense</name>
				<text>At 2nd level, you gain an uncanny sense of when things nearby aren&#8217;t as they should be, giving you an edge when you dodge away from danger.</text>
				<text>	You have advantage on Dexterity saving throws against effects that you can see, such as traps and spells. To gain this benefit, you can&#8217;t be blinded, deafened, or incapacitated.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Primal Path</name>
				<text>At 3rd level, you choose a path that shapes the nature of your rage. Choose the Path of the Berserker or the Path of the Totem Warrior.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Extra Attack</name>
				<text>Beginning at 5th level, you can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Fast Movement</name>
				<text>Starting at 5th level, your speed increases by 10 feet while you aren&#8217;t wearing heavy armor.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Feral Instinct</name>
				<text>By 7th level, your instincts are so honed that you have advantage on initiative rolls.</text>
				<text>	Additionally, if you are surprised at the beginning of combat and aren&#8217;t incapacitated, you can act normally on your first turn, but only if you enter your rage before doing anything else on that turn.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Brutal Critical</name>
				<text>Beginning at 9th level, you can roll one additional weapon damage die when determining the extra damage for a critical hit with a melee attack.</text>
				<text>	This increases to two additional dice at 13th level and three additional dice at 17th level.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Relentless Rage</name>
				<text>Starting at 11th level, your rage can keep you fighting despite grievous wounds. If you drop to 0 hit points while you&#8217;re raging and don&#8217;t die outright, you can make a DC 10 Constitution saving throw. If you succeed, you drop to 1 hit point instead.</text>
				<text>	Each time you use this feature after the first, the DC increases by 5. When you finish a short or long rest, the DC resets to 10.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Persistent Rage</name>
				<text>Beginning at 15th level, your rage is so fierce that it ends early only if you fall unconscious or if you choose to end it.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Indomitable Might</name>
				<text>Beginning at 18th level, if your total for a Strength check is less than your Strength score, you can use that score in place of the total.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Primal Champion</name>
				<text>At 20th level, you embody the power of the wilds. Your Strength and Constitution scores increase by 4. Your maximum for those scores is now 24.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				
			
		</lvlskill>

</subclass>


<subclass>
	<name>Bard</name>
	<hd>8</hd>
	<proficiency>Acrobatics, Animal Handling, Arcana, Athletics, Deception, History, Insight, Intimidation, Investigation, Medicine, Nature, Perception, Performance, Persuasion, Religion, Sleight of Hand, Stealth, Survival</proficiency>
	<spellAbility>Charisma</spellAbility>
	<numSkills>3</numSkills>
	<saves>Dexterity, Charisma</saves>

	<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Starting Bard</name>
				<text>As a 1st-level Bard, you begin play with 8+your Constitution modifier hit points.</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>You are proficient with the following items, in addition to any proficiencies provided by your race or background.</text>
				<text>&#8226; Armor: light armor</text>
				<text>&#8226; Weapons: simple weapons, hand crossbows, longswords, rapiers, shortswords</text>
				<text>&#8226; Tools: three musical instruments of your choice</text>
				<text>&#8226; Skills: Choose any three</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>You begin play with the following equipment, in addition to any equipment provided by your background.</text>
				<text>&#8226; (a) a rapier, (b) a longsword, or (c) any simple weapon</text>
				<text>&#8226; (a) a diplomat's pack or (b) an entertainer's pack</text>
				<text>&#8226; (a) a lute or (b) any other musical instrument</text>
				<text>&#8226; Leather armor and a dagger</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>Alternatively, you may start with 5d4x10 gp and choose your own equipment.</text>
				<text> </text>
				
			
		</lvlskill>

		<multiclass>
			
				<name>Multiclass Bard</name>
				<text>To multiclass as a Bard, you must meet the following prerequisites:</text>
				<text>&#8226; Charisma 13</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>You gain the following proficiencies:</text>
				<text>&#8226; light armor, one skill of your choice, one musical instrument of your choice</text>
				<text> </text>
			
			
		</multiclass>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Spellcasting</name>
				<text>You have learned to untangle and reshape the fabric of reality in harmony with your wishes and music. Your spells are part of your vast repertoire, magic that you can tune to different situations. See chapter 10 for the general rules of spellcasting and chapter 11 for the bard spell list.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Cantrips:</text>
				<text>	You know two cantrips of your choice from the bard spell list. You learn additional bard cantrips of your choice at higher levels, learning a 3rd cantrip at 4th level and a 4th at 10th level.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Spell Slots:</text>
				<text>	The Bard table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your spells of 1st level and higher. To cast one of these spells, you must expend a slot of the spell&#8217;s level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.</text>
				<text>	For example, if you know the 1st-level spell cure wounds and have a 1st-level and a 2nd-level spell slot available, you can cast cure wounds using either slot.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Spells Known of 1st Level and Higher:</text>
				<text>	You know four 1st-level spells of your choice from the bard spell list.</text>
				<text>	You learn an additional bard spell of your choice at each level except 12th, 16th, 19th, and 20th. Each of these spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots. For instance, when you reach 3rd level in this class, you can learn one new spell of 1st or 2nd level.</text>
				<text>	Additionally, when you gain a level in this class, you can choose one of the bard spells you know and replace it with another spell from the bard spell list, which also must be of a level for which you have spell slots.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Spellcasting Ability:</text>
				<text>	Charisma is your spellcasting ability for your bard spells. Your magic comes from the heart and soul you pour into the performance of your music or oration. You use your Charisma whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Charisma modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a bard spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.</text>
				<text>	Spell save DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier</text>
				<text>	Spell attack modifier = your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Ritual Casting:</text>
				<text>	You can cast any bard spell you know as a ritual if that spell has the ritual tag.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Spellcasting Focus:</text>
				<text>	You can use a musical instrument (found in chapter 5) as a spellcasting focus for your bard spells.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Bardic Inspiration</name>
				<text>You can inspire others through stirring words or music. To do so, you use a bonus action on your turn to choose one creature other than yourself within 60 feet of you who can hear you. That creature gains one Bardic Inspiration die, a d6.</text>
				<text>	Once within the next 10 minutes, the creature can roll the die and add the number rolled to one ability check, attack roll, or saving throw it makes. The creature can wait until after it rolls the d20 before deciding to use the Bardic Inspiration die, but must decide before the DM says whether the roll succeeds or fails. Once the Bardic Inspiration die is rolled, it is lost. A creature can have only one Bardic Inspiration die at a time.</text>
				<text>	You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Charisma modifier (a minimum of once). You regain any expended uses when you finish a long rest.</text>
				<text>	Your Bardic Inspiration die changes when you reach certain levels in this class. The die becomes a d8 at 5th level, a d10 at 10th level, and a d12 at 15th level.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Jack of All Trades</name>
				<text>Starting at 2nd level, you can add half your proficiency bonus, rounded down, to any ability check you make that doesn&#8217;t already include your proficiency bonus.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Song of Rest</name>
				<text>Beginning at 2nd level, you can use soothing music or oration to help revitalize your wounded allies during a short rest. If you or any friendly creatures who can hear your performance regain hit points at the end of the short rest by spending one or more Hit Dice, each of those creatures regains an extra 1d6 hit points.</text>
				<text>	The extra hit points increase when you reach certain levels in this class: to 1d8 at 9th level, to 1d10 at 13th level, and to 1d12 at 17th level.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Expertise</name>
				<text>At 3rd level, choose two of your skill proficiencies. Your proficiency bonus is doubled for any ability check you make that uses either of the chosen proficiencies.</text>
				<text>	At 10th level, you can choose another two skill proficiencies to gain this benefit.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Bard College</name>
				<text>At 3rd level, you delve into the advanced techniques of a bard college of your choice: the College of Lore or the College of Valor, both detailed at the end of the class description. Your choice grants you features at 3rd level and again at 6th and 14th level.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				
			
		</lvlskill>
		
		
	
	</subclass>

		
<subclass>
	<name>cleric core</name>
	<class></class>
	<hd>8</hd>
	<saves>Wisdom, Charisma</saves>
	<proficiency>History, Insight, Medicine, Persuasion, Religion</proficiency>
	<spellAbility>Wisdom</spellAbility>
	<numSkills>2</numSkills>
		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Starting Cleric</name>
				<text>As a 1st-level Cleric, you begin play with 8+your Constitution modifier hit points.</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>You are proficient with the following items, in addition to any proficiencies provided by your race or background.</text>
				<text>&#8226; Armor: light armor, medium armor, shields</text>
				<text>&#8226; Weapons: simple weapons</text>
				<text>&#8226; Tools: none</text>
				<text>&#8226; Skills: Choose two from History, Insight, Medicine, Persuasion, and Religion</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>You begin play with the following equipment, in addition to any equipment provided by your background.</text>
				<text>&#8226; (a) a mace or (b) a warhammer (if proficient)</text>
				<text>&#8226; (a) scale mail, (b) leather armor, or (c) chain mail (if proficient)</text>
				<text>&#8226; (a) a light crossbow and 20 bolts or (b) any simple weapon</text>
				<text>&#8226; (a) a priest's pack or (b) an explorer's pack</text>
				<text>&#8226; A shield and a holy symbol</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>Alternatively, you may start with 5d4x10 gp and choose your own equipment.</text>
				<text> </text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<multiclass>
			
				<name>Multiclass Cleric</name>
				<text>To multiclass as a Cleric, you must meet the following prerequisites:</text>
				<text>&#8226; Wisdom 13</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>You gain the following proficiencies:</text>
				<text>&#8226; light armor, medium armor, shields</text>
				<text> </text>
			
		</multiclass>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Spellcasting</name>
				<text>As a conduit for divine power, you can cast cleric spells. See chapter 10 for the general rules of spellcasting and chapter 11 for the cleric spell list.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Cantrips:</text>
				<text>	At 1st level, you know three cantrips of your choice from the cleric spell list. You learn an additional cleric cantrip of your choice at 4th level and another at 10th level. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Preparing and Casting Spells:</text>
				<text>	The Cleric table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your spells of 1st level and higher. To cast one of these spells, you must expend a slot of the spell&#8217;s level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.</text>
				<text>	You prepare the list of cleric spells that are available for you to cast, choosing from the cleric spell list. When you do so, choose a number of cleric spells equal to your Wisdom modifier + your cleric level (minimum of one spell). The spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots.</text>
				<text>	For example, if you are a 3rd-level cleric, you have four 1st-level and two 2nd-level spell slots. With a Wisdom of 16, your list of prepared spells can include six spells of 1st or 2nd level, in any combination. If you prepare the 1st-level spell cure wounds, you can cast it using a 1st-level or 2nd-level slot. Casting the spell doesn&#8217;t remove it from your list of prepared spells.</text>
				<text>	You can change your list of prepared spells when you finish a long rest. Preparing a new list of cleric spells requires time spent in prayer and meditation: at least 1 minute per spell level for each spell on your list. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Spellcasting Ability:</text>
				<text>	Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for your cleric spells. The power of your spells comes from your devotion to your deity. You use your Wisdom whenever a cleric spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Wisdom modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a cleric spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.</text>
				<text>	Spell save DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier</text>
				<text>	Spell attack modifier = your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Ritual Casting:</text>
				<text>	You can cast a cleric spell as a ritual if that spell has the ritual tag and you have the spell prepared. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Spellcasting Focus:</text>
				<text>	You can use a holy symbol (found in chapter 5) as a spellcasting focus for your cleric spells.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Divine Domain</name>
				<text>Choose one domain related to your deity: Knowledge, Life, Light, Nature, Tempest, Trickery, or War. Each domain is detailed at the end of the class description, and each one provides examples of gods associated with it. Your choice grants you domain spells and other features when you choose it at 1st level. It also grants you additional ways to use Channel Divinity when you gain that feature at 2nd level, and additional benefits at 6th, 8th, and 17th levels. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Domain Spells:</text>
				<text>	Each domain has a list of spells &#8212; its domain spells &#8212; that you gain at the cleric levels noted in the domain description. Once you gain a domain spell, you always have it prepared, and it doesn&#8217;t count against the number of spells you can prepare each day.</text>
				<text>	If you have a domain spell that doesn&#8217;t appear on the cleric spell list, the spell is nonetheless a cleric spell for you.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Channel Divinity</name>
				<text>At 2nd level, you gain the ability to channel divine energy directly from your deity, using that energy to fuel magical effects. You start with two such effects: Turn Undead and an effect determined by your domain. Some domains grant you additional effects as you advance in levels, as noted in the domain description.</text>
				<text>	When you use your Channel Divinity, you choose which effect to create. You must then finish a short or long rest to use your Channel Divinity again.</text>
				<text>	Some Channel Divinity effects require saving throws. When you use such an effect from this class, the DC equals your cleric spell save DC.</text>
				<text>	Beginning at 6th level, you can use your Channel Divinity twice between rests, and beginning at 18th level, you can use it three times between rests. When you finish a short or long rest, you regain your expended uses. </text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Channel Divinity: Turn Undead</name>
				<text>As an action, you present your holy symbol and speak a prayer censuring the undead. Each undead that can see or hear you within 30 feet of you must make a Wisdom saving throw. If the creature fails its saving throw, it is turned for 1 minute or until it takes any damage.</text>
				<text>	A turned creature must spend its turns trying to move as far away from you as it can, and it can&#8217;t willingly move to a space within 30 feet of you. It also can&#8217;t take reactions. For its action, it can use only the Dash action or try to escape from an effect that prevents it from moving. If there&#8217;s nowhere to move, the creature can use the Dodge action.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>


		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Destroy Undead</name>
				<text>Starting at 5th level, when an undead fails its saving throw against your Turn Undead feature, the creature is instantly destroyed if its challenge rating is at or below a certain threshold</text>
				<text>	At 5th level, you destroy undead of CR 1/2 or lower; at 8th level, CR 1 or lower; at 11th level, CR 2 or lower; at 14th level, CR 3 or lower; and at 17th level, CR 4 or lower.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Divine Intervention</name>
				<text>Beginning at 10th level, you can call on your deity to intervene on your behalf when your need is great.</text>
				<text>	Imploring your deity&#8217;s aid requires you to use your action. Describe the assistance you seek, and roll percentile dice. If you roll a number equal to or lower than your cleric level, your deity intervenes. The DM chooses the nature of the intervention; the effect of any cleric spell or cleric domain spell would be appropriate.</text>
				<text>	If your deity intervenes, you can&#8217;t use this feature again for 7 days. Otherwise, you can use it again after you finish a long rest.</text>
				<text>	At 20th level, your call for intervention succeeds automatically, no roll required.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>


</subclass>


<subclass>
	<name>druid core</name>
	<class>Druid</class>
	<hd>8</hd>
	<saves>Intelligence, Wisdom</saves>
	<proficiency>Arcana, Animal Handling, Insight, Medicine, Nature, Perception, Religion, Survival</proficiency>
	<spellAbility>Wisdom</spellAbility>
	<numSkills>2</numSkills>
		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Starting Druid</name>
				<text>As a 1st-level Druid, you begin play with 8+your Constitution modifier hit points.</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>You are proficient with the following items, in addition to any proficiencies provided by your race or background.</text>
				<text>&#8226; Armor: light armor, medium armor, shields (druids will not wear armor or use shields made of metal)</text>
				<text>&#8226; Weapons: clubs, daggers, darts, javelins, maces, quarterstaffs, scimitars, sickles, slings, spears</text>
				<text>&#8226; Tools: herbalism kit</text>
				<text>&#8226; Skills: Choose two from Arcana, Animal Handling, Insight, Medicine, Nature, Perception, Religion, and Survival</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>You begin play with the following equipment, in addition to any equipment provided by your background.</text>
				<text>&#8226; (a) a wooden shield or (b) any simple weapon</text>
				<text>&#8226; (a) a scimitar or (b) any simple melee weapon</text>
				<text>&#8226; Leather armor, an explorer's pack, and a druidic focus</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>Alternatively, you may start with 2d4x10 gp and choose your own equipment.</text>
				<text> </text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<multiclass>
			
				<name>Multiclass Druid</name>
				<text>To multiclass as a Druid, you must meet the following prerequisites:</text>
				<text>&#8226; Wisdom 13</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>You gain the following proficiencies:</text>
				<text>&#8226; light armor, medium armor, shields (druids will not wear armor or use shields made of metal)</text>
				<text> </text>
			
		</multiclass>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Druidic</name>
				<text>You know Druidic, the secret language of druids. You can speak the language and use it to leave hidden messages. You and others who know this language automatically spot such a message. Others spot the message&#8217;s presence with a successful DC 15 Wisdom (Perception) check but can&#8217;t decipher it without magic.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Spellcasting</name>
				<text>Drawing on the divine essence of nature itself, you can cast spells to shape that essence to your will. See chapter 10 for the general rules of spellcasting and chapter 11 for the druid spell list. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Cantrips:</text>
				<text>	At 1st level, you know two cantrips of your choice from the druid spell list. You learn an additional druid cantrip of your choice at 4th level and another at 10th level. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Preparing and Casting Spells:</text>
				<text>	The Druid table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your spells of 1st level and higher. To cast one of these druid spells, you must expend a slot of the spell&#8217;s level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.</text>
				<text>	You prepare the list of druid spells that are available for you to cast, choosing from the druid spell list. When you do so, choose a number of druid spells equal to your Wisdom modifier + your druid level (minimum of one spell). The spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots.</text>
				<text>	For example, if you are a 3rd-level druid, you have four 1st-level and two 2nd-level spell slots. With a Wisdom of 16, your list of prepared spells can include six spells of 1st or 2nd level, in any combination. If you prepare the 1st-level spell cure wounds, you can cast it using a 1st-level or 2nd-level slot. Casting the spell doesn&#8217;t remove it from your list of prepared spells.</text>
				<text>	You can also change your list of prepared spells when you finish a long rest. Preparing a new list of druid spells requires time spent in prayer and meditation: at least 1 minute per spell level for each spell on your list. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Spellcasting Ability:</text>
				<text>	Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for your druid spells, since your magic draws upon your devotion and attunement to nature. You use your Wisdom whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Wisdom modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a druid spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.</text>
				<text>	Spell save DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier</text>
				<text>	Spell attack modifier = your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Ritual Casting:</text>
				<text>	You can cast a druid spell as a ritual if that spell has the ritual tag and you have the spell prepared. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Spellcasting Focus:</text>
				<text>	You can use a druidic focus (found in chapter 5) as a spellcasting focus for your druid spells.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Wild Shape</name>
				<text>Starting at 2nd level, you can use your action to magically assume the shape of a beast that you have seen before. You can use this feature twice. You regain expended uses when you finish a short or long rest.</text>
				<text>	Your druid level determines the beasts you can transform into, as shown in the Beast Shapes table (Player&#8217;s Handbook, p. 66).</text>
				<text>	At 2nd level, you can transform into any beast that has a challenge rating of 1/4 or lower that doesn&#8217;t have a flying or swimming speed. At 4th level, you can transform into any beast that has a challenge rating of 1/2 or lower that doesn&#8217;t have a flying speed. At 8th level, you can transform into any beast that has a challenge rating of 1 or lower.</text>
				<text>	You can stay in a beast shape for a number of hours equal to half your druid level (rounded down). You then revert to your normal form unless you expend another use of this feature. You can revert to your normal form earlier by using a bonus action on your turn. You automatically revert if you fall unconscious, drop to 0 hit points, or die.</text>
				<text>	While you are transformed, the following rules apply.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>&#8226; Your game statistics are replaced by the statistics of the beast, but you retain your alignment, personality, and Intelligence, Wisdom, and Charisma scores. You also retain all of your skill and saving throw proficiencies, in addition to gaining those of the creature. If the creature has the same proficiency as you and the bonus in its stat block is higher than yours, use the creature&#8217;s bonus instead of yours. If the creature has any legendary or lair actions, you can&#8217;t use them.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>&#8226; When you transform, you assume the beast&#8217;s hit points and Hit Dice. When you revert to your normal form, you return to the number of hit points you had before you transformed. However, if you revert as a result of dropping to 0 hit points, any excess damage carries over to your normal form. For example, if you take 10 damage in animal form and have only 1 hit point left, you revert and take 9 damage. As long as the excess damage doesn&#8217;t reduce your normal form to 0 hit points, you aren&#8217;t knocked unconscious.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>&#8226; You can&#8217;t cast spells, and your ability to speak or take any action that requires hands is limited to the capabilities of your beast form. Transforming doesn&#8217;t break your concentration on a spell you&#8217;ve already cast, however, or prevent you from taking actions that are part of a spell, such as call lightning, that you&#8217;ve already cast.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>&#8226; You retain the benefit of any features from your class, race, or other source and can use them if the new form is physically capable of doing so. However, you can&#8217;t use any of your special senses, such as darkvision, unless your new form also has that sense.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>&#8226; You choose whether your equipment falls to the ground in your space, merges into your new form, or is worn by it. Worn equipment functions as normal, but the DM decides whether it is practical for the new form to wear a piece of equipment, based on the creature&#8217;s shape and size. Your equipment doesn&#8217;t change size or shape to match the new form, and any equipment that the new form can&#8217;t wear must either fall to the ground or merge with it. Equipment that merges with the form has no effect until you leave the form. </text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Druid Circle</name>
				<text>At 2nd level, you choose to identify with a circle of druids: the Circle of the Land or the Circle of the Moon, both detailed at the end of the class description. Your choice grants you features at 2nd level and again at 6th, 10th, and 14th level.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Timeless Body</name>
				<text>Starting at 18th level, the primal magic that you wield causes you to age more slowly. For every 10 years that pass, your body ages only 1 year.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Beast Spells</name>
				<text>Beginning at 18th level, you can cast many of your druid spells in any shape you assume using Wild Shape. You can perform the somatic and verbal components of a druid spell while in a beast shape, but you aren&#8217;t able to provide material components.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Archdruid</name>
				<text>At 20th level, you can use your Wild Shape an unlimited number of times.</text>
				<text>	Additionally, you can ignore the verbal and somatic components of your druid spells, as well as any material components that lack a cost and aren&#8217;t consumed by a spell. You gain this benefit in both your normal shape and your beast shape from Wild Shape.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

</subclass>

	
	<subclass>
	<name>fighter core</name>
	<class>Fighter</class>
	<hd>10</hd>
	<saves>Strength, Constitution</saves>
	<proficiency>Acrobatics, Animal Handling, Athletics, History, Insight, Intimidation, Perception, Survival</proficiency>
	<spellAbility>Intelligence</spellAbility>
	<numSkills>2</numSkills>
		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Starting Fighter</name>
				<text>As a 1st-level Fighter, you begin play with 10+your Constitution modifier hit points.</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>You are proficient with the following items, in addition to any proficiencies provided by your race or background.</text>
				<text>&#8226; Armor: light armor, medium armor, heavy armor, shields</text>
				<text>&#8226; Weapons: simple weapons, martial weapons</text>
				<text>&#8226; Tools: none</text>
				<text>&#8226; Skills: Choose two skills from Acrobatics, Animal Handling, Athletics, History, Insight, Intimidation, Perception, and Survival</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>You begin play with the following equipment, in addition to any equipment provided by your background.</text>
				<text>&#8226; (a) chain mail or (b) leather, longbow, and 20 arrows</text>
				<text>&#8226; (a) a martial weapon and a shield or (b) two martial weapons</text>
				<text>&#8226; (a) a light crossbow and 20 bolts or (b) two handaxes</text>
				<text>&#8226; (a) a dungeoneer's pack or (b) an explorer's pack </text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>Alternatively, you may start with 5d4x10 gp and choose your own equipment.</text>
				<text> </text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<multiclass>
			
				<name>Multiclass Fighter</name>
				<text>To multiclass as a Fighter, you must meet the following prerequisites:</text>
				<text>&#8226; Strength 13 or Dexterity 13</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>You gain the following proficiencies:</text>
				<text>&#8226; light armor, medium armor, shields, simple weapons, martial weapons</text>
				<text> </text>
			
		</multiclass>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Second Wind</name>
				<text>You have a limited well of stamina that you can draw on to protect yourself from harm. On your turn, you can use a bonus action to regain hit points equal to 1d10 + your fighter level.</text>
				<text>	Once you use this feature, you must finish a short or long rest before you can use it again.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Fighting Style</name>
				<text>You adopt a particular style of fighting as your specialty. Choose one of the following options: Archery, Defense, Dueling, Great Weapon Fighting, Mariner, Protection, or Two-Weapon Fighting. You can&#8217;t take a Fighting Style option more than once, even if you later get to choose again.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		

		
			
				<text>Fighting Style: Archery</text>
				<text>You gain a +2 bonus to attack rolls you make with ranged weapons.</text>
				<text>	</text>		
			
				<text>Fighting Style: Defense</text>
				<text>While you are wearing armor, you gain a +1 bonus to AC.</text>
				<text>	</text>		
			
				<text>Fighting Style: Dueling</text>
				<text>When you are wielding a melee weapon in one hand and no other weapons, you gain a +2 bonus to damage rolls with that weapon.</text>
				<text>	</text>		
			
				<text>Fighting Style: Great Weapon Fighting</text>
				<text>When you roll a 1 or 2 on a damage die for an attack you make with a melee weapon that you are wielding with two hands, you can reroll the die and must use the new roll, even if the new roll is a 1 or a 2. The weapon must have the two-handed or versatile property for you to gain this benefit.</text>
				<text>	</text>		
			
				<text>Fighting Style: Protection</text>
				<text>When a creature you can see attacks a target other than you that is within 5 feet of you, you can use your reaction to impose disadvantage on the attack roll. You must be wielding a shield.</text>
				<text>	</text>		
			
				<text>Fighting Style: Two-Weapon Fighting</text>
				<text>When you engage in two-weapon fighting, you can add your ability modifier to the damage of the second attack.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Action Surge</name>
				<text>Starting at 2nd level, you can push yourself beyond your normal limits for a moment. On your turn, you can take one additional action on top of your regular action and a possible bonus action.</text>
				<text>	Once you use this feature, you must finish a short or long rest before you can use it again. Starting at 17th level, you can use it twice before a rest, but only once on the same turn.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Martial Archetype</name>
				<text>At 3rd level, you choose an archetype that you strive to emulate in your combat styles and techniques. Choose Champion, Battle Master, or Eldritch Knight, all detailed at the end of the class description. The archetype you choose grants you features at 3rd level and again at 7th, 10th, 15th, and 18th level.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Extra Attack</name>
				<text>Beginning at 5th level, you can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</text>
				<text>	The number of attacks increases to three when you reach 11th level in this class and to four when you reach 20th level in this class.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Indomitable</name>
				<text>Beginning at 9th level, you can reroll a saving throw that you fail. If you do so, you must use the new roll, and you can&#8217;t use this feature again until you finish a long rest. You can use this feature twice between long rests starting at 13th level and three times between long rests starting at 17th level.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>
	
	</subclass>

		
<subclass>
	<name>monk core</name>
	<class>Monk</class>
	<hd>8</hd>
	<saves>Strength, Dexterity</saves>
	<proficiency>Acrobatics, Athletics, History, Insight, Religion, Stealth</proficiency>
	<spellAbility></spellAbility>
	<numSkills>2</numSkills>
		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Starting Monk</name>
				<text>As a 1st-level Monk, you begin play with 8+your Constitution modifier hit points.</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>You are proficient with the following items, in addition to any proficiencies provided by your race or background.</text>
				<text>&#8226; Armor: none</text>
				<text>&#8226; Weapons: simple weapons, shortswords</text>
				<text>&#8226; Tools: any one type of artisan's tools or any one musical instrument of your choice</text>
				<text>&#8226; Skills: Choose two from Acrobatics, Athletics, History, Insight, Religion, and Stealth</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>You begin play with the following equipment, in addition to any equipment provided by your background.</text>
				<text>&#8226; (a) a shortsword or (b) any simple weapon</text>
				<text>&#8226; (a) a dungeoneer's pack or (b) an explorer's pack</text>
				<text>&#8226; 10 darts</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>Alternatively, you may start with 5d4 gp and choose your own equipment.</text>
				<text> </text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<multiclass>
			
				<name>Multiclass Monk</name>
				<text>To multiclass as a Monk, you must meet the following prerequisites:</text>
				<text>&#8226; Dexterity 13 and Wisdom 13</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>You gain the following proficiencies:</text>
				<text>&#8226; simple weapons, shortswords</text>
				<text> </text>
			
		</multiclass>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Unarmored Defense</name>
				<text>Beginning at 1st level, while you are wearing no armor and not wielding a shield, your AC equals 10 + your Dexterity modifier + your Wisdom modifier.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Martial Arts</name>
				<text>At 1st level, your practice of martial arts gives you mastery of combat styles that use unarmed strikes and monk weapons, which are shortswords and any simple melee weapons that don&#8217;t have the two-handed or heavy property.</text>
				<text>	You gain the following benefits while you are unarmed or wielding only monk weapons and you aren&#8217;t wearing armor or wielding a shield.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>&#8226; You can use Dexterity instead of Strength for the attack and damage rolls of your unarmed strikes and monk weapons.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>&#8226; You can roll a d4 in place of the normal damage of your unarmed strike or monk weapon. This die changes as you gain monk levels &#8212; to a d6 at 5th level, a d8 at 11th level, and a d10 at 17th level. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>&#8226; When you use the Attack action with an unarmed strike or a monk weapon on your turn, you can make one unarmed strike as a bonus action. For example, if you take the Attack action and attack with a quarterstaff, you can also make an unarmed strike as a bonus action, assuming you haven&#8217;t already taken a bonus action this turn.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>	Certain monasteries use specialized forms of the monk weapons. For example, you might use a club that is two lengths of wood connected by a short chain (called a nunchaku) or a sickle with a shorter, straighter blade (called a kama). Whatever name you use for a monk weapon, you can use the game statistics provided for the weapon in chapter 5.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<text>Ki</text>
				<text>Starting at 2nd level, your training allows you to harness the mystic energy of ki. Your access to this energy is represented by a number of ki points. You have a number of Ki points equal to your monk level.</text>
				<text>	You can spend these points to fuel various ki features.</text>
				<text>	You start knowing three such features: Flurry of Blows, Patient Defense, and Step of the Wind. You learn more ki features as you gain levels in this class. When you spend a ki point, it is unavailable until you finish a short or long rest, at the end of which you draw all of your expended ki back into yourself. You must spend at least 30 minutes of the rest meditating to regain your ki points.</text>
				<text>	Some of your ki features require your target to make a saving throw to resist the feature&#8217;s effects. The saving throw DC is calculated as follows:</text>
				<text>	Ki save DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier</text>
				<text>	</text>		
			
				<text>Flurry of Blows:</text>
				<text>Immediately after you take the Attack action on your turn, you can spend 1 ki point to make two unarmed strikes as a bonus action.</text>
				<text>	</text>		
			
				<text>Patient Defense:</text>
				<text>You can spend 1 ki point to take the Dodge action as a bonus action on your turn.</text>
				<text>	</text>		
			
				<text>Step of the Wind</text>
				<text>You can spend 1 ki point to take the Disengage or Dash action as a bonus action on your turn, and your jump distance is doubled for the turn.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Unarmored Movement:</name>
				<text>Starting at 2nd level, your speed increases by 10 feet while you are not wearing armor or wielding a shield. This bonus increases when you reach certain monk levels &#8212; to 15 ft. at 6th level, to 20 ft. at 10th level, to 25 ft. at 14th level, and to 30 ft. at 18th level.</text>
				<text>	At 9th level, you gain the ability to move along vertical surfaces and across liquids on your turn without falling during the move.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Deflect Missiles:</name>
				<text>Starting at 3rd level, you can use your reaction to deflect or catch the missile when you are hit by a ranged weapon attack. When you do so, the damage you take from the attack is reduced by 1d10 + your Dexterity modifier + your monk level.</text>
				<text>	If you reduce the damage to 0, you can catch the missile if it is small enough for you to hold in one hand and you have at least one hand free. If you catch a missile in this way, you can spend 1 ki point to make a ranged attack with the weapon or piece of ammunition you just caught, as part of the same reaction. You make this attack with proficiency, regardless of your weapon proficiencies, and the missile counts as a monk weapon for the attack, which has a normal range of 20 feet and a long range of 60 feet.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Monastic Tradition</name>
				<text>When you reach 3rd level, you commit yourself to a monastic tradition: the Way of the Open Hand, the Way of Shadow, or the Way of the Four Elements, all detailed at the end of the class description. Your tradition grants you features at 3rd level and again at 6th, 11th, and 17th level.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Slow Fall</name>
				<text>Beginning at 4th level, you can use your reaction when you fall to reduce any falling damage you take by an amount equal to five times your monk level.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Extra Attack</name>
				<text>Beginning at 5th level, you can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Stunning Strike</name>
				<text>Starting at 5th level, you can interfere with the flow of ki in an opponent&#8217;s body. When you hit another creature with a melee weapon attack, you can spend 1 ki point to attempt a stunning strike. The target must succeed on a Constitution saving throw or be stunned until the end of your next turn.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Stunned:</text>
				<text>&#8226; A stunned creature is incapacitated, meaning it can't take actions or reactions, can't move, and can speak only falteringly.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>&#8226; The creature automatically fails Strength and Dexterity saving throws.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>&#8226; Attack rolls against the creature have advantage.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Ki-Empowered Strikes</name>
				<text>Starting at 6th level, your unarmed strikes count as magical for the purpose of overcoming resistance and immunity to nonmagical attacks and damage.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Evasion</name>
				<text>At 7th level, your instinctive agility lets you dodge out of the way of certain area effects, such as a blue dragon&#8217;s lightning breath or a fireball spell. When you are subjected to an effect that allows you to make a Dexterity saving throw to take only half damage, you instead take no damage if you succeed on the saving throw, and only half damage if you fail.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Stillness of Mind</name>
				<text>Starting at 7th level, you can use your action to end one effect on yourself that is causing you to be charmed or frightened.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Purity of Body</name>
				<text>At 10th level, your mastery of the ki flowing through you makes you immune to disease and poison.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>


		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Tongue of the Sun and Moon</name>
				<text>Starting at 13th level, you learn to touch the ki of other minds so that you understand all spoken languages. Moreover, any creature that can understand a language can understand what you say.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Diamond Soul</name>
				<text>Beginning at 14th level, your mastery of ki grants you proficiency in all saving throws.</text>
				<text>	Additionally, whenever you make a saving throw and fail, you can spend 1 ki point to reroll it and take the second result.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Timeless Body</name>
				<text>At 15th level, your ki sustains you so that you suffer none of the frailty of old age, and you can&#8217;t be aged magically. You can still die of old age, however. In addition, you no longer need food or water.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

	
		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Empty Body</name>
				<text>Beginning at 18th level, you can use your action to spend 4 ki points to become invisible for 1 minute. During that time, you also have resistance to all damage but force damage.</text>
				<text>	Additionally, you can spend 8 ki points to cast the astral projection spell, without needing material components. When you do so, you can&#8217;t take any other creatures with you.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Invisible:</text>
				<text>&#8226; An invisible creature is impossible to see without the aid of magic or a special sense. For the purpose of hiding, the creature is heavily obscured. The creature's location can be detected by any noise it makes or any tracks it leaves.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>&#8226; Attack rolls against the creature have disadvantage, and the creature's attack rolls have advantage.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Perfect Self</name>
				<text>At 20th level, when you roll for initiative and have no ki points remaining, you regain 4 ki points.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

	</subclass>

	
<subclass>
	<name>mystic core</name>
	<class>Mystic</class>
	<hd>8</hd>
	<saves>Intelligence, Wisdom</saves>
	<proficiency>Arcana, History, Insight, Medicine, Nature, Perception, Religion</proficiency>
	<spellAbility>Intelligence</spellAbility>
	<numSkills>2</numSkills>
		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Starting Mystic</name>
				<text>As a 1st-level Mystic, you begin play with 8+your Constitution modifier hit points.</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>You are proficient with the following items, in addition to any proficiencies provided by your race or background.</text>
				<text>&#8226; Armor: light armor</text>
				<text>&#8226; Weapons: simple weapons</text>
				<text>&#8226; Tools: none</text>
				<text>&#8226; Skills: Choose two skills from Arcana, History, Insight, Medicine, Nature, Perception, and Religion</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>You begin play with the following equipment, in addition to any equipment provided by your background.</text>
				<text>&#8226; (a) a spear or (b) a mace </text>
				<text>&#8226; (a) leather armor or (b) studded leather armor </text>
				<text>&#8226; (a) a light crossbow and 20 bolts or (b) any simple weapon </text>
				<text>&#8226; (a) a scholar&#8217;s pack or (b) an explorer&#8217;s pack</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>Alternatively, you may start with 5d4x10 gp and choose your own equipment.</text>
				<text> </text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Psionics</name>
				<text>As a student of psionics, you can master and use psionic talents and disciplines. Psionics is a special form of magic use, distinct from spellcasting. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Psionic Talents: </text>
				<text>	A psionic talent is a minor psionic effect you have mastered. At 1st level, you know one psionic talent of your choice. You learn additional talents of your choice at higher levels. You learn an additional talent at 3rd, 10th, and 17th level. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Psionic Disciplines: </text>
				<text>	A psionic discipline is a rigid set of mental exercises that allows a mystic to manifest psionic power. A mystic masters only a few disciplines at a time. </text>
				<text>	At 1st level, you know one psionic discipline of your choice. You learn an additional discipline of your choice at 3rd, 5th, 7th, 9th, 12th, 15th, and 18th level.</text>
				<text>	In addition, whenever you gain a level in this class, you can replace one discipline you know with a different one of your choice. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Psi Points: </text>
				<text>	You have an internal reservoir of energy that can be devoted to psionic disciplines you know. This energy is represented by psi points. Each psionic discipline describes effects you can create with it by spending a certain number of psi points. A psionic talent requires no psi points. </text>
				<text>	The number of psi points you have is based on your mystic level: 4 points at 1st level, 6 at 2nd, 14 at 3rd, 17 at 4th, 27 at 5th, 32 at 6th, 38 at 7th, 44 at 8th, 57 at 9th, 64 at 10th, and 71 at 18th.. The number shown for your level is your psi point maximum. Your psi point total returns to its maximum when you finish a long rest. The number of psi points you have can&#8217;t go below 0 or over your maximum. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Psi Limit: </text>
				<text>	Though you have access to a potent amount of psionic energy, it takes training and practice to channel that energy. There is a limit on the number of psi points you can spend to activate a psionic discipline. The limit is based on your mystic level; at 1st level, your psi limit is 2, and it increases to 3 at 3rd, 5 at 5th, 6 at 7th, and 7 at 9th.  For example, as a 3rd-level mystic, you can spend no more than 3 psi points on a discipline each time you use it, no matter how many psi points you have. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Psychic Focus: </text>
				<text>	You can focus psionic energy on one of your psionic disciplines to draw ongoing benefits from it. As a bonus action, you can choose one of your psionic disciplines and gain its psychic focus benefit, which is detailed in that discipline&#8217;s description. The benefit lasts until you are incapacitated or until you use another bonus action to choose a different focus benefit. </text>
				<text>	You can have only one psychic focus benefit at a time, and using the psychic focus of one discipline doesn&#8217;t limit your ability to use other disciplines. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Psionic Ability: </text>
				<text>	Intelligence is your psionic ability for your psionic disciplines. You use your Intelligence modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a psionic discipline or when making an attack roll with one. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Discipline save DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Discipline attack modifier = your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Mystic Order</name>
				<text>At 1st level, you choose a Mystic Order: the Order of the Avatar, the Order of the Awakened, the Order of the Immortal, the Order of the Nomad, the Order of the Soul Knife, or the Order of the Wu Jen, each of which is detailed at the end of the class description. Each order specializes in a specific approach to psionics. </text>
				<text>	Your order gives you features when you choose it at 1st level and additional features at 3rd, 6th, and 14th level.</text>
				<text>	</text>
				<text>Source: Unearthed Arcana: The Mystic Class, p. 4</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Mystical Recovery</name>
				<text>Starting at 2nd level, you can draw vigor from the psi energy you use to power your psionic disciplines. </text>
				<text>	Immediately after you spend psi points on a psionic discipline, you can take a bonus action to regain hit points equal to the number of psi points you spent.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Telepathy</name>
				<text>At 2nd level, your mind awakens to the ability to communicate via telepathy. You can telepathically speak to any creature you can see within 120 feet of you in this manner. You don&#8217;t need to share a language with the creature for it to understand your telepathic messages, but the creature must be able to understand at least one language or be telepathic itself.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>


		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Strength of Mind</name>
				<text>Even the simplest psionic technique requires a deep understanding of how psionic energy can augment mind and body. This understanding allows you to alter your defenses to better deal with threats.</text>
				<text>	Starting at 4th level, you can replace your proficiency in Wisdom saving throws whenever you finish a short or long rest. To do so, choose Strength, Dexterity, Constitution, or Charisma. You gain proficiency in saves using that ability, instead of Wisdom. This change lasts until you finish your next short or long rest.
</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>


		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Potent Psionics</name>
				<text>At 8th level, you gain the ability to infuse your weapon attacks with psychic energy. Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with a weapon, you can deal an extra 1d8 psychic damage to that target. When you reach 14th level, this extra damage increases to 2d8.</text>
				<text>	In addition, you add your Intelligence modifier to any damage roll you make for a psionic talent.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Consumptive Power</name>
				<text>At 10th level, you gain the ability to sacrifice your physical durability in exchange for psionic power. When activating a psionic discipline, you can pay its psi point cost with your hit points, instead of using any psi points. Your current hit points and hit point maximum are both reduced by the number of hit points you spend. This reduction can&#8217;t be lessened in any way, and the reduction to your hit point maximum lasts until you finish a long rest.</text>
				<text>	Once you use this feature, you can&#8217;t use it again until you finish a long rest.
</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Psionic Mastery</name>
				<text>Beginning at 11th level, your mastery of psionic energy allows you to push your mind beyond its normal limits. As an action, you gain 9 special psi points that you can spend only on disciplines that require an action or a bonus action to use. You can use all 9 points on one discipline, or you can spread them across multiple disciplines. You can&#8217;t also spend your normal psi points on these disciplines; you can spend only the special points gained from this feature. When you finish a long rest, you lose any of these special points that you haven&#8217;t spent.</text>
				<text>	If more than one of the disciplines you activate with these points require concentration, you can concentrate on all of them. Activating one of them ends any effect you were already concentrating on, and if you begin concentrating on an effect that doesn&#8217;t use these special points, the disciplines end that you&#8217;re concentrating on.</text>
				<text>	At 15th level, the pool of psi points you gain from this feature increases to 11.</text>
				<text>	You have one use of this feature, and you regain any expended use of it with a long rest. You gain one additional use of this feature at 13th, 15th, and 17th level.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>


		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Psionic Body</name>
				<text>At 20th level, your mastery of psionic power causes your mind to transcend the body. Your physical form is infused with psionic energy. You gain the following benefits:</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>&#8226; You gain resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage.</text>
				<text>&#8226; You no longer age.</text>
				<text>&#8226; You are immune to disease, poison damage, and the poisoned condition.</text>
				<text>&#8226; If you die, roll a d20. On a 10 or higher, you discorporate with 0 hit points, instead of dying, and you fall unconscious. You and your gear disappear. You appear at a spot of your choice 1d3 days later on the plane of existence where you died, having gained the benefits of one long rest.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

</subclass>


<subclass>
	<name>paladin core</name>
	<class>Paladin</class>
	<hd>10</hd>
	<saves>Wisdom, Charisma</saves>
	<proficiency> Athletics, Insight, Intimidation, Medicine, Persuasion, Religion</proficiency>
	<spellAbility>Charisma</spellAbility>
	<numSkills>2</numSkills>
		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Starting Paladin</name>
				<text>As a 1st-level Paladin, you begin play with 10+your Constitution modifier hit points.</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>You are proficient with the following items, in addition to any proficiencies provided by your race or background.</text>
				<text>&#8226; Armor: light armor, medium armor, heavy armor, shields</text>
				<text>&#8226; Weapons: simple weapons, martial weapons</text>
				<text>&#8226; Tools: none</text>
				<text>&#8226; Skills: Choose two from Athletics, Insight, Intimidation, Medicine, Persuasion, and Religion</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>You begin play with the following equipment, in addition to any equipment provided by your background.</text>
				<text>&#8226; (a) a martial weapon and a shield or (b) two martial weapons</text>
				<text>&#8226; (a) five javelins or (b) any simple melee weapon</text>
				<text>&#8226; (a) a priest's pack or (b) an explorer's pack</text>
				<text>&#8226; Chain mail and a holy symbol </text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>Alternatively, you may start with 5d4x10 gp and choose your own equipment.</text>
				<text> </text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<multiclass>
			
				<name>Multiclass Paladin</name>
				<text>To multiclass as a Paladin, you must meet the following prerequisites:</text>
				<text>&#8226; Strength 13 and Charisma 13</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>You gain the following proficiencies:</text>
				<text>&#8226; light armor, medium armor, shields, simple weapons, martial weapons</text>
				<text> </text>
			
		</multiclass>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Divine Sense</name>
				<text>The presence of strong evil registers on your senses like a noxious odor, and powerful good rings like heavenly music in your ears. As an action, you can open your awareness to detect such forces. Until the end of your next turn, you know the location of any celestial, fiend, or undead within 60 feet of you that is not behind total cover. You know the type (celestial, fiend, or undead) of any being whose presence you sense, but not its identity (the vampire Count Strahd von Zarovich, for instance). Within the same radius, you also detect the presence of any place or object that has been consecrated or desecrated, as with the hallow spell.</text>
				<text>	You can use this feature a number of times equal to 1 + your Charisma modifier. When you finish a long rest, you regain all expended uses.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Lay on Hands</name>
				<text>Your blessed touch can heal wounds. You have a pool of healing power that replenishes when you take a long rest. With that pool, you can restore a total number of hit points equal to your paladin level x 5.</text>
				<text>	As an action, you can touch a creature and draw power from the pool to restore a number of hit points to that creature, up to the maximum amount remaining in your pool.</text>
				<text>	Alternatively, you can expend 5 hit points from your pool of healing to cure the target of one disease or neutralize one poison affecting it. You can cure multiple diseases and neutralize multiple poisons with a single use of Lay on Hands, expending hit points separately for each one.</text>
				<text>	This feature has no effect on undead and constructs.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Spellcasting</name>
				<text>By 2nd level, you have learned to draw on divine magic through meditation and prayer to cast spells as a cleric does. See chapter 10 for the general rules of spellcasting and chapter 11 for the paladin spell list. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Preparing and Casting Spells:</text>
				<text>	The Paladin table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your spells. To cast one of your paladin spells of 1st level or higher, you must expend a slot of the spell&#8217;s level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.</text>
				<text>	You prepare the list of paladin spells that are available for you to cast, choosing from the paladin spell list. When you do so, choose a number of paladin spells equal to your Charisma modifier+half your paladin level, rounded down (minimum of one spell). The spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots.</text>
				<text>	For example, if you are a 5th-level paladin, you have four 1st-level and two 2nd-level spell slots. With a Charisma of 14, your list of prepared spells can include four spells of 1st or 2nd level, in any combination. If you prepare the 1st-level spell cure wounds, you can cast it using a 1st-level or a 2nd-level slot. Casting the spell doesn&#8217;t remove it from your list of prepared spells.</text>
				<text>	You can change your list of prepared spells when you finish a long rest. Preparing a new list of paladin spells requires time spent in prayer and meditation: at least 1 minute per spell level for each spell on your list. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Spellcasting Ability:</text>
				<text>	Charisma is your spellcasting ability for your paladin spells, since their power derives from the strength of your convictions. You use your Charisma whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Charisma modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a paladin spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.</text>
				<text>	Spell save DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier</text>
				<text>	Spell attack modifier = your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Spellcasting Focus:</text>
				<text>	You can use a holy symbol (found in chapter 5) as a spellcasting focus for your paladin spells.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Divine Smite</name>
				<text>Starting at 2nd level, when you hit a creature with a melee weapon attack, you can expend one spell slot to deal radiant damage to the target, in addition to the weapon&#8217;s damage. The extra damage is 2d8 for a 1st-level spell slot, plus 1d8 for each spell level higher than 1st, to a maximum of 5d8. The damage increases by 1d8 if the target is an undead or a fiend.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Fighting Style</name>
				<text>At 2nd level, you adopt a style of fighting as your specialty. Choose one of the following options: Defense, Dueling, Great Weapon Fighting, Mariner, or Protection. You can&#8217;t take a Fighting Style option more than once, even if you later get to choose again.</text>
				<text>	</text>		
			
				<text>Fighting Style: Defense</text>
				<text>While you are wearing armor, you gain a +1 bonus to AC.</text>
				<text>	</text>		
			
				<text>Fighting Style: Dueling</text>
				<text>When you are wielding a melee weapon in one hand and no other weapons, you gain a +2 bonus to damage rolls with that weapon.</text>
				<text>	</text>	
			
				<text>Fighting Style: Great Weapon Fighting</text>
				<text>When you roll a 1 or 2 on a damage die for an attack you make with a melee weapon that you are wielding with two hands, you can reroll the die and must use the new roll, even if the new roll is a 1 or a 2. The weapon must have the two-handed or versatile property for you to gain this benefit.</text>
				<text>	</text>		
			
				<text>Fighting Style: Protection</text>
				<text>When a creature you can see attacks a target other than you that is within 5 feet of you, you can use your reaction to impose disadvantage on the attack roll. You must be wielding a shield.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Divine Health</name>
				<text>By 3rd level, the divine magic flowing through you makes you immune to disease.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Sacred Oath</name>
				<text>When you reach 3rd level, you swear the oath that binds you as a paladin forever. Up to this time you have been in a preparatory stage, committed to the path but not yet sworn to it. Now you choose the Oath of Devotion, the Oath of the Ancients, or the Oath of Vengeance, all detailed at the end of the class description.</text>
				<text>	Your choice grants you features at 3rd level and again at 7th, 15th, and 20th level. Those features include oath spells and the Channel Divinity feature. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Oath Spells:</text>
				<text>	Each oath has a list of associated spells. You gain access to these spells at the levels specified in the oath description. Once you gain access to an oath spell, you always have it prepared. Oath spells don&#8217;t count against the number of spells you can prepare each day.</text>
				<text>	If you gain an oath spell that doesn&#8217;t appear on the paladin spell list, the spell is nonetheless a paladin spell for you.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Channel Divinity</name>
				<text>Your oath allows you to channel divine energy to fuel magical effects. Each Channel Divinity option provided by your oath explains how to use it.</text>
				<text>	When you use your Channel Divinity, you choose which option to use. You must then finish a short or long rest to use your Channel Divinity again.</text>
				<text>	Some Channel Divinity effects require saving throws. When you use such an effect from this class, the DC equals your paladin spell save DC.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>


		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Extra Attack</name>
				<text>Beginning at 5th level, you can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Aura of Protection</name>
				<text>Starting at 6th level, whenever you or a friendly creature within 10 feet of you must make a saving throw, the creature gains a bonus to the saving throw equal to your Charisma modifier (with a minimum bonus of +1). You must be conscious to grant this bonus.</text>
				<text>	At 18th level, the range of this aura increases to 30 feet.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>


		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Aura of Courage</name>
				<text>Starting at 10th level, you and friendly creatures within 10 feet of you can&#8217;t be frightened while you are conscious.</text>
				<text>	At 18th level, the range of this aura increases to 30 feet.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Improved Divine Smite</name>
				<text>By 11th level, you are so suffused with righteous might that all your melee weapon strikes carry divine power with them. Whenever you hit a creature with a melee weapon, the creature takes an extra 1d8 radiant damage. If you also use your Divine Smite with an attack, you add this damage to the extra damage of your Divine Smite.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>


		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Cleansing Touch</name>
				<text>Beginning at 14th level, you can use your action to end one spell on yourself or on one willing creature that you touch.</text>
				<text>	You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Charisma modifier (a minimum of once). You regain expended uses when you finish a long rest.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>


</subclass>


<subclass>
	<name>ranger core</name>
	<class>Ranger</class>
	<hd>10</hd>
	<saves>Strength, Dexterity</saves>
	<proficiency>Animal Handling, Athletics, Insight, Investigation, Nature, Perception, Stealth, Survival</proficiency>
	<spellAbility>Wisdom</spellAbility>
	<numSkills>3</numSkills>
		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Starting Ranger</name>
				<text>As a 1st-level Ranger, you begin play with 10+your Constitution modifier hit points.</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>You are proficient with the following items, in addition to any proficiencies provided by your race or background.</text>
				<text>&#8226; Armor: light armor, medium armor, shields</text>
				<text>&#8226; Weapons: simple weapons, martial weapons</text>
				<text>&#8226; Tools: none</text>
				<text>&#8226; Skills: Choose three from Animal Handling, Athletics, Insight, Investigation, Nature, Perception, Stealth, and Survival</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>You begin play with the following equipment, in addition to any equipment provided by your background.</text>
				<text>&#8226; (a) scale mail or (b) leather armor</text>
				<text>&#8226; (a) two shortswords or (b) two simple melee weapons</text>
				<text>&#8226; (a) a dungeoneer's pack or (b) an explorer's pack</text>
				<text>&#8226; A longbow and a quiver of 20 arrows</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>Alternatively, you may start with 5d4x10 gp and choose your own equipment.</text>
				<text> </text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<multiclass>
			
				<name>Multiclass Ranger</name>
				<text>To multiclass as a Ranger, you must meet the following prerequisites:</text>
				<text>&#8226; Dexterity 13 and Wisdom 13</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>You gain the following proficiencies:</text>
				<text>&#8226; light armor, medium armor, shields, simple weapons, martial weapons; choose one skill from Animal Handling, Athletics, Insight, Investigation, Nature, Perception, Stealth, and Survival</text>
				<text> </text>
			
		</multiclass>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Favored Enemy</name>
				<text>Beginning at 1st level, you have significant experience studying, tracking, hunting, and even talking to a certain type of enemy.</text>
				<text>	Choose a type of favored enemy: aberrations, beasts, celestials, constructs, dragons, elementals, fey, fiends, giants, monstrosities, oozes, plants, or undead. Alternatively, you can select two races of humanoid (such as gnolls and orcs) as favored enemies.</text>
				<text>	You have advantage on Wisdom (Survival) checks to track your favored enemies, as well as on Intelligence checks to recall information about them.</text>
				<text>	When you gain this feature, you also learn one language of your choice that is spoken by your favored enemies, if they speak one at all.</text>
				<text>	You choose one additional favored enemy, as well as an associated language, at 6th and 14th level. As you gain levels, your choices should reflect the types of monsters you have encountered on your adventures.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Natural Explorer</name>
				<text>You are particularly familiar with one type of natural environment and are adept at traveling and surviving in such regions. Choose one type of favored terrain: arctic, coast, desert, forest, grassland, mountain, swamp, or the Underdark. When you make an Intelligence or Wisdom check related to your favored terrain, your proficiency bonus is doubled if you are using a skill that you&#8217;re proficient in.</text>
				<text>	While traveling for an hour or more in your favored terrain, you gain the following benefits.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>&#8226; Difficult terrain doesn&#8217;t slow your group&#8217;s travel.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>&#8226; Your group can&#8217;t become lost except by magical means.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>&#8226; Even when you are engaged in another activity while traveling (such as foraging, navigating, or tracking), you remain alert to danger.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>&#8226; If you are traveling alone, you can move stealthily at a normal pace.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>&#8226; When you forage, you find twice as much food as you normally would.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>&#8226; While tracking other creatures, you also learn their exact number, their sizes, and how long ago they passed through the area.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>	You choose additional favored terrain types at 6th and 10th level.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Spellcasting</name>
				<text>By the time you reach 2nd level, you have learned to use the magical essence of nature to cast spells, much as a druid does. See chapter 10 for the general rules of spellcasting and chapter 11 for the ranger spell list. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Spell Slots:</text>
				<text>	The Ranger table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your spells of 1st level and higher. To cast one of these spells, you must expend a slot of the spell&#8217;s level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.</text>
				<text>	For example, if you know the 1st-level spell animal friendship and have a 1st-level and a 2nd-level spell slot available, you can cast animal friendship using either slot. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Spells Known of 1st Level and Higher:</text>
				<text>	You know two 1st-level spells of your choice from the ranger spell list.</text>
				<text>	You learn an additional ranger spell of your choice at each odd numbered level thereafter. Each of these spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots. For instance, when you reach 5th level in this class, you can learn one new spell of 1st or 2nd level.</text>
				<text>	Additionally, when you gain a level in this class, you can choose one of the ranger spells you know and replace it with another spell from the ranger spell list, which also must be of a level for which you have spell slots. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Spellcasting Ability:</text>
				<text>	Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for your ranger spells, since your magic draws on your attunement to nature. You use your Wisdom whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Wisdom modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a ranger spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.</text>
				<text>	Spell save DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier</text>
				<text>	Spell attack modifier = your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Fighting Style</name>
				<text>At 2nd level, you adopt a particular style of fighting as your specialty. Choose one of the following options: Archery, Defense, Dueling, Mariner, or Two-Weapon Fighting. You can&#8217;t take a Fighting Style option more than once, even if you later get to choose again.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		

		
			
				<text>Fighting Style: Archery</text>
				<text>You gain a +2 bonus to attack rolls you make with ranged weapons.</text>
				<text>	</text>
		
			
		

		
			
				<text>Fighting Style: Defense</text>
				<text>While you are wearing armor, you gain a +1 bonus to AC.</text>
				<text>	</text>
		
			
		

		
			
				<text>Fighting Style: Dueling</text>
				<text>When you are wielding a melee weapon in one hand and no other weapons, you gain a +2 bonus to damage rolls with that weapon.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		

		
			
				<text>Fighting Style: Two-Weapon Fighting</text>
				<text>When you engage in two-weapon fighting, you can add your ability modifier to the damage of the second attack.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Primeval Awareness</name>
				<text>Beginning at 3rd level, you can use your action and expend one ranger spell slot to focus your awareness on the region around you. For 1 minute per level of the spell slot you expend, you can sense whether the following types of creatures are present within 1 mile of you (or within up to 6 miles if you are in your favored terrain): aberrations, celestials, dragons, elementals, fey, fiends, and undead. This feature doesn&#8217;t reveal the creatures&#8217; location or number.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Ranger Archetype</name>
				<text>At 3rd level, you choose an archetype that you strive to emulate: Hunter or Beast Master, both detailed at the end of the class description. Your choice grants you features at 3rd level and again at 7th, 11th, and 15th level.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>


		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Extra Attack</name>
				<text>Beginning at 5th level, you can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>


		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Land's Stride</name>
				<text>Starting at 8th level, moving through nonmagical difficult terrain costs you no extra movement. You can also pass through nonmagical plants without being slowed by them and without taking damage from them if they have thorns, spines, or a similar hazard.</text>
				<text>	In addition, you have advantage on saving throws against plants that are magically created or manipulated to impede movement, such those created by the entangle spell.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		
		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Hide in Plain Sight</name>
				<text>Starting at 10th level, you can spend 1 minute creating camouflage for yourself. You must have access to fresh mud, dirt, plants, soot, and other naturally occurring materials with which to create your camouflage.</text>
				<text>	Once you are camouflaged in this way, you can try to hide by pressing yourself up against a solid surface, such as a tree or wall, that is at least as tall and wide as you are. You gain a +10 bonus to Dexterity (Stealth) checks as long as you remain there without moving or taking actions. Once you move or take an action or a reaction, you must camouflage yourself again to gain this benefit.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>


		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Vanish</name>
				<text>Starting at 14th level, you can use the Hide action as a bonus action on your turn. Also, you can&#8217;t be tracked by nonmagical means, unless you choose to leave a trail.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>


		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Feral Senses</name>
				<text>At 18th level, you gain preternatural senses that help you fight creatures you can&#8217;t see. When you attack a creature you can&#8217;t see, your inability to see it doesn&#8217;t impose disadvantage on your attack rolls against it.</text>
				<text>	You are also aware of the location of any invisible creature within 30 feet of you, provided that the creature isn&#8217;t hidden from you and you aren&#8217;t blinded or deafened.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Foe Slayer</name>
				<text>At 20th level, you become an unparalleled hunter of your enemies. Once on each of your turns, you can add your Wisdom modifier to the attack roll or the damage roll of an attack you make against one of your favored enemies. You can choose to use this feature before or after the roll, but before any effects of the roll are applied.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

</subclass>


<subclass>
	<name>rogue core</name>
	<class>Rogue</class>
	<hd>8</hd>
	<saves>Dexterity, Intelligence</saves>
	<proficiency>Acrobatics, Athletics, Deception, Insight, Intimidation, Investigation, Perception, Performance. Persuasion, Sleight of Hand, Stealth</proficiency>
	<spellAbility>Intelligence</spellAbility>
	<numSkills>4</numSkills>
		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Starting Rogue</name>
				<text>As a 1st-level Rogue, you begin play with 8+your Constitution modifier hit points.</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>You are proficient with the following items, in addition to any proficiencies provided by your race or background.</text>
				<text>&#8226; Armor: light armor</text>
				<text>&#8226; Weapons: simple weapons, hand crossbows, longswords, rapiers, shortswords</text>
				<text>&#8226; Tools: thieves' tools</text>
				<text>&#8226; Skills: Choose four from Acrobatics, Athletics, Deception, Insight, Intimidation, Investigation, Perception, Performance. Persuasion, Sleight of Hand, and Stealth</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>You begin play with the following equipment, in addition to any equipment provided by your background.</text>
				<text>&#8226; (a) a rapier or (b) a shortsword</text>
				<text>&#8226; (a) a shortbow and quiver of 20 arrows or (b) a shortsword</text>
				<text>&#8226; (a) a burglar's pack, (b) a dungeoneer's pack, or (c) an explorer's pack</text>
				<text>&#8226; Leather armor, two daggers, and thieves' tools </text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>Alternatively, you may start with 4d4x10 gp and choose your own equipment.</text>
				<text> </text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<multiclass>
			
				<name>Multiclass Rogue</name>
				<text>To multiclass as a Rogue, you must meet the following prerequisites:</text>
				<text>&#8226; Dexterity 13</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>You gain the following proficiencies:</text>
				<text>&#8226; light armor, thieves' tools; choose one skill from Acrobatics, Athletics, Deception, Insight, Intimidation, Investigation, Perception, Performance. Persuasion, Sleight of Hand, and Stealth</text>
				<text> </text>
			
		</multiclass>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Expertise</name>
				<text>At 1st level, choose two of your skill proficiencies, or one of your skill proficiencies and your proficiency with thieves&#8217; tools. Your proficiency bonus is doubled for any ability check you make that uses either of the chosen proficiencies.</text>
				<text>	At 6th level, you can choose two more of your proficiencies (in skills or with thieves&#8217; tools) to gain this benefit.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Sneak Attack</name>
				<text>Beginning at 1st level, you know how to strike subtly and exploit a foe&#8217;s distraction. Once per turn, you can deal an extra 1d6 damage to one creature you hit with an attack if you have advantage on the attack roll. The attack must use a finesse or a ranged weapon.</text>
				<text>	You don&#8217;t need advantage on the attack roll if another enemy of the target is within 5 feet of it, that enemy isn&#8217;t incapacitated, and you don&#8217;t have disadvantage on the attack roll.</text>
				<text>	The amount of the extra damage increases by 1d6 every odd level you gain in this class, to a maximum of 10d6 at 19th level.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Thieves' Cant</name>
				<text>During your rogue training you learned thieves&#8217; cant, a secret mix of dialect, jargon, and code that allows you to hide messages in seemingly normal conversation. Only another creature that knows thieves&#8217; cant understands such messages. It takes four times longer to convey such a message than it does to speak the same idea plainly.</text>
				<text>	In addition, you understand a set of secret signs and symbols used to convey short, simple messages, such as whether an area is dangerous or the territory of a thieves&#8217; guild, whether loot is nearby, or whether the people in an area are easy marks or will provide a safe house for thieves on the run.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Cunning Action</name>
				<text>Starting at 2nd level, your quick thinking and agility allow you to move and act quickly. You can take a bonus action on each of your turns in combat. This action can be used only to take the Dash, Disengage, or Hide action.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Roguish Archetype</name>
				<text>At 3rd level, you choose an archetype that you emulate in the exercise of your rogue abilities: Thief, Assassin, or Arcane Trickster, all detailed at the end of the class description. Your archetype choice grants you features at 3rd level and then again at 9th, 13th, and 17th level.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>


		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Uncanny Dodge</name>
				<text>Starting at 5th level, when an attacker that you can see hits you with an attack, you can use your reaction to halve the attack&#8217;s damage against you.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Evasion</name>
				<text>Beginning at 7th level, you can nimbly dodge out of the way of certain area effects, such as a red dragon&#8217;s fiery breath or an ice storm spell. When you are subjected to an effect that allows you to make a Dexterity saving throw to take only half damage, you instead take no damage if you succeed on the saving throw, and only half damage if you fail.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Reliable Talent</name>
				<text>By 11th level, you have refined your chosen skills until they approach perfection. Whenever you make an ability check that lets you add your proficiency bonus, you can treat a d20 roll of 9 or lower as a 10.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Blindsense</name>
				<text>Starting at 14th level, if you are able to hear, you are aware of the location of any hidden or invisible creature within 10 feet of you.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Slippery Mind</name>
				<text>By 15th level, you have acquired greater mental strength. You gain proficiency in Wisdom saving throws.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>


		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Elusive</name>
				<text>Beginning at 18th level, you are so evasive that attackers rarely gain the upper hand against you. No attack roll has advantage against you while you aren&#8217;t incapacitated.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>


		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Stroke of Luck</name>
				<text>At 20th level, you have an uncanny knack for succeeding when you need to. If your attack misses a target within range, you can turn the miss into a hit. Alternatively, if you fail an ability check, you can treat the d20 roll as a 20.</text>
				<text>	Once you use this feature, you can&#8217;t use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

</subclass>


<subclass>
	<name>sorcerer core</name>
	<class>Sorcerer</class>
	<hd>6</hd>
	<saves>Constitution, Charisma</saves>
	<proficiency>Arcana, Deception, Insight, Intimidation, Persuasion, Religion</proficiency>
	<spellAbility>Charisma</spellAbility>
	<numSkills>2</numSkills>
		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Starting Sorcerer</name>
				<text>As a 1st-level Sorcerer, you begin play with 6+your Constitution modifier hit points.</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>You are proficient with the following items, in addition to any proficiencies provided by your race or background.</text>
				<text>&#8226; Armor: none</text>
				<text>&#8226; Weapons: daggers, darts, slings, quarterstaffs, light crossbows</text>
				<text>&#8226; Tools: none</text>
				<text>&#8226; Skills: Choose two from Arcana, Deception, Insight, Intimidation, Persuasion, and Religion</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>You begin play with the following equipment, in addition to any equipment provided by your background.</text>
				<text>&#8226; (a) a light crossbow and 20 bolts or (b) any simple weapon</text>
				<text>&#8226; (a) a component pouch or (b) an arcane focus</text>
				<text>&#8226; (a) a dungeoneer's pack or (b) an explorer's pack</text>
				<text>&#8226; Two daggers </text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>Alternatively, you may start with 3d4x10 gp and choose your own equipment.</text>
				<text> </text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<multiclass>
			
				<name>Multiclass Sorcerer</name>
				<text>To multiclass as a Sorcerer, you must meet the following prerequisites:</text>
				<text>&#8226; Charisma 13</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>You gain the following proficiencies:</text>
				<text>&#8226; none</text>
				<text> </text>
			
		</multiclass>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Spellcasting</name>
				<text>An event in your past, or in the life of a parent or ancestor, left an indelible mark on you, infusing you with arcane magic. This font of magic, whatever its origin, fuels your spells. See chapter 10 for the general rules of spellcasting and chapter 11 for the sorcerer spell list. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Cantrips:</text>
				<text>	At 1st level, you know four cantrips of your choice from the sorcerer spell list. You learn an additional sorcerer cantrip of your choice at 4th level and another at 10th level. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Spell Slots:</text>
				<text>	The Sorcerer table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your spells of 1st level and higher. To cast one of these sorcerer spells, you must expend a slot of the spell&#8217;s level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.</text>
				<text>	For example, if you know the 1st-level spell burning hands and have a 1st-level and a 2nd-level spell slot available, you can cast burning hands using either slot. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Spells Known of 1st Level and Higher:</text>
				<text>	You know two 1st-level spells of your choice from the sorcerer spell list.</text>
				<text>	You learn an additional sorcerer spell of your choice at each level except 12th, 14th, 16th, 18th, 19th, and 20th. Each of these spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots. For instance, when you reach 3rd level in this class, you can learn one new spell of 1st or 2nd level.</text>
				<text>	Additionally, when you gain a level in this class, you can choose one of the sorcerer spells you know and replace it with another spell from the sorcerer spell list, which also must be of a level for which you have spell slots.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Spellcasting Ability:</text>
				<text>	Charisma is your spellcasting ability for your sorcerer spells, since the power of your magic relies on your ability to project your will into the world. You use your Charisma whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Charisma modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a sorcerer spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.</text>
				<text>	Spell save DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier</text>
				<text>	Spell attack modifier = your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Sorcerous Origin</name>
				<text>Choose a sorcerous origin, which describes the source of your innate magical power: Draconic Bloodline or Wild Magic, both detailed at the end of the class description.</text>
				<text>	Your choice grants you features when you choose it at 1st level and again at 6th, 14th, and 18th level.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Font of Magic</name>
				<text>At 2nd level, you tap into a deep wellspring of magic within yourself. This wellspring is represented by sorcery points, which allow you to create a variety of magical effects. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Sorcery Points:</text>
				<text>	You have a number of sorcery points equal to your sorcerer level. You can never have more sorcery points than your sorcerer level. You regain all spent sorcery points when you finish a long rest. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Flexible Casting:</text>
				<text>	You can use your sorcery points to gain additional spell slots, or sacrifice spell slots to gain additional sorcery points. You learn other ways to use your sorcery points as you reach higher levels. Spell slots you create using sorcery poinys are lost at the end of a long rest.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Creating Spell Slots:</text>
				<text>	You can transform unexpended sorcery points into one spell slot as a bonus action on your turn. It costs 2 sorcery points to create a 1st level spell slot, 3 to create a 2nd level slot, 5 for a 3rd level slot, 6 for a 4th level slot, or 7 for a 5th level slot. You can create spell slots no higher in level than 5th.</text>
				<text>	Any spell slot you create with this feature vanishes when you finish a long rest.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Converting a Spell Slot to Sorcery Points:</text>
				<text>	As a bonus action on your turn, you can expend one spell slot and gain a number of sorcery points equal to the slot&#8217;s level.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Metamagic</name>
				<text>At 3rd level, you gain the ability to twist your spells to suit your needs. You gain two of the following Metamagic options of your choice. You gain another one at 10th and 17th level.</text>
				<text>	You can use only one Metamagic option on a spell when you cast it, unless otherwise noted.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		

		
			
				<text>Metamagic: Careful Spell</text>
				<text>When you cast a spell that forces other creatures to make a saving throw, you can protect some of those creatures from the spell&#8217;s full force. To do so, you spend 1 sorcery point and choose a number of those creatures up to your Charisma modifier (minimum of one creature). A chosen creature automatically succeeds on its saving throw against the spell. </text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		

		
			
				<text>Metamagic: Distant Spell</text>
				<text>When you cast a spell that has a range of 5 feet or greater, you can spend 1 sorcery point to double the range of the spell.</text>
				<text>	When you cast a spell that has a range of touch, you can spend 1 sorcery point to make the range of the spell 30 feet. </text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		

		
			
				<text>Metamagic: Empowered Spell</text>
				<text>When you roll damage for a spell, you can spend 1 sorcery point to reroll a number of the damage dice up to your Charisma modifier (minimum of one). You must use the new rolls.</text>
				<text>	You can use Empowered Spell even if you have already used a different Metamagic option during the casting of the spell. </text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		

		
			
				<text>Metamagic: Extended Spell</text>
				<text>When you cast a spell that has a duration of 1 minute or longer, you can spend 1 sorcery point to double its duration, to a maximum duration of 24 hours. </text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		

		
			
				<text>Metamagic: Heightened Spell</text>
				<text>When you cast a spell that forces a creature to make a saving throw to resist its effects, you can spend 3 sorcery points to give one target of the spell disadvantage on its first saving throw made against the spell. </text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		

		
			
				<text>Metamagic: Quickened Spell</text>
				<text>When you cast a spell that has a casting time of 1 action, you can spend 2 sorcery points to change the casting time to 1 bonus action for this casting. </text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		

		
			
				<text>Metamagic: Subtle Spell</text>
				<text>When you cast a spell, you can spend 1 sorcery point to cast it without any somatic or verbal components. </text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		

		
			
				<text>Metamagic: Twinned Spell</text>
				<text>When you cast a spell that targets only one creature and doesn&#8217;t have a range of self, you can spend a number of sorcery points equal to the spell&#8217;s level to target a second creature in range with the same spell (1 sorcery point if the spell is a cantrip).</text>
				<text>	To be eligible, a spell must be incapable of targeting more than one creature at the spell&#8217;s current level. For example, magic missile and scorching ray aren&#8217;t eligible, but ray of frost and chromatic orb are.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>



		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Metamagic Option (3rd)</name>
				<text>At 10th level, you learn an additional metamagic option.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Metamagic Option (4th)</name>
				<text>At 17th level, you learn an additional metamagic option.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Sorcerous Restoration</name>
				<text>At 20th level, you regain 4 expended sorcery points whenever you finish a short rest.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

</subclass>


<subclass>
	<name>warlock core</name>
	<class>Warlock</class>
	<hd>8</hd>
	<saves>Wisdom, Charisma</saves>
	<proficiency>Arcana, Deception, History, Intimidation, Investigation, Nature, Religion</proficiency>
	<spellAbility>Charisma</spellAbility>
	<numSkills>2</numSkills>
		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Starting Warlock</name>
				<text>As a 1st-level Warlock, you begin play with 8+your Constitution modifier hit points.</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>You are proficient with the following items, in addition to any proficiencies provided by your race or background.</text>
				<text>&#8226; Armor: light armor</text>
				<text>&#8226; Weapons: simple weapons</text>
				<text>&#8226; Tools: none</text>
				<text>&#8226; Skills: Choose two skills from Arcana, Deception, History, Intimidation, Investigation, Nature, and Religion</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>You begin play with the following equipment, in addition to any equipment provided by your background.</text>
				<text>&#8226; (a) a light crossbow and 20 bolts or (b) any simple weapon</text>
				<text>&#8226; (a) a component pouch or (b) an arcane focus</text>
				<text>&#8226; (a) a scholar's pack or (b) a dungeoneer's pack</text>
				<text>&#8226; Leather armor, any simple weapon, and two daggers </text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>Alternatively, you may start with 4d4x10 gp and choose your own equipment.</text>
				<text> </text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<multiclass>
			
				<name>Multiclass Warlock</name>
				<text>To multiclass as a Warlock, you must meet the following prerequisites:</text>
				<text>&#8226; Charisma 13</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>You gain the following proficiencies:</text>
				<text>&#8226; light armor, simple weapons</text>
				<text> </text>
			
		</multiclass>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Pact Magic</name>
				<text>Your arcane research and the magic bestowed on you by your patron have given you facility with spells. See chapter 10 for the general rules of spellcasting and chapter 11 for the warlock spell list. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Cantrips:</text>
				<text>	You know two cantrips of your choice from the warlock spell list. You learn an additional warlock cantrip of your choice at 4th level, and another at 10th level. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Spell Slots:</text>
				<text>	The Warlock table shows how many spell slots you have. The table also shows what the level of those slots is; all of your spell slots are the same level. To cast one of your warlock spells of 1st level or higher, you must expend a spell slot. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a short or long rest.</text>
				<text>	For example, when you are 5th level, you have two 3rd-level spell slots. To cast the 1st-level spell witch bolt you must spend one of those slots, and you cast it as a 3rd-level spell. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Spells Known of 1st Level and Higher:</text>
				<text>	At 1st level, you know two 1st-level spells of your choice from the warlock spell list.</text>
				<text>	You learn an additional warlock spell at 2nd through 9th level, and at every odd level thereafter. A spell you choose must be of a level no higher than what&#8217;s shown in the table&#8217;s Slot Level column for your level. When you reach 6th level, for example, you learn a new warlock spell, which can be 1st, 2nd, or 3rd level.</text>
				<text>	Additionally, when you gain a level in this class, you can choose one of the warlock spells you know and replace it with another spell from the warlock spell list, which also must be of a level for which you have spell slots. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Spellcasting Ability:</text>
				<text>	Charisma is your spellcasting ability for your warlock spells, so you use your Charisma whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Charisma modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a warlock spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.</text>
				<text>	Spell save DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier</text>
				<text>	Spell attack modifier = your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Spellcasting Focus:</text>
				<text>	You can use an arcane focus (found in chapter 5) as a spellcasting focus for your warlock spells.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Otherworldly Patron</name>
				<text>At 1st level, you have struck a bargain with an otherworldly being of your choice: the Archfey, the Fiend, or the Great Old One, each of which is detailed at the end of the class description. Your choice grants you features at 1st level and again at 6th, 10th, and 14th level.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Eldritch Invocations</name>
				<text>In your study of occult lore, you have unearthed eldritch invocations, fragments of forbidden knowledge that imbue you with an abiding magical ability.</text>
				<text>	At 2nd level, you gain two eldritch invocations of your choice. Your invocation options are detailed at the end of the class description. When you gain certain warlock levels, you gain additional invocations of your choice. You gain an additional invocation at 5th, 7th, 9th, 12th, 15th, and 18th warlock level.</text>
				<text>	Additionally, when you gain a level in this class, you can choose one of the invocations you know and replace it with another invocation that you could learn at that level.</text>
				<text>	To select or change your invocations, add them as spells from the "Eldritch Invocations" spell list.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Pact Boon</name>
				<text>At 3rd level, your otherworldly patron bestows a gift upon you for your loyal service. You gain one of the following features of your choice: Pact of the Chain, Pact of the Blade, or Pact of the tome.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Pact Boon: Pact of the Blade</name>
				<text>You can use your action to create a pact weapon in your empty hand. You can choose the form that this melee weapon takes each time you create it (see chapter 5 for weapon options). You are proficient with it while you wield it. This weapon counts as magical for the purpose of overcoming resistance and immunity to nonmagical attacks and damage.</text>
				<text>	Your pact weapon disappears if it is more than 5 feet away from you for 1 minute or more. It also disappears if you use this feature again, if you dismiss the weapon (no action required), or if you die.</text>
				<text>	You can transform one magic weapon into your pact weapon by performing a special ritual while you hold the weapon. You perform the ritual over the course of 1 hour, which can be done during a short rest. You can then dismiss the weapon, shunting it into an extradimensional space, and it appears whenever you create your pact weapon thereafter. You can&#8217;t affect an artifact or a sentient weapon in this way. The weapon ceases being your pact weapon if you die, if you perform the 1-hour ritual on a different weapon, or if you use a 1-hour ritual to break your bond to it. The weapon appears at your feet if it is in the extradimensional space when the bond breaks. </text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Pact Boon: Pact of the Chain</name>
				<text>You learn the find familiar spell and can cast it as a ritual. The spell doesn&#8217;t count against your number of spells known.</text>
				<text>	When you cast the spell, you can choose one of the normal forms for your familiar or one of the following special forms: imp, pseudodragon, quasit, or sprite.</text>
				<text>	Additionally, when you take the Attack action, you can forgo one of your own attacks to allow your familiar to make one attack of its own with its reaction.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Pact Boon: Pact of the Tome</name>
				<text>Your patron gives you a grimoire called a Book of Shadows. When you gain this feature, choose three cantrips from any class&#8217;s spell list (the three needn&#8217;t be from the same list). While the book is on your person, you can cast those cantrips at will. They don&#8217;t count against your number of cantrips known. If they don&#8217;t appear on the warlock spell list, they are nonetheless warlock spells for you.</text>
				<text>	If you lose your Book of Shadows, you can perform a 1-hour ceremony to receive a replacement from your patron. This ceremony can be performed during a short or long rest, and it destroys the previous book. The book turns to ash when you die.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>


		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Additional Invocation</name>
				<text>At 5th level, you learn an additional Eldritch Invocation.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Additional Invocation</name>
				<text>At 7th level, you learn an additional Eldritch Invocation.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Additional Invocation</name>
				<text>At 9th level, you learn an additional Eldritch Invocation.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Mystic Arcanum</name>
				<text>At 11th level, your patron bestows upon you a magical secret called an arcanum. Choose one 6th-level spell from the warlock spell list as this arcanum.</text>
				<text>	You can cast your arcanum spell once without expending a spell slot. You must finish a long rest before you can do so again.</text>
				<text>	At higher levels, you gain more warlock spells of your choice that can be cast in this way: one 7th-level spell at 13th level, one 8th-level spell at 15th level, and one 9th-level spell at 17th level. You regain all uses of your Mystic Arcanum when you finish a long rest.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>


		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Additional Invocation</name>
				<text>At 12th level, you learn an additional Eldritch Invocation.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Additional Invocation</name>
				<text>At 15th level, you learn an additional Eldritch Invocation.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Additional Invocation</name>
				<text>At 18th level, you learn an additional Eldritch Invocation.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Eldritch Master</name>
				<text>At 20th level, you can draw on your inner reserve of mystical power while entreating your patron to regain expended spell slots. You can spend 1 minute entreating your patron for aid to regain all your expended spell slots from your Pact Magic feature. Once you regain spell slots with this feature, you must finish a long rest before you can do so again.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

</subclass>


<subclass>
	<name>wizard core</name>
	<class>Wizard</class>
	<hd>6</hd>
	<saves>Intelligence, Wisdom</saves>
	<proficiency>Arcana, History, Insight, Investigation, Medicine, Religion</proficiency>
	<spellAbility>Intelligence</spellAbility>
	<numSkills>2</numSkills>
		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Starting Wizard</name>
				<text>As a 1st-level Wizard, you begin play with 6+your Constitution modifier hit points.</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>You are proficient with the following items, in addition to any proficiencies provided by your race or background.</text>
				<text>&#8226; Armor: none</text>
				<text>&#8226; Weapons: daggers, darts, slings, quarterstaffs, light crossbows</text>
				<text>&#8226; Tools: none</text>
				<text>&#8226; Skills: Choose two from Arcana, History, Insight, Investigation, Medicine, and Religion</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>You begin play with the following equipment, in addition to any equipment provided by your background.</text>
				<text>&#8226; (a) a quarterstaff or (b) a dagger</text>
				<text>&#8226; (a) a component pouch or (b) an arcane focus</text>
				<text>&#8226; (a) a scholar's pack or (b) an explorer's pack</text>
				<text>&#8226; A spellbook</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>Alternatively, you may start with 4d4x10 gp and choose your own equipment.</text>
				<text> </text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<multiclass>
			
				<name>Multiclass Wizard</name>
				<text>To multiclass as a Wizard, you must meet the following prerequisites:</text>
				<text>&#8226; Intelligence 13</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>You gain the following proficiencies:</text>
				<text>&#8226; none</text>
				<text> </text>
			
		</multiclass>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Spellcasting</name>
				<text>As a student of arcane magic, you have a spellbook containing spells that show the first glimmerings of your true power. See chapter 10 for the general rules of spellcasting and chapter 11 for the wizard spell list. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Cantrips:</text>
				<text>	At 1st level, you know three cantrips of your choice from the wizard spell list. You learn an additional wizard cantrip of your choice at 4th level, and another at 10th level.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Spellbook:</text>
				<text>	At 1st level, you have a spellbook containing six 1st-level wizard spells of your choice. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Preparing and Casting Spells:</text>
				<text>	The Wizard table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your spells of 1st level and higher. To cast one of these spells, you must expend a slot of the spell&#8217;s level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.</text>
				<text>	You prepare the list of wizard spells that are available for you to cast. To do so. choose a number of wizard spells from your spellbook equal to your Intelligence modifier + your wizard level (minimum of one spell). The spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots.</text>
				<text>	For example, if you&#8217;re a 3rd-level wizard, you have four 1st-level and two 2nd-level spell slots. With an Intelligence of 16, your list of prepared spells can include six spells of 1st or 2nd level, in any combination, chosen from your spellbook. If you prepare the 1st-level spell magic missile, you can cast it using a 1st-level or a 2nd-level slot. Casting the spell doesn&#8217;t remove it from your list of prepared spells.</text>
				<text>	You can change your list of prepared spells when you finish a long rest. Preparing a new list of wizard spells requires time spent studying your spellbook and memorizing the incantations and gestures you must make to cast the spell: at least 1 minute per spell level for each spell on your list. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Spellcasting Ability:</text>
				<text>	Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for your wizard spells, since you learn your spells through dedicated study and memorization. You use your Intelligence whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Intelligence modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a wizard spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.</text>
				<text>	Spell save DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier</text>
				<text>	Spell attack modifier = your proficiency bonus + your intelligence modifier </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Ritual Casting:</text>
				<text>	You can cast a wizard spell as a ritual if that spell has the ritual tag and you have the spell in your spellbook. You don&#8217;t need to have the spell prepared. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Spellcasting Focus:</text>
				<text>	You can use an arcane focus (found in chapter 5) as a spellcasting focus for your wizard spells. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Learning Spells of 1st Level and Higher:</text>
				<text>	Each time you gain a wizard level, you can add two wizard spells of your choice to your spellbook. Each of these spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots, as shown on the Wizard table. On your adventures, you might find other spells that you can add to your spellbook.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Spellbook</name>
				<text>The spells of 1st level and higher that you add to your spellbook as you gain levels reflect the arcane research you conduct on your own, as well as intellectual breakthroughs you have had about the nature of the multiverse. You might find other spells during your adventures. You could discover a spell recorded on a scroll in an evil wizard&#8217;s chest, for example, or in a dusty tome in an ancient library.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Copying a Spell into the Book:</text>
				<text>	When you find a wizard spell of 1st level or higher, you can add it to your spellbook if it is of a spell level you can prepare and if you can spare the time to decipher and copy it.</text>
				<text>	Copying that spell into your spellbook involves reproducing the basic form of the spell, then deciphering the unique system of notation used by the wizard who wrote it. You must practice the spell until you understand the sounds or gestures required, then transcribe it into your spellbook using your own notation.</text>
				<text>	For each level of the spell, the process takes 2 hours and costs 50 gp. The cost represents material components you expend as you experiment with the spell to master it, as well as the fine inks you need to record it. Once you have spent this time and money, you can prepare the spell just like your other spells.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Replacing the Book:</text>
				<text>	You can copy a spell from your own spellbook into another book &#8212; for example, if you want to make a backup copy of your spellbook. This is just like copying a new spell into your spellbook, but faster and easier, since you understand your own notation and already know how to cast the spell. You need spend only 1 hour and 10 gp for each level of the copied spell.</text>
				<text>	If you lose your spellbook, you can use the same procedure to transcribe the spells that you have prepared into a new spellbook. Filling out the remainder of your spellbook requires you to find new spells to do so, as normal. For this reason, many wizards keep backup spellbooks in a safe place.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>The Book&#8217;s Appearance:</text>
				<text>	Your spellbook is a unique compilation of spells, with its own decorative flourishes and margin notes. It might be a plain, functional leather volume that you received as a gift from your master, a finely bound gilt-edged tome you found in an ancient library, or even a loose collection of notes scrounged together after you lost your previous spellbook in a mishap.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Arcane Recovery</name>
				<text>You have learned to regain some of your magical energy by studying your spellbook. Once per day when you finish a short rest, you can choose expended spell slots to recover. The spell slots can have a combined level that is equal to or less than half your wizard level (rounded up), and none of the slots can be 6th level or higher.</text>
				<text>	For example, if you&#8217;re a 4th-level wizard, you can recover up to two levels worth of spell slots. You can recover either a 2nd-level spell slot or two 1st-level spell slots.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Arcane Tradition</name>
				<text>When you reach 2nd level, you choose an arcane tradition, shaping your practice of magic through one of eight schools: Abjuration, Conjuration, Divination, Enchantment, Evocation, Illusion, Necromancy, or Transmutation, all detailed at the end of the class description.</text>
				<text>	Your choice grants you features at 2nd level and again at 6th, 10th, and 14th level.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

	
		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Spell Mastery</name>
				<text>At 18th level, you have achieved such mastery over certain spells that you can cast them at will. Choose a 1st-level wizard spell and a 2nd-level wizard spell that are in your spellbook. You can cast those spells at their lowest level without expending a spell slot when you have them prepared. If you want to cast either spell at a higher level, you must expend a spell slot as normal.</text>
				<text>	By spending 8 hours in study, you can exchange one or both of the spells you chose for different spells of the same levels.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Signature Spell</name>
				<text>When you reach 20th level, you gain mastery over two powerful spells and can cast them with little effort. Choose two 3rd-level wizard spells in your spellbook as your signature spells. You always have these spells prepared, they don&#8217;t count against the number of spells you have prepared, and you can cast each of them once at 3rd level without expending a spell slot. When you do so, you can&#8217;t do so again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
				<text>	If you want to cast either spell at a higher level, you must expend a spell slot as normal.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>
</subclass>


<subclass>
	<name>core revised ranger</name>
	<class>Revised Ranger</class>
	<hd>10</hd>
	<saves>Strength, Dexterity</saves>
	<proficiency>Animal Handling, Athletics, Insight, Investigation, Nature, Perception, Stealth, Survival</proficiency>
	<spellAbility>Wisdom</spellAbility>
	<numSkills>3</numSkills>
		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Starting Ranger (Revised)</name>
				<text>As a 1st-level Ranger (Revised), you begin play with 10+your Constitution modifier hit points.</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>You are proficient with the following items, in addition to any proficiencies provided by your race or background.</text>
				<text>&#8226; Armor: light armor, medium armor, shields</text>
				<text>&#8226; Weapons: simple weapons, martial weapons</text>
				<text>&#8226; Tools: none</text>
				<text>&#8226; Skills: Choose three from Animal Handling, Athletics, Insight, Investigation, Nature, Perception, Stealth, and Survival</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>You begin play with the following equipment, in addition to any equipment provided by your background.</text>
				<text>&#8226; (a) scale mail or (b) leather armor </text>
				<text>&#8226; (a) two shortswords or (b) two simple melee weapons </text>
				<text>&#8226; (a) a dungeoneer&#8217;s pack or (b) an explorer&#8217;s pack </text>
				<text>&#8226; A longbow and a quiver of 20 arrows</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>Alternatively, you may start with 5d4x10 gp and choose your own equipment.</text>
				<text> </text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<multiclass>
			
				<name>Multiclass Ranger (Revised)</name>
				<text>To multiclass as a Ranger (Revised), you must meet the following prerequisites:</text>
				<text>&#8226; Dexterity 13 and Wisdom 13</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>You gain the following proficiencies:</text>
				<text>&#8226; light armor, medium armor, shields, simple weapons, martial weapons; choose one skill from Animal Handling, Athletics, Insight, Investigation, Nature, Perception, Stealth, and Survival</text>
				<text> </text>
			
		</multiclass>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Favored Enemy</name>
				<text>Beginning at 1st level, you have significant experience studying, tracking, hunting, and even talking to a certain type of enemy commonly encountered in the wilds. Choose a type of favored enemy: beasts, fey, humanoids, monstrosities, or undead. You gain a +2 bonus to damage rolls with weapon attacks against creatures of the chosen type. Additionally, you have advantage on Wisdom (Survival) checks to track your favored enemies, as well as on Intelligence checks to recall information about them.</text>
				<text>	When you gain this feature, you also learn one language of your choice, typically one spoken by your favored enemy or creatures associated with it. However, you are free to pick any language you wish to learn.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Natural Explorer</name>
				<text>You are a master of navigating the natural world, and you react with swift and decisive action when attacked. This grants you the following benefits: </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>&#8226; You ignore difficult terrain. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>&#8226; You have advantage on initiative rolls. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>&#8226; On your first turn during combat, you have advantage on attack rolls against creatures that have not yet acted. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>	In addition, you are skilled at navigating the wilderness. You gain the following benefits when traveling for an hour or more: </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>&#8226; Difficult terrain doesn&#8217;t slow your group&#8217;s travel. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>&#8226; Your group can&#8217;t become lost except by magical means. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>&#8226; Even when you are engaged in another activity while traveling (such as foraging, navigating, or tracking), you remain alert to danger. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>&#8226; If you are traveling alone, you can move stealthily at a normal pace. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>&#8226; When you forage, you find twice as much food as you normally would. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>&#8226; While tracking other creatures, you also learn their exact number, their sizes, and how long ago they passed through the area.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Fighting Style</name>
				<text>At 2nd level, you adopt a particular style of fighting as your specialty. Choose one of the following options. You can&#8217;t take a Fighting Style option more than once, even if you later get to choose again.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		

		
			
				<text>Fighting Style: Archery</text>
				<text>You gain a +2 bonus to attack rolls you make with ranged weapons.</text>
				<text>	</text>		
			
				<text>Fighting Style: Defense</text>
				<text>While you are wearing armor, you gain a +1 bonus to AC.</text>
				<text>	</text>		
			
				<text>Fighting Style: Dueling</text>
				<text>When you are wielding a melee weapon in one hand and no other weapons, you gain a +2 bonus to damage rolls with that weapon.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
				<text>Fighting Style: Two-Weapon Fighting</text>
				<text>When you engage in two-weapon fighting, you can add your ability modifier to the damage of the second attack.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>


		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Spellcasting</name>
				<text>By the time you reach 2nd level, you have learned to use the magical essence of nature to cast spells, much as a druid does. See chapter 10 for the general rules of spellcasting and chapter 11 for the ranger spell list. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Spell Slots: </text>
				<text>	The Ranger table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your spells of 1st level and higher. To cast one of these spells, you must expend a slot of the spell&#8217;s level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest. </text>
				<text>	For example, if you know the 1st-level spell animal friendship and have a 1st-level and a 2nd-level spell slot available, you can cast animal friendship using either slot. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Spells Known of 1st Level and Higher: </text>
				<text>	You know two 1st-level spells of your choice from the ranger spell list. </text>
				<text>	At each odd level, you learn an additional ranger spell of your choice. Each of these spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots. For instance, when you reach 5th level in this class, you can learn one new spell of 1st or 2nd level. </text>
				<text>	Additionally, when you gain a level in this class, you can choose one of the ranger spells you know and replace it with another spell from the ranger spell list, which also must be of a level for which you have spell slots. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Spellcasting Ability: </text>
				<text>	Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for your ranger spells, since your magic draws on your attunement to nature. You use your Wisdom whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Wisdom modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a ranger spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one. </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Spell save DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier </text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Spell attack modifier = your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>


		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Primeval Awareness</name>
				<text>Beginning at 3rd level, your mastery of ranger lore allows you to establish a powerful link to beasts and to the land around you. </text>
				<text>	You have an innate ability to communicate with beasts, and they recognize you as a kindred spirit. Through sounds and gestures, you can communicate simple ideas to a beast as an action, and can read its basic mood and intent. You learn its emotional state, whether it is affected by magic of any sort, its short-term needs (such as food or safety), and actions you can take (if any) to persuade it to not attack. </text>
				<text>	You cannot use this ability against a creature that you have attacked within the past 10 minutes. </text>
				<text>	Additionally, you can attune your senses to determine if any of your favored enemies lurk nearby. By spending 1 uninterrupted minute in concentration (as if you were concentrating on a spell), you can sense whether any of your favored enemies are present within 5 miles of you. This feature reveals which of your favored enemies are present, their numbers, and the creatures&#8217; general direction and distance (in miles) from you. </text>
				<text>	If there are multiple groups of your favored enemies within range, you learn this information for each group.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Ranger Conclave</name>
				<text>At 3rd level, you choose to emulate the ideals and training of a ranger conclave: the Beast Conclave, the Hunter Conclave, or the Stalker Conclave, all detailed at the end of the class description. Your choice grants you features at 3rd level and again at 5th, 7th, 11th, and 15th level.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Greater Favored Enemy</name>
				<text>At 6th level, you are ready to hunt even deadlier game. Choose a type of greater favored enemy: aberrations, celestials, constructs, dragons, elementals, fiends, or giants. You gain all the benefits against this chosen enemy that you normally gain against your favored enemy, including an additional language. Your bonus to damage rolls against all your favored enemies increases to +4.</text>
				<text>	Additionally, you have advantage on saving throws against the spells and abilities used by a greater favored enemy.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>
	

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Fleet of Foot</name>
				<text>Beginning at 8th level, you can use the Dash action as a bonus action on your turn.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Hide in Plain Sight</name>
				<text>Starting at 10th level, you can remain perfectly still for long periods of time to set up ambushes. </text>
				<text>	When you attempt to hide on your turn, you can opt to not move on that turn. If you avoid moving, creatures that attempt to detect you take a _10 penalty to their Wisdom (Perception) checks until the start of your next turn. You lose this benefit if you move or fall prone, either voluntarily or because of some external effect. You are still automatically detected if any effect or action causes you to no longer be hidden. </text>
				<text>	If you are still hidden on your next turn, you can continue to remain motionless and gain this benefit until you are detected.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Vanish</name>
				<text>Starting at 14th level, you can use the Hide action as a bonus action on your turn. Also, you can&#8217;t be tracked by nonmagical means, unless you choose to leave a trail.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Feral Senses</name>
				<text>At 18th level, you gain preternatural senses that help you fight creatures you can&#8217;t see. When you attack a creature you can&#8217;t see, your inability to see it doesn&#8217;t impose disadvantage on your attack rolls against it.</text>
				<text>	You are also aware of the location of any invisible creature within 30 feet of you, provided that the creature isn&#8217;t hidden from you and you aren&#8217;t blinded or deafened.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Foe Slayer</name>
				<text>At 20th level, you become an unparalleled hunter. Once on each of your turns, you can add your Wisdom modifier to the attack roll or the damage roll of an attack you make. You can choose to use this feature before or after the roll, but before any effects of the roll are applied.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

</subclass>


<subclass>
	<name>blood hunter core</name>
	<class>Blood Hunter</class>
	<hd>10</hd>
	<saves>Strength, Wisdom</saves>
	<proficiency>Athletics, Acrobatics, Arcana, Insight, Investigation, Survival</proficiency>
	<spellAbility>Intelligence</spellAbility>
	<numSkills>2</numSkills>
		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Starting Blood Hunter</name>
				<text>As a 1st-level Blood Hunter, you begin play with 10+your Constitution modifier hit points.</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>You are proficient with the following items, in addition to any proficiencies provided by your race or background.</text>
				<text>&#8226; Armor: Light Armor. Medium Armor, Shields</text>
				<text>&#8226; Weapons: Simple Weapons, Martial Weapons</text>
				<text>&#8226; Tools: Alchemist's Supplies</text>
				<text>&#8226; Skills: Choose two from Athletics, Acrobatics, Arcana, Insight, Investigation, and Survival</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>You begin play with the following equipment, in addition to any equipment provided by your background.</text>
				<text>&#8226; (a) a martial weapon or (b) two simple weapons</text>
				<text>&#8226; (a) a light crossbow and 20 bolts or (b) hand crossbow and 20 bolts</text>
				<text>&#8226; (a)studded leather armor or (b) scale mail armor</text>
				<text>&#8226; An explorer's pack</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>Alternatively, you may start with 4d4x10 gp and choose your own equipment.</text>
				<text> </text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Hunter's Bane</name>
				<text>Beginning at 1st level, you have survived the imbibing of the Hunters Bane, a poisonous alchemical concoction that alters your lifes blood, forever binding you to the darkness and honing your senses against it. You have advantage on Wisdom (Survival) checks to track Fey, Fiends, and undead , as well as on Intelligence checks to recall information about them. If you are actively tracking one of these creature types, you cannot be surprised by any creatures of that type. You can only be tracking one type of creature at a time.</text>
				<text>	 </text>
				<text>Upon reaching 11th level, you can flare the internal toxic scars from the ritual, using the pain to give clarity, or promote anger. You can choose to suffer damage equal to a roll of your crimson rite damage die to gain  advantage on a Wisdom (Insight ) check or Charisma (Intimidation) check.</text>
				
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Crimson Rite</name>
				<text>At 1st level, you learn to invoke a rite of blood magic within your weapon at the cost of your own vitality. Choose to learn one rite from the Primal Rites list below. You cannot change this choice.</text>
				<text>As a bonus action, you imbue a single weapon with the elemental energy of a known rite until your next short or long rest. While active, attacks from this weapon deal an additional 1d4 rite damage of the chosen elemental type. Rite damage is considered  magical. The rite damage die changes as you gain blood hunter levels, as shown in the crimson rite damage die column of the blood hunter table. Should your weapon leave your grip, the rite fades immediately. An active rite on a weapon thrown fades directly after the attack is complete.</text>
				<text>When a crimson rite is activated, you suffer damage equal to your character level, and you reduce your maximum hit points by an amount equal to your character level. These lost maximum hit points return once the rite fades and cannot be restored otherwise. When a rite fades, no hit points are regained as part of the restoring of maximum hit points.</text>
				<text>Crimson rite can be used on multiple weapons, costing additional hit point loss. Most weapons can only be subject to a single rite at any given time. Each end of a polearm or quarterstaff is treated as a separate weapon for the purposes of this feature. A rite can be allowed to fade at any time on your turn (no action required ).</text>
				<text>You gain access to an additional Primal Rite at 6th level and 11th level. You may learn an Esoteric Rite at 14th level.</text>
				<text></text>
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Primal Rites</name>
				<text>Choose from the following:</text>
				<text>Rite of the Flame: Your rite damage is fire type.</text>
				<text>Rite of the Frozen: Your rite damage is cold type.</text>
				<text>Rite of the Storm: Your rite damage is Lightning type.</text>
				<text></text>
			
		</lvlskill>

				<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Fighting Style</name>
				<text>At 2nd level, you adopt a style of fighting as your specialty. Choose one of the following options: Defense, Dueling, Great Weapon Fighting, Mariner, or Protection. You can&#8217;t take a Fighting Style option more than once, even if you later get to choose again.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		

				
			
				<text>Fighting Style: Archery</text>
				<text>You gain a +2 bonus to attack rolls you make with ranged weapons.</text>
				<text>	</text>
		
			
		


		
			
				<text>Fighting Style: Dueling</text>
				<text>When you are wielding a melee weapon in one hand and no other weapons, you gain a +2 bonus to damage rolls with that weapon.</text>
				<text>	</text>
	
			
		

		
			
				<text>Fighting Style: Great Weapon Fighting</text>
				<text>When you roll a 1 or 2 on a damage die for an attack you make with a melee weapon that you are wielding with two hands, you can reroll the die and must use the new roll, even if the new roll is a 1 or a 2. The weapon must have the two-handed or versatile property for you to gain this benefit.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		

		
			
				<text>Fighting Style: Two-Weapon Fighting</text>
				<text>When you engage in two-weapon fighting, you can add your ability modifier to the damage of the second attack.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Blood Maledict</name>
				<text>At 2nd level, you gain the knowledge to further channel , and sacrifice, a part of your vital essence to curse and manipulate your enemies. You gain one blood curse of your choice, detailed in the  blood curses section below. You learn one additional blood curse of your choice at 5th, 9th, 13th, 16th, and 20th level.</text>
				<text>When you use your Blood Maledict, you choose which curse to invoke. While invoking a blood curse, but before it affects the target , you may choose to amplify the curse by suffering damage equal to a roll of your crimson rite damage die. An amplified curse gains an additional effect, noted in the curses description. Creatures that do not have blood in their bodies are immune to blood curses (DM s discretion).</text>
				<text>You can use this feature once. You regain expended uses when you finish a short or long rest. Beginning at 6th level, you can use your Blood Maledict feature twice between rests, at 11th level you can use it three times between rests, and at 17th level, you can use it four times between rests.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>
		
		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Blood Hunter Order</name>
				<text>At 3rd level, you commit to an order of blood hunter martial focus. Choose Order of the Mutant, Order of the Ghostslayer. Order of the Lycan or Order of the Profane Soul, all detailed at the end of the class description. The order you choose grants you features at 3rd level, and again at 7th, 11th, 15th, and 18th level.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>
		
		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Extra Attack</name>
				<text>Beginning at 5th level, you can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>
		
		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Additional Blood Curse</name>
				<text>Beginning at 5th level, you can choose one additional blood curse.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>
		
		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Additional Primal Rite</name>
				<text>Beginning at 6th level, you can choose one additional primal rite.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>

	
		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Additional Blood Curse</name>
				<text>Beginning at 9th level, you can choose one additional blood curse.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>
		
		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Grim Psychometry</name>
				<text>When you reach 9th level, you can take 10 minutes to meditate on an object to discern vague details regarding any lingering evil or wicked past surrounding it. Make a Wisdom ability check. Based on the result, the DM may reveal obscure information about dark events that mayhave previously surrounded the object, or hints toward a sinister purpose. This feature has no effect on objects untouched by evil. An object can only be targeted by this feature once, and future attempts reveal no further details.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>
		
		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Dark Velocity</name>
				<text>Upon reaching 10th level, you beckon the surrounding shadows to grant you unnatural swiftness on the battlefield. You gain darkvision out to 30 feet, or if you have darkvision, extend it out an additional 30 feet. While in dim light or darkness, your speed increases by 10 feet, and attacks of opportunity made against you have disadvantage.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>
		
		
		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Additional Primal Rite</name>
				<text>Beginning at 11th level, you can choose one additional primal rite.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>
		
		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Hunter's Bane: Additional Feature</name>
				<text>Upon reaching 11th level, you can flare the internal toxic scars from the ritual, using the pain to give clarity, or promote anger. You can choose to suffer damage equal to a roll of your crimson rite damage die to gain  advantage on a Wisdom (Insight ) check or Charisma (Intimidation) check.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>
	
		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Additional Blood Curse</name>
				<text>Beginning at 13th level, you can choose one additional blood curse.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>
		
		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Hardened Soul</name>
				<text>When you reach 14th level, you can no longer become Frightened, and you have advantage on saving throws against magical Charm effects.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>
		
		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Additional Blood Curse</name>
				<text>Beginning at 16th level, you can choose one additional blood curse.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>
	
		<lvlskill>
			
				<name>Sanguine Mastery</name>
				<text>Upon becoming 20th level, your ability to harness your pain and the pain of your foes,is perfected. When you are below one fourth of your current maximum hit points,all of your crimson rite damage dice are maximized, In addition, when you critically hit with a weapon attack that bears your crimson rite, you regain a use of your blood maledict feature.</text>
				<text>	</text>
			
		</lvlskill>
</subclass>


</compendium>