<world version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  
  <item>
    <title>Ring of Armoring</title>
	<type>item</type>
	<itemType>ring</itemType>
    <itemMagic>1</itemMagic>
	<itemValue>Unofficial</itemValue>
    <itemDetail>Ring, rare (requires Attunement by a spellcaster)</itemDetail>
    <text>While you wear this ring, whenever you cast a spell that gives you a bonus to AC, sets your AC to a specific number or gives you a new way to calculate your AC, the AC, bonus or calculation gets a +1 bonus.
</text>
  </item>
  
    <item>
    <title>Ring of Blinking</title>
	<type>item</type>
    <itemType>ring</itemType>
    <itemMagic>1</itemMagic>
	<itemValue>Unofficial</itemValue>
    <itemDetail>Ring, Uncommon (requires Attunement)</itemDetail>
    <text>A ring of blinking allows you to cast blink. Once you do so, you can't use the ring again until you complete a short or long rest

</text>
  </item>
  
    <item>
    <title>Ring of Cirulon</title>
	<type>item</type>
    <itemType>ring</itemType>
    <itemMagic>1</itemMagic>
	<itemValue>Unofficial</itemValue>
    <itemDetail>Ring, Rare  (requires Attunement)</itemDetail>
    <text>This ring has two powers. First, it allows you to use an action to touch a creature and heal 2d8 hit points of damage. This power can't be used again until the next dawn.

Its second power benefits only you. When a blow strikes you that would reduce you to 0 hit points, the ring reduces the damage the blow deals by 3d6 points. This power can't be used again until the next dawn.


</text>
  </item>
  
    <item>
    <title>Ring of Combat Prowess</title>
	<type>item</type>
    <itemType>ring</itemType>
    <itemMagic>1</itemMagic>
	<itemValue>Unofficial</itemValue>
    <itemDetail>Ring, Rare  (requires Attunement)</itemDetail>
    <text>A magical ring of this type empowers you in combat. It grants you the following benefits.
• Opportunity attacks against you have disadvantage.

• You can move through the space of enemies in combat, though you still treat them as difficult terrain and provoke opportunity attacks normally.


• Once per round on your turn, if you reduce an enemy to 0 hit points with a melee weapon attack, you can apply any damage exceeding what it took to reduce it to 0 hit points to another target within 5' of both you and the original target. You must make another attack roll against the secondary target, and no additional effects apply against it (only the damage that carried over).

</text>
  </item>
  
    <item>
    <title>Ring of Dashing Derring-Do</title>
	<type>item</type>
    <itemType>ring</itemType>
    <itemMagic>1</itemMagic>
	<itemValue>Unofficial</itemValue>
    <itemDetail>Ring, Rare  (requires Attunement)
</itemDetail>
    <text>As long as you keep uttering quips and japes at your foe's expense and your foe can understand your language, you add your Charisma bonus to damage with melee weapon attacks instead of DEX or STR.


</text>
  </item>
  
    <item>
    <title>Ring of Enduring Arcana</title>
	<type>item</type>
    <itemType>ring</itemType>
    <itemMagic>1</itemMagic>
	<itemValue>Unofficial</itemValue>
    <itemDetail>Ring, Rare  (requires Attunement)</itemDetail>
    <text>While you wear this ring, any attempt to dispel or counter a spell you cast treats the spell as if it were cast using a slot two levels higher.

</text>
  </item>
  
    <item>
    <title>Ring of Famulus</title>
	<type>item</type>
    <itemType>ring</itemType>
    <itemMagic>1</itemMagic>
	<itemValue>Unofficial</itemValue>
    <itemDetail>Ring, Rare  (requires Attunement)</itemDetail>
    <text>While you wear this ring with no armor or shield, you gain a +1 bonus to AC.

**Misty Step.** The ring has 2 charges, which it regains each dawn. You can expend 1 charge to cast misty step.

</text>
  </item>
  
      <item>
    <title>Ring of Linguistic Learning</title>
	<type>item</type>
    <itemType>ring</itemType>
    <itemMagic>1</itemMagic>
	<itemValue>Unofficial</itemValue>
    <itemDetail>Ring, uncommon</itemDetail>
    <text>This gold ring's band is carved to resemble a pair of people talking to each other. Such a ring has three charges; when the final charge is expended, it loses its magic. You can use a bonus action to spend a charge from the ring upon hearing a language you do not understand, and the ring instantly floods your mind with information, teaching you to speak, understand, read and write the language (if it has a written form).

</text>
  </item>
  
      <item>
    <title>Ring of Quickness</title>
	<type>item</type>
    <itemType>ring</itemType>
    <itemMagic>1</itemMagic>
	<itemValue>Unofficial</itemValue>
    <itemDetail>Ring, uncommon (requires attunement)</itemDetail>
    <text>While you wear this ring, you can use a bonus action to magically accelerate yourself to inhuman speed. Until the end of your turn, your speed doubles, and if you take the Attack action, you can make one additional attack. Once you use the ring's power, it won't work again until the next dawn.

</text>
  </item>
  
      <item>
    <title>Ring of Spell Holding</title>
	<type>item</type>
    <itemType>ring</itemType>
    <itemMagic>1</itemMagic>
	<itemValue>Unofficial</itemValue>
    <itemDetail>Ring, legendary (requires attunement)</itemDetail>
    <text>This ring can maintain concentration on one spell (or other similar effect) for you. If you must make a save to maintain concentration, so must it; it's save bonus is +0.

</text>
  </item>
  
      <item>
    <title>Ring of the Eagle</title>
	<type>item</type>
    <itemType>ring</itemType>
    <itemMagic>1</itemMagic>
	<itemValue>Unofficial</itemValue>
    <itemDetail>Ring, uncommon</itemDetail>
    <text>You can use an action to polymorph yourself into a giant eagle, except that the effect lasts until you use a bonus action to end it or until you fall to 0 hit points. Once you exist giant eagle form, you can't resume it until the next dawn. If you stay in giant eagle form for more than 24 hours, each day there is a 1% chance that the ring loses its powers and leaves you permanently in giant eagle form.

</text>
  </item>
  
      <item>
    <title>Ring of the Icy Soul</title>
	<type>item</type>
    <itemType>ring</itemType>
    <itemMagic>1</itemMagic>
	<itemValue>Unofficial</itemValue>
    <itemDetail>Ring, uncommon</itemDetail>
    <text>When you attune to this ring, you take on an icy appearance. For instance, your skin, hair and eyes may turn blue or white, or your breath might always be visible in the air. You gain immunity to cold damage but vulnerability to fire damage.

</text>
  </item>
  
      <item>
    <title>Ring of the Phoenix</title>
	<type>item</type>
    <itemType>ring</itemType>
    <itemMagic>1</itemMagic>
	<itemValue>Unofficial</itemValue>
    <itemDetail>Ring, Legendary (requires attunement)</itemDetail>
    <text>While you wear this ring, you gain resistance to fire damage. In addition, if you die, the ring melts into your finger and you are reborn at the start of your next turn in a fiery conflagration that deals 10d6 fire damage to each unfriendly creature within 5' of you. In your new form, you look the same as before you died, except eyes glow with burning embers and your hair turns red. 

Your alignment changes to Neutral Good, and you gain the following trait: “Evil must be opposed and destroyed at every turn.” Once you have been reborn, you gain the ability to innately cast the following spells 1/day each, using Charisma as your spellcasting ability: fireball, protection from fire, wall of fire.

</text>
  </item>
  
      <item>
    <title>Ring of Truth</title>
	<type>item</type>
    <itemType>ring</itemType>
    <itemMagic>1</itemMagic>
	<itemValue>Unofficial</itemValue>
    <itemDetail>Ring, Rare (requires attunement)</itemDetail>
    <text>This ring is a mixed blessing. While wearing it, you automatically detect lies spoken in your presence. However, you are unable to lie yourself, and if you attempt to do so, you find yourself speaking literal truth instead. If you encounter a creature under the influence
of magic that renders its lies undetectable, you don't detect the lies, but are also unable to hear the creature's voice.

</text>
  </item>
  
      <item>
    <title>Ring of Vengeance</title>
	<type>item</type>
    <itemType>ring</itemType>
    <itemMagic>1</itemMagic>
	<itemValue>Unofficial</itemValue>
    <itemDetail>Ring, Rare (requires attunement)</itemDetail>
    <text>Whenever a creature scores a critical hit on you, this magic ring flares to life, inflicting 5d6 radiant damage on that creature.

</text>
  </item>
  
      <item>
    <title>Ring of Weeping</title>
	<type>item</type>
    <itemType>ring</itemType>
    <itemMagic>1</itemMagic>
	<itemValue>Unofficial</itemValue>
    <itemDetail>Ring, Rare (requires attunement)</itemDetail>
    <text>You can use this dull gray ring to inflict great sadness on a creature. You can use an action to make a Strength or Dexterity attack at a creature you can reach; if you hit, it must make a DC 15 Wisdom save or become so overwhelmed with sadness that it is incapacitated until the end of its next turn, then has disadvantage on attacks and checks for 1 minute. At the end of each of its turns, it can repeat the save, ending the effect on a success. Once you use this ability, you can not use it again until the next dawn.

</text>
  </item>
  
  </world>