<world version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  
       <item>
    <title>Bracer of Flying Daggers</title>
	<type>item</type>
    <itemType>wondrous item</itemType>
    <itemMagic>1</itemMagic>
	<itemValue>Unofficial</itemValue>
	<itemStock>blacksmith</itemStock>
    <itemDetail>Wondrous item, rare (requires attunement)</itemDetail>
    <text>This armband appears to have thin daggers strapped to it. As a n action, you can pull up to two magic daggers from the bracer and immediately hurl them, making a ranged attack with each dagger. A dagger vanishes if you don't hurl it right away, and the daggers disappear right after they hit or miss. The bracer never runs out of daggers.
	
	Source: Waterdeep: Dragon Heist
</text></item>

       <item>
    <title>Knave's Eye Patch</title>
	<type>item</type>
    <itemType>wondrous item</itemType>
    <itemMagic>1</itemMagic>
	<itemValue>Unofficial</itemValue>
	<itemStock>enchanter</itemStock>
    <itemDetail>Wondrous item, rare (requires attunement)</itemDetail>
    <text>While wearing this eye patch, you gain these benefits:
	
You have advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on sight.

If you have the Sunlight Sensitivity trait, you are unaffected by the trait.

You are immune to magic that allows other creatures to read your thoughts or determine whether you are lying. Creatures can communicate telepathically with you only if you allow it.
	
	Source: Waterdeep: Dragon Heist
</text></item>

       <item>
    <title>Paper Bird</title>
	<type>item</type>
    <itemType>wondrous item</itemType>
    <itemMagic>1</itemMagic>
	<itemValue>Unofficial</itemValue>
	<itemStock>enchanter</itemStock>
    <itemDetail>Wondrous item. uncommon</itemDetail>
    <text>After you write a message of fifty words or fewer on this magic sheet of parchment and speak a creature's name, the parchment magicaJly folds into a Tiny paper bird and Hies to the recipient whose name you uttered. The recipient must be on the same plane of existence as you, otherwise the bird turns into ash as it takes flight. The bird is an object that has 1 hit point, an Armor Class of 13, and flying speed of 60 feet. 	

	Source: Waterdeep: Dragon Heist
</text></item>


       <item>
    <title>Ring of Truth Telling</title>
	<type>item</type>
    <itemType>ring</itemType>
    <itemMagic>1</itemMagic>
	<itemValue>Unofficial</itemValue>
	<itemStock>jeweler</itemStock>
    <itemDetail>Ring, uncommon (requires attuncment)</itemDetail>
    <text>While wearing this ring, you have advantage on Wisdom (Insight) checks to determine whether someone is lying to you.
	
	Source: Waterdeep: Dragon Heist
</text></item>
	        
  </world>
  