<world version="5" auto_indent="NO">
  
           <item>
    <title>Shadowstrike Weapon</title>
	<type>item</type>
    <itemType>weapon</itemType>
    <itemMagic>1</itemMagic>
	<itemValue>Unofficial</itemValue>
	<itemstock></itemstock>
    <itemDetail>Weapon (any melee), rare (requires attunement)</itemDetail>
    <text>This weapon has a +2 bonus to hit and damage. You can use a bonus action to strike through your shadow, adding 5' to your reach with it until the end of your turn. Once you do so, you must complete a short or long rest before this power will function again.
</text>
  </item> 
  
     <item>
    <title>Shield of Defiance</title>
	<type>item</type>
    <itemType>shield</itemType>
    <itemMagic>1</itemMagic>
	<itemValue>Unofficial</itemValue>
	<itemstock></itemstock>
    <itemDetail>Armor (shield), common</itemDetail>
    <text>This shield has 7 charges, and it loses its magic when the last charge is expended but remains a normal, well-wrought shield. When you suffer a critical hit, you can use your reaction to spend a charge to reduce it to a normal hit.
</text>
  </item> 
  
     <item>
    <title>Shield of Haste</title>
	<type>item</type>
    <itemType>shield</itemType>
    <itemMagic>1</itemMagic>
	<itemValue>Unofficial</itemValue>
	<itemstock></itemstock>
    <itemDetail>Armor (shield), uncommon (requires attunement)</itemDetail>
    <text>This shield allows you to cast haste on yourself. Once you do so, it won't function again until the next dawn.
</text>
  </item> 
  
     <item>
    <title>Silver Seeker's Symbol</title>
	<type>item</type>
    <itemType>wondrous item</itemType>
    <itemMagic>1</itemMagic>
	<itemValue>Unofficial</itemValue>
	<itemstock></itemstock>
    <itemDetail>Wondrous item, uncommon (requires attunement)</itemDetail>
    <text>While you bear this symbol, which resembles an open book, you gain a +1 bonus on Arcana and Religion checks.
</text>
  </item> 
  
     <item>
    <title>Shock Weapon</title>
	<type>item</type>
    <itemType>weapon</itemType>
    <itemMagic>1</itemMagic>
	<itemValue>Unofficial</itemValue>
	<itemstock></itemstock>
    <itemDetail>Weapon (any), rare</itemDetail>
    <text>This magical weapon has no attack bonus, but when it hits, it deals an extra 1d6 lightning damage. Such a weapon is often chased with copper, set with studs of amber, made of wood taken from a tree that was struck by lightning, inscribed with lightning bolts, etc.
</text>
  </item> 
  
     <item>
    <title>Silver Spoon</title>
	<type>item</type>
    <itemType>wondrous item</itemType>
    <itemMagic>1</itemMagic>
	<itemValue>Unofficial</itemValue>
	<itemstock></itemstock>
    <itemDetail>Wondrous item, rare</itemDetail>
    <text>If you use an action to place this silver spoon in the mouth of an infant not more than a day old, then ensure that the spoon remains in the baby's dwelling until its birthday, the baby will inherit a fortune from a long-lost forgotten relative. This fortune will be worth from 1,000 to 50,000 gp.
	
	If the spoon is removed before the baby's first birthday, a curse falls upon the baby, and it loses all its money and possessions.
</text>
  </item> 
  
     <item>
    <title>Skald's Armor</title>
	<type>item</type>
    <itemType>armor</itemType>
    <itemMagic>1</itemMagic>
	<itemValue>Unofficial</itemValue>
	<itemstock></itemstock>
    <itemDetail>Armor (leather), rare (requires attunement by a bard)</itemDetail>
    <text>Favored by wandering minstrels who often need to talk their way out of hairy situations, this magical armor allows you to add +1d4 to any Charisma (Deception or Persuasion) check you make
</text>
  </item> 
  
     <item>
    <title>Skirmisher Boots</title>
	<type>item</type>
    <itemType>wondrous item</itemType>
    <itemMagic>1</itemMagic>
	<itemValue>Unofficial</itemValue>
	<itemstock></itemstock>
    <itemDetail>Wondrous item, uncommon (requires attunement)</itemDetail>
    <text>While you wear these boots, you gain a +2 bonus on damage on opportunity attacks.
</text>
  </item> 
  
     <item>
    <title>Spellguard Rings</title>
	<type>item</type>
    <itemType>wondrous item</itemType>
    <itemMagic>1</itemMagic>
	<itemValue>Unofficial</itemValue>
	<itemstock></itemstock>
    <itemDetail>Ring, very rare (requires attunement)</itemDetail>
    <text>These magical rings come in pairs. One is worn by a spellcaster, and is considered the 'master' ring. The other- the 'bonded' ring- can be worn by any creature. The creature wearing the bonded ring is immune to the effects of any spell cast by the wearer of the master ring.
</text>
  </item> 
  
     <item>
    <title>Sphere of Awakening</title>
	<type>item</type>
    <itemType>wondrous item</itemType>
    <itemMagic>1</itemMagic>
	<itemValue>Unofficial</itemValue>
	<itemstock></itemstock>
    <itemDetail>Wondrous item, common (requires attunement)</itemDetail>
    <text>While you hold this fist-sized crystal sphere in hand, you can use a bonus action to cause all sleeping creatures within 60' to awaken. Once you have used it, it won't function until the next dawn.
</text>
  </item> 
     
	      <item>
    <title>Spring Renewal Totem</title>
	<type>item</type>
    <itemType>wondrous item</itemType>
    <itemMagic>1</itemMagic>
	<itemValue>Unofficial</itemValue>
	<itemstock></itemstock>
    <itemDetail>Wondrous item, very rare (requires attunement)</itemDetail>
    <text>This carved length of green wood has blossoms and fresh growth coming out of it, as if it were still alive. It has 3 charges, which it regains each dawn. You can use a bonus action to spend a charge. If you do so, choose one creature you can see within 30'. For the next minute, whenever that creature starts its turn with 1 hit point or more, it regains 3 hit points.
</text>
  </item> 
  
       <item>
    <title>Squire's Sword</title>
	<type>item</type>
    <itemType>weapon</itemType>
    <itemMagic>1</itemMagic>
	<itemValue>Unofficial</itemValue>
	<itemstock></itemstock>
    <itemDetail>Weapon (any sword), uncommon (requires attunement)</itemDetail>
    <text>While you wield this sword, allies within 5' of you gain a +1 bonus to AC.
</text>
  </item> 
  
       <item>
    <title>Staff of Fiery Might</title>
	<type>item</type>
    <itemType>wondrous item</itemType>
    <itemMagic>1</itemMagic>
	<itemValue>Unofficial</itemValue>
	<itemstock></itemstock>
    <itemDetail>Staff, uncommon (requires attunement by a spellcaster)</itemDetail>
    <text>You can use this staff as a spellcasting focus. In addition, when you use it to cast a fire spell, you can reroll any 1s on the damage dice, but you must accept the second result.
</text>
  </item> 
  
       <item>
    <title>Silver Seeker's Symbol</title>
	<type>item</type>
    <itemType>wondrous item</itemType>
    <itemMagic>1</itemMagic>
	<itemValue>Unofficial</itemValue>
	<itemstock></itemstock>
    <itemDetail>Wondrous item, uncommon (requires attunement)</itemDetail>
    <text>While you bear this symbol, which resembles an open book, you gain a +1 bonus on Arcana and Religion checks.
</text>
  </item> 
  
       <item>
    <title>Staff of Spell Focusing</title>
	<type>item</type>
    <itemType>wondrous item</itemType>
    <itemMagic>1</itemMagic>
	<itemValue>Unofficial</itemValue>
	<itemstock></itemstock>
    <itemDetail>Staff, very rare (requires attunement by a spellcaster)</itemDetail>
    <text>This staff functions as a spellcasting focus. In addition, it has 3 charges, which it regains each day at dawn. When you cast a spell, you can expend a charge to cause one creature affected to have disadvantage on its saving throw. If you spend the last charge, you gain a level of exhaustion.
</text>
  </item> 
  
       <item>
    <title>Staff of the Shark</title>
	<type>item</type>
    <itemType>wondrous item</itemType>
    <itemMagic>1</itemMagic>
	<itemValue>Unofficial</itemValue>
	<itemstock></itemstock>
    <itemDetail>Staff, very rare (requires attunement)</itemDetail>
    <text>This driftwood staff is studded with shark teeth and smells of the sea. Its surface is remarkably rough for driftwood. You can use it as a quarterstaff, in which case it deals an extra 1d4 points of piercing damage on a hit and scores a critical hit on a 19 or 20.
	
	In addition, you can use it as an arcane, divine or druidic spellcasting focus. If you do so, any spell attacks you make also score a critical hit on a 19 or 20.
</text>
  </item> 
  
       <item>
    <title>Star Opal Ring</title>
	<type>item</type>
    <itemType>ring</itemType>
    <itemMagic>1</itemMagic>
	<itemValue>Unofficial</itemValue>
	<itemstock></itemstock>
    <itemDetail>Ring, very rare (requires attunement)</itemDetail>
    <text>While you wear this ring, you gain a +10' bonus to your walking speed. In addition, the ring has 3 charges, regaining 1 each morning at dawn. You can use an action to spend a charge and teleport to a placethat you can see within 100' of you. Immediately after you do, the ring also produces a brilliant explosion in a 15' radius sphere centered on the space you teleported out of. Each creature in the sphere must make a DC 15 Dexterity saving throw, suffering 8d8 radiant damage on a failure and half that on a success.
</text>
  </item> 
  
       <item>
    <title>Storm Gauntlets</title>
	<type>item</type>
    <itemType>wondrous item</itemType>
    <itemMagic>1</itemMagic>
	<itemValue>Unofficial</itemValue>
	<itemstock></itemstock>
    <itemDetail>Wondrous item, rare (requires attunement)</itemDetail>
    <text>These blue metal gauntlets have 4 charges, which they regain each dawn. You can expend one or more charges to cast the following spells: lightning bolt (2 charges), chain lightning (4 charges), shocking grasp (1 charge). The DC for these spells is 15.
</text>
  </item> 
  
       <item>
    <title>Storm Pendant</title>
	<type>item</type>
    <itemType>wondrous item</itemType>
    <itemMagic>1</itemMagic>
	<itemValue>Unofficial</itemValue>
	<itemstock></itemstock>
    <itemDetail>Wondrous item, very rare (requires attunement)</itemDetail>
    <text>When you take lightning damage, you can use your reaction to fire a line of lightning 5' wide and 30' long, extending from your body. Each creature caught in this line must make a DC 15 Dexterity saving throw, suffering 3d6 lightning damage on a failure or half that on a success.
	
	When you take thunder damage, you can use your reaction to emit a peal of thunder in a 10' radius sphere centered on you. Each creature other than you in this sphere must make a DC 15 Constitution saving throw, suffering 1d10 thunder damage or half that on a success. In addition, a creature that fails this saving throw is deafened for 1 minute. It can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on a success.
</text>
  </item> 
   
  </world>
  